Night one of the 2026 NFL draft was one
that Cowboys fans will never forget.
Caleb DS now a Dallas Cowboy with the
11th overall pick, trading up with the
Miami Dolphins. And then at pick number
23 following a trade with the
Philadelphia Eagles. Malachi Lawrence is
now a Dallas Cowboy as well. We now sit
and wait as the second round is about
set to get underway in Pittsburgh,
Pennsylvania. The next pick currently, I
might add, for the Dallas Cowboys is at
92 overall. Welcome in to our 2026 NFL
draft coverage on the Dallas Cowboys
radio network and on dallascowboys.com.
Once again, we will be here through
every single pick of the second and the
third round tonight, plus the press
conference with the Cowboys front office
to follow. Then we will get you set for
day three tomorrow. So, starting us off
tonight, we've got Vatch Lombardi,
YouTube superstar in his own right,
wearing the sport coat for the second
night in a row. Looks nice over there,
Vch with the sunglasses. We've got Tommy
Yarish from Dallas Cowboys.com, Cowboys
Insider and Beat Rider. We've got 1053
the fan and especially known from Gbag
Nation, Mr. Zack Walchuck, draft insider
and expert. We also have Fort Worth Star
Telegram Cowboys beat writer Mr. Nick
Harris, also I would like to add, as a
draft expert. I'm Kyleman's. Glad you're
with us here on night two of the draft.
This is going to be a fun one,
gentlemen.
>> But like voice of the Dallas Cowboys
draft show, Kyleman,
top tier ass host Kyle.
>> Like big dog Kyle Yman. Six year veteran
Kyle Yman.
>> This is my seventh draft.
>> Sevenyear veteran man. Quit playing with
us, man. Come on. It's lucky number
seven. And it worked out last night for
Dallas getting Caleb DS. it. Last night,
gentlemen, was about as fun as I've ever
had watching the NFL draft, not only as
a fan, but as a a host of the draft
show. This was just unforgettable. And
as we get ready for the start of the
second round, Roger Goodell is actually
going to the podium right now. Let's
check in as he gets this thing kicked
off on night two
>> last night in front of more than 320,000
fans right here in Pittsburgh. Give
yourself a hand. That's awesome.
>> Let's see.
>> Hut. Hut.
>> And millions more watching around the
world. We welcome 32 incredible young
men to the NFL family.
>> What are you wearing?
>> And tonight, already there are over
260,000
fans here. You've already set a record
for two night two.
And as you can see, I'm joined by 32
players and legends of our game. All
here to help us select the next
generation of talent to join the NFL.
Many of these players of me on stage
have either grown up in Western
Pennsylvania or played football here.
This area is one of the most talentrich
football regions in the country.
>> With more than 650 players advancing to
the National Football League,
>> long known as the creator of
quarterbacks,
>> Western Pennsylvania is a true pipeline
of greatness, producing 23.
>> California's got some guys. Yeah.
>> Please give them a warm welcome.
>> How many football players out of
Wyoming?
>> He's trying to convert. Hey, listen.
They have a mean Joe Green jersey up
there. So that that's go mean green.
Yeah.
>> But where did he come from initially?
>> He came from Texas.
>> Temple, Texas.
>> 2026 NFL draft is officially open.
>> And as he was saying there, the San
Francisco 49ers are now on the clock. As
we wait, we could probably just play
some smooth jazz. We could kick the feet
up for a little bit over the next two
and a half hours. 60 picks now between
now and when the Cowboys selected 92
overall.
>> Yeah, they based on the capital that
they picked up yesterday, they could
move back into the third round if the
right uh opportunity presents itself,
but certainly not the second round. Uh I
think we're going to be just sitting
here talking about some really good
players coming off the board and excited
to dive into your guys' evals and
scouting reports on these guys. there's
going to be some fun players go at the
top of the second.
>> When you you talk about the the
inability to get back up into the
second, even if you pair it with the
third round pick and and wanted to go
get a linebacker, because I know that's
the probably the number one position, if
we go across the table, what's the
number one hole for for the Cowboys
right now is linebacker. If you've got a
linebacker that you like and he's there
in the later parts of the second, do you
have enough draft capital this year to
not wager the future draft capital to go
back up and get him if he's in the back
half of the second?
>> Yeah. If you used your third round pick
and your first fourth round pick, you
still would not be able to crack into
the second. And so, um, and actually, as
I'm doing the math here, if you took,
uh, uh, two of your fourth round picks
and your third round pick, you would not
be able to move into the second round.
So yeah, you would have to garner or or
wager um future capital to to get into
the second. And based on the
conversations last night, it doesn't
sound like they they want to do that.
That they feel like
>> there there is not going to be a
position that they feel like they have
to do that. They don't like spending
three players for one player. They've
talked about that multiple times and I
get the sense that there's multiple
conting contingency plans at linebacker
if they don't come away with one they
feel good about starting today. I think
the highest realistically you could
probably get to would be 78 which would
be 92 and 112 if my math is correct
there. So I mean maybe if one of these
line because I'm going to be sweating
the linebackers all night and I all it
might take is just one and the next
thing you know here's Anthony Hill Jr.
from Texas here's CJ Allen from Georgia,
Jacob Rodriguez from Tech and all these
guys are going. But I'm going to be
praying that one can at least get to
striking distance in the third so that
you can make a move if you need to.
>> Who would you go up to go get Fox? Who
are the the top linebackers remaining on
your board?
>> Man, Nick Harris told me that we that we
can't. So, if I had to just daydream
about it, um, you know, man, you know,
CJ Allen is a name that that that we all
love at this point. Uh, I'm a I'm a big
Jake Gold Day guy. I know everybody's
not a big Jake Gold Day guy, but if if
it's a name that I can be like, "All
right, realistically, can he fall and
can teams kind of suck at drafting to
get us to a point to where we can meet
in the middle a little bit?" I would
love if like Gold Day or like Troder or
something like that. as far as like
Anthony Hill, I don't think you stand a
chance at all. Uh
>> Jacob Rodriguez, you know, you're
obviously higher on him than the rest of
us, but if the league kind of feels like
he should be in the third round, hey, I
think that's a knockout pick if he if he
falls to you at 92. On my board, he's
like 57. Um so that'll be great great
value there. Uh but I just don't
anticipate that good players is gonna be
falling that much for you.
>> Uh I'm with Votch. think that, you know,
if you look at 92 and I think Zach
pointed it out well too that you very
well could see a run linebackers. I
think corners too is another spot where
you can see a run on guys. McCoy is
still there from Tennessee. Hood
Tennessee is still there. Keonte Scott
Miami, Keith Abney, uh Arizona State,
Brandon Cay, South Carolina. There are
so many guys that both of those
positions I feel like that are still on
the board that when you talk about 40
picks in front of you, I find it
difficult to think that um a lot of
these top tier guys that we've been
talking about for a majority of the
process are going to be there. Um if
there is a linebacker that you know you
maybe hope gets there, uh Missou's
Josiah Troder is a guy that we've talked
about a lot. I think the Cowboys like
him. Um, oh my goodness, I'm blanking on
my buddy from Arizon Keeshan Elliot from
Arizona Arizona State is another one to
keep an eye on there. And then I don't
think you know you necessarily can you
don't want to rule out corner either.
One of the what if one of these guys
falls all the way down to you there. Uh,
but linebacker definitely based on
everything that I've heard and all the
conversations that I've had is the
biggest priority if they can get one at
at 92.
>> Would you guys assume that they'll
double dip at edge? I know we're we're
thinking offball linebacker like, "All
right, y'all. It's got to be
linebacker." But what if they're like
not super pressed about linebacker? You
know, we were listening to the Joneses
have conversations and Stephen was like,
"Hey man, we talked to some teams and
stuff lined up and we'll talk about when
we talk about like what if they're not
pressed and they're really just going to
let the board come to them." Could they
double dip at edge? Because there's
still a lot of edges I like.
>> I could ask that same question for the
secondary, too,
>> for sure. you you make the pick with
Caleb DS, you want to play him in
nickel, you want to play him at safety,
that's fine, but you still have multiple
red flags at the cornerback spot, too,
if you really want to look at your
roster.
>> And it stretches to Tommy's point. I
mean, if you're looking at, you know,
Ponds, I think is probably going to go
pretty early from Indiana, but could you
get a David Ignosin? Is that a guy that
could be in consideration a bigger true
outside corner that's already played
with Caleb DS? Now, he could be a
walking penalty, but I love the
physicality that he plays with, and he's
also a guy that it seems like big games.
David Ignosan's just making plays for
Ohio State. So, you've got Malik
Muhammad, who they brought in as well,
uh, from the University of Texas. Tommy,
we can tell you all about Malik
Muhammad. Great dude. Keith Abney, local
product as well from Arizona State.
Dalen Everett from Georgia.
>> Oh, that's that would be mine.
>> I love him. I mean, there's just so many
really, really good corners, but I know
we've got people listening that are
probably playing drinking games for how
many times they'll say this name. Let's
just
>> Jacob Rodriguez,
>> everybody take a drink.
>> Just Jacob Rodriguez to 92. How will it
I hope Bobby's right. He's been telling
me third round, third round, third
round. I'm like I'm I think there's
plenty of teams that like him. Carolina
at 51 I've kind of earmarked as a as a
spot. Maybe he could go, but I'm here.
Let's ride the wave. Let's get him to
92.
>> I think he's a fourth round linebacker.
I think he can't go anywhere before 92.
>> You're so
I think if if he goes anywhere before
92, I think it's a bad value.
>> Just awful. One of the worst mustaches
you've ever seen. just disgusting.
>> Definitely not not be a face of your
defense immediately that would be
recognizable or
>> see Kyle Nick Zack Tommy. Can I just say
something?
>> Yeah, please.
>> Bernard from Alabama, Sarah from
Indiana.
>> Boston probably won't fall. You know,
Daniels from Miami, Williams from
Clemson, Lance from North Dakota State.
Is wide receiver sneaky? I mean, you
know, the Cowboys had interest in maybe
wide receiver in the first round
possibly. We heard some of the buzz
around it. Is this a good time that the
Cowboys could sneakily look at wide
receiver?
>> I think so. Uh I I would wonder who
would be on the board necessarily. I
think Jeremy Bernard was one name that I
looked at this morning. I was like, man,
that could be fun.
>> Yeah. Guy gets up field quick for sure.
>> For sure. Uh so Bernard is one that I
personally would would like to see. Uh I
don't think a guy like Ted Hurst
probably gets that deep into it. Um that
man, that would be so good.
>> He's high on their board, too. I like
him. And he gives you something that you
don't have with that 6'4 frame. with Dan
Stribbling. Um, that's that's another
one uh that I have kind of in that
range. Uh,
>> man.
And man, I love Jeff Caldwell out of
Cincinnati. I think you could probably
get him in the fourth, though. But I I I
feel pretty highly about him. And then
Jacobe Lane out of USC. That one could
be fascinating if he's there.
>> Absolutely.
>> All right, here's Andy Lee with the
49ers selection.
>> He's a punter. Um, it's an honor to play
here for four years. And I just want to
thank the 49ers opportunity. I want to
give a shout out to the 49er faithful,
the best fans in the NFL.
>> With the 33rd pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the San Francisco 49ers select
Desawn Stribbling
Old Miss.
>> Never mind.
>> Well, well, go ahead, Nick.
>> That was a great Friday.
>> Hey Nick, tell us why there's no way
we'll get Stribbling. Are you tipping
pics?
>> Tell us why, Nick.
>> No, I Yeah, this was not a tipping
situation, I promise. Uh, no, he is a
Hawaiian native, which I think is really
fascinating. Uh, yeah, he is. Um, but a
big body and I
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> From Hawaii. Um,
>> you think he can do the hockey?
>> He do that dancing.
>> He wet them flowers right there. I'm
sorry. Go ahead, man. Um, he uh he has a
big body and then at Misses last year,
he really showed the uh the playmaking
ability. He showed it at Oklahoma State
as well. Um, but specifically at Old
Miss, that big play ability, that yak
ability really showed up.
>> HE'S WEARING THE FLOWERS.
>> HE HE'S WEARING THE FLOWERS ON THE
BROADCAST. He is.
>> I'm sorry. That's probably a better name
for it than what I just called it.
>> I don't know nothing.
>> It's I just I just never would have
thought that a Djon.
>> So, his father spent 17 years in the
Marines. He's originally from North
Carolina.
>> What his daddy mean?
>> Uh, his Carlos.
>> His daddy.
>> No way.
>> With a K.
>> Oh, damn.
>> His black Carlos for sure. Yeah.
>> Hey y'all, we don't have a pick till 92.
I got to do something, guys.
>> I'm sorry, dude.
>> We're 13 minutes into the broadcast.
>> People on the radio like, "What the hell
is going on?"
>> All right, so he started off at
Washington State, went to Oklahoma
State, finished off at Old Miss, showed
ability at all three levels to have the
big play, have the shore hands. I'm
surprised he got to taken this high, but
I think he could live up to that
potential. It is just very interesting
that this is the first pick the 49ers
felt like making. I felt like this was
comfortably a third- round pick, but
hey, you see the yakability on display.
he has a good feel of where his
defenders are always are at. Um I I I
was a big fan of how he translated his
game to the SEC. I I want to see him
actually add a little bit more weight to
his upper frame because I think it could
help in his contested catch situations.
I think he has the frame to put on
probably five or 10 more pounds there
and benefit from it specifically in the
arms. Um but yeah, big dribbling guy and
uh yeah, I think he lands in a good spot
here.
>> Yeah. Go ahead, Zach. I'm sorry.
>> I just can't believe that they would
take him over Denzel Boston.
>> It's a couple it's it's got I got a lot
of receivers over him. I mean, if you
just want a big body that can play in
the slot, can play the X for you. Hey,
his uncle, any pro wrestler fans out
there? Don the Rock Morocco. Oh, yeah.
So, he's got that in his lineage in his
family. I don't know. I don't know who
that even is, but I put that in my
notes. It's just a little fun fact. I do
like him, Nick, but I just I didn't have
him going this high. I just think
there's better receivers on the board.
>> Miss didn't really help him. Him him
being Yak guy, I kind of wanted him to
be on the move a little bit more. They
ran a bunch of hitches and slants with
him and stuff like that. Short stuff. I
felt like that they could have
definitely helped him. But, hey, man,
shouts out to him. He's uh a little
lower on on my board. I got a couple
names ahead of him, but uh shots out the
49ers.
>> I will say one thing is very willing
blocker and if there's something that's
consistent what San Francisco wants in
the receivers, you've got to be able to
team block.
>> Here's the Cardinal selection at 34 with
James Connor
>> with the 34th pick in the N in a 220
2026 NFL draft. The Arizona Cardinals
select Chase Bantis, guard Texas A&M.
>> She's Brian's favorite player.
>> There you go. Aggies standing up. If
Brian wants to talk about him, he can
come.
>> Let's just reach all over the place,
man. Uh hey, I I you know, I I think
this is also a little high for um Chase
as well, but you know, teams are going
to love the athleticism. They're going
to love the the uh movement ability if
you're going to be doing some outside
zone stuff. Knock yourself out. Uh you
just drafted a running back to go along
with your other two running backs, so
you're going to want to keep those guys
safe there. My only thing about Chase is
that I thought he was a tackle be, you
know, because of his feet and his
athleticism, his lateral movement. uh
but you know just a a just a bit of a
catcher and I thought that you know
guard work happened a little too fast on
the inside for him. So maybe he'll work
better in these exchanges where more
patience more timing is involved but
like in at guard inside versus these one
takes three takes where like hand
fighting is is quick is it happens
quickly. I thought he let guys get into
his chest a bunch and he'll lose some of
those power exchanges or whatnot. But if
you're going to be running a bunch of
zone he should be good to go. Shouts out
to Chase.
>> I was going to say if you if you draft
Jeremiah Love, this is the guy that you
want to guard blocking for him. He's 40
for me, 6'5, 315. Uh Texas A&M, you
know, kind of had some struggles at the
quarterback position, so they tried to
go on the ground a lot and they would
run behind him. Then they they had some
good offensive linemen across that
group. Uh Trey Zoo is another guy.
Demetrius Crown over. So they had some
dudes up front that could move people in
the run game. And you know, again, if
you're Mike Laflur and you want to run
the football and you take a running back
at number three overall, give him the
most guaranteed money I think ever for a
running back, um, this is the kind of
guy that you want blocking for him.
>> I love the versatility. I mean, he's
played multiple positions along the
offensive line. He's got starts at right
guard, left guard, right tackle. He He's
wide. He's very athletic. I think he's a
better pass protector than he is run
blocker right now. For me personally, I
do think leverage is an issue at times,
but I do like the pick. I mean, I think
that he's one of these guys that can
pass off assignments well. Uh, the
inside leverage is something he needs to
do a better job about. I think he can
get beat inside. He's got some fast
hands, gets the jab going. He's got some
really dominant reps when you see him in
pass protection once he gets into his
set. I I don't mind the pick at all. I
mean, I don't think this is an overly
great offensive line draft. Personally,
>> he is a little bit of a project, but I
think he could end up being a really
good player.
>> Zack, you're an O line guy. How many
guards you got over him on your board?
Well, Pregnon for me was my top guard,
you know, which was I mean, it's not
that I didn't like Vega Yoani. They were
they were right there for me, but uh I
had Bantis as my third and then it was
Rutled, Dunker, Farmer.
>> There you go.
>> You thought Bisantes was was better than
Farmer.
>> Uh I did have him over Farmer.
>> We're not going to fuss on Friday cuz
it's, you know, it's over.
>> But you know why?
>> Okay.
>> He's got tackle flex.
>> So I just like the if you wanted to cuz
I'm with you. I think maybe his home
could be a tackle. Sure. Farmer is just
a true guard.
>> Guard. I feel that. Just getting
underway here in round two of the 2026
NFL draft. Dejon Stribbling goes 33rd
overall out of Miss to the San Francisco
49ers. And then Chase Basantis, the
guard out of Texas A&M, goes 34th
overall. The Bills have their pick in,
meaning the Raiders are on the clock 35
and 36, respectively. Let's step aside.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com. Black Carlos is
crazy.
>> Hawaiian
>> with a K.
>> Hawaiian Dejan is crazy.
>> I haven't heard clear from anybody yet,
but if that's the case, we're just going
to go with the selection.
>> We go back.
>> Well, we're we're just streaming anyway.
>> There's no commercials.
>> The Buffalo Bills select.
>> I don't know.
>> Linebacker TJ Parker from Clemson.
>> I love that system as a linebacker. That
is great.
>> That's a good fit for Buffalo.
>> It's an outside linebacker situation.
They're running the same thing that
Dallas is transitioning to. They're
actually going through a very similar
transition uh with the Buffalo Bills
with uh Jim Leonard as their new DC. But
yeah, you step TJ Parker into that role
uh of that stand up outside linebacker,
pass rusher, also been set the edge in
the run game. This is going to be a
really fun player for Buffalo. And you
know, there were times last year,
especially in the playoffs, where that
like they just got run down uh in the
run game. And this is going to be a guy
that can certainly help contain the edge
in that. And I think he has the pass
rush upside to be a really damn good
player for Buffalo.
>> Last year's film was really good. You
know, this year's film, I don't know. I
don't know what happened. You know,
changes happened, but uh plays with
length, some good power. He had a really
good senior bowl. Whooped up on
everybody down there. So hopefully that
uh that um translates to the next level.
>> As a true freshman, you thought this guy
would be a top 10 pick. I mean, he set
the Clemson record for force fumbles in
a season. Freshman record 12 and a half
tackles for loss. He's long, athletic,
he's bendy. It just it ran hot and cold
when you watched him play last year. And
it could be for v variety of reasons.
But I mean, the the athleticism, the
size, the lateral movement, all of
that's there. He could end up being one
of the steals of the draft or it could
end up not being so good.
>> 29 overall for me. I think he's a great
technician, strong punch, he's got good
hands to kind of destabilize tackles
when he goes against him. I think he has
a better get off than some folks give
him credit for, but he kind of just like
glides into his rush rather than
storming in. I would say sets the edwell
plus run defender. Even kind of has the
ability to drop back in coverage. They
did some of that with him a little bit
and cover the flats. Um again, you you
guys mentioned that turnover production
his sophomore year. Relatively quiet and
25, but kind of like we talked about
last night with some of these Clemson
guys. I I don't think I'm too concerned
with that.
>> Yeah, he's one of those guys that we
talked about through the course of the
draft show this year. Zach, I'm
interested to get your take on this.
When when you look at Clemson, they had
the college football playoff run in
2024. A lot of these guys were a part of
that run. They come back, return the
majority of their core members, and then
have a down year almost collectively as
a group, right?
>> Does that worry you at all when it comes
to these guys? And when you look up on
the board, you've got TJ Parker still
available available going into day two.
Avon Terrell still available going into
day two. it it doesn't look like it it
translated well despite maybe the talent
level that they showed in 2024.
>> Yeah, because I mean a year ago this
time uh the sickos you get done with
with the draft and you start looking
ahead to the next year and Peter Woods
who who went last night to Kansas City,
TJ Parker just went now, right? These
are all guys that were considered to be
top 10 type of players. So the question
is like what happened? Was it you guys
just got beat down, the season didn't go
the way you wanted it to and and things
didn't go your way and you mailed it in,
which isn't isn't a good thing. you're
going to lose games in the NFL. What
happens when things don't go your way
when you move up to the next level? But
the fact that it was everybody along
that defense outside of really Avon
Terrell for me, I didn't see a big dip
from from last year's tape to the year
before. Uh maybe there was something
schematically, maybe there was something
coaching, maybe some of these guys were
kind of, you know, when it comes to
sacri, you know, you don't want to
necessarily you're looking ahead, you're
peeking ahead a little bit to the next
level. Are you holding some stuff back?
I don't know. That's when it comes to us
who aren't able to to maybe talk to the
coaches all the time, talk to the
individual, learn that why, all I can do
is watch the tape. And TJ Parker is a
guy that was probably the biggest
question mark for me in the draft
because you can see it. You can see a
star, but you can also see a guy that
just runs hot and cold and makes me
extremely nervous to select. I wouldn't
have taken him in the first round. Here,
I think it's a good value pick.
>> I probably would have taken him in the
first. I had him graded as a second, but
he was number 24 on my board. He's the
highest rated edge rusher remaining.
>> So if that's the case, then I would
probably take him in the back half of
the first.
>> So like you said, value at 35 makes a
lot of sense. And for a team that is
already pretty good and close to to
making a run, they just got a really big
contributor.
All right, the 35th overall pick is now
off the board. The Buffalo Bills at 35
take TJ Parker, edge rusher, out of
Clemson. He goes with Dejon Stribbling,
the wide receiver out of Old Miss, to
the 49ers at 33. Chase Basantis, the
offensive lineman from Texas A&M to the
Cardinals at 34, then Parker at 35. The
Texans are on the clock at the moment.
>> Trade it up.
>> Traded up with the Las Vegas Raiders to
go get this pick, right?
>> Yeah. Houston gets 3617.
Vegas goes back three spots to 38 and
they get 91.
>> They've traded up a couple times now
technically.
>> Yeah, they did. They traded up yesterday
to get Reich.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know.
>> Yeah. I I
>> even you saying that doesn't sound
>> he could have took relish right here.
>> Probably could have.
>> Who knows, man? You know, I
>> I would think
>> corner.
>> I would think defensive tackle here.
>> Oh, McDonald.
>> McDonald still there. He's the second
best player.
>> That make a lot of sense. I think there
was a lot of love for for McDonald in
Houston.
>> Let it be linebacker so we could talk
about a trademark potentially.
>> Ah,
little dramatic, don't you think? Wow.
>> Original Houston Texan
>> scored the first touchdown for the
Texans both in preseason and regular
season. A record game
>> with the 36th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Houston Texans select Kaden
McDonald.
>> All right, there it is.
>> Defense tackle.
>> That's a great pick.
>> Gosh, a great defense.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Nobody's going to be able to score
against these guys next year.
>> Tell me about them, Tommy.
>> Yeah. Uh, I think he's just a massive
human being who's going to plug up a ton
in the middle of the field. You think
about the pass rushers that they've got.
Will Anderson, uh, who they paid a bunch
of money to, Neil Hunter, who they also
paid a bunch of money to, and the pass
rush production that they had. This is a
guy who's going to be able to help them
in the middle stop the run. That's where
Houston's defense, if they had any kind
of weakness, was maybe a little bit
weaker in some senses. Kater McDonald
changes that. And I think that you plug
him in, it knows he's a plug-and-play
starter. Better get off than I expected
for a guy his size. at times he kind of
plays high but he's got the strength to
make up for it and win still in some of
those instances when he is in the right
spot he's so hard to move takes up
multiple blocks eats up space uh really
like I said especially strong in the run
game and closing gaps he's going to let
those linebackers come down the field
and fill in their respective spots not
going to give you too much as a pass
rusher but he does have the effort there
strong and stack and shed and with some
more refined technique he's going to be
a really good player in this league
>> your old trash can full of dirt type of
dude right there I mean he's a big guy I
You think you're right, Tommy. He lacks
consistent pass rush, but he shows some
flashes. He He's more of your typical
space heater that can play the run.
Occasionally he'll bully lineman into
the lap of the quarterback, but he is a
really good player that holds his ground
at the point of attack. Uh I mean to me,
you needed to probably get ahead of
Vegas is kind of what some of the
whispers were today at 38. The Raiders
might have pulled the trigger here. So
if they had eyed Kade McD McDonald, it
makes sense that you got to move up to
go get him. and they go up to get him at
36 overall off the board. Now, we talked
a little bit yesterday uh about
yesterday uh today. We got the chance to
to finally get to see Caleb DS and
Malachi Lawrence in the building and and
get to share some special moments with
them as they get their first look of the
star as a part of the Cowboys
organization. Get to meet the front
office, talk with coaches. Nick, I know
you were kind of in the middle of all of
that. What stood out to you about their
first day at the Star and kind of their
introduction to the franchise?
>> Yeah, you could tell they hadn't gotten
a lot of sleep. Caleb, Caleb was walking
through, he's like, "Man, I kind of feel
like a zombie a little bit." But, uh,
no, it's really cool. That's one of the
coolest pressers of the year. And it's
cool that we got two of them this year.
Uh, and just a really cool moment. And
when they step off the bus and they're
greeted by everybody. Um, you know, it's
it's it's it's an awesome experience.
And I think, you know, hearing Caleb DS
talk and understanding how intentional
he is, understanding the quote unquote
brain works, um, you know, method that
Brian Shottenheimr and Christian Parker
in this front office have hammered so
much over the course of this off season.
You see that show up with Caleb DS, even
in a setting like that. Uh, and then
hearing his dad talk outside the press
conference room after just about how
Caleb has always been, how he's taken on
that NFL pedigree from his father and
his older brother Josh DS. Just really
cool to see. And then Malachi Lawrence
uh comes in and he has this kind of aura
about him in the sense of uh nothing is
too big for him and everything feels
really grounded and I think that's
really important. Uh coming from Central
Florida arriving here at the Cowboys I I
specifically asked him I was like hey
how do you know that you're going to be
ready for this spotlight and he said God
wouldn't have put me here if he didn't
think I was ready. And so I have to
trust that. And so I'm I'm I'm excited
to see what both of these guys provide
to the defense. Uh it's going to be a
lot of fun to see what their fits look
like specifically after today if they
come away say with another DB or with
another edge rusher. Uh it could be
could be fun to see what that looks
like.
>> Tommy, what did you take away? This is
only your your second draft, but it's
the first one with multiple first round
picks
>> that you've had to to kind of sift
through in one day.
>> Yeah, Caleb DS I think is as advertised.
Um, we you talk about his intelligence,
the football pedigree that is in his
mind from a family of football, not just
his dad, his brother, his uncle, his
cousins who play college football. You
you can tell that so many people have
poured into him. And you add that to the
fact that the game just kind of comes
naturally to him. That's what kept
coming up when talking to him was, you
know, from the time that he was 6 years
old when he started playing football,
the game just came easy to him and and
it stayed that way throughout the course
of his career. And Nick, you mentioned
being ready for this. If if there's
anybody that's built for playing for the
Dallas Cowboys and everything that comes
with that, it's Caleb DS. He was a
five-star recruit in high school,
playing at Alabama, Ohio State, and now
the Dallas Cowboys. Those are not easy
programs to play for. There's so much
pedigree and pressure that comes from
playing at those universities and those
programs. And it's no different here in
Dallas. So, he is built he was built for
this and he's built for the NFL. And
it's going to be really fun to watch him
play.
>> The media circus has followed him from
his high school years. Yeah, I'd say
>> is ultimately what it is. So, today was
no different. It was a little bit
different for for Malachi Lawrence. I
thought I thought there were
>> He was very real in his press
conference, which I thought was really
cool. I I had the pleasure of riding on
the the the Cowboys bus back from the
the airport with him, got an interview
with him, and he's so down to earth, and
you could tell loyalty means a lot to
him, and you could tell that uh his his
family is is where he's grounded, but uh
he keeps kind of a small circle. He
might be a little bit more reserved uh
as an individual, but man, when it comes
to football, he's all business and it
was it was really cool getting to kind
of talk to him. I know you were on the
bus with with Caleb. What stood out to
you there?
>> Well, real quick about Malachi. You talk
about loyalty. Stayed at UCF all five
years. He registered his first year,
then still stayed about a month after he
he signed as I'll wait for this.
>> Here's the Giants selection at 37 with
Roger.
>> He played for the Giants. What a great
man he is. With the 37th pick in the
2026 NFL draft, the New York Giants
select, Colton Hood.
>> Wow.
>> Defensive.
>> Yeah, this is going to be very
fascinating.
>> Way to go.
>> That's tough. That's a good player going
to the Giants at 37 after they had the
top 10 hall of Arll Reese and Francis
Malaninoa. Now they get probably the
best corner remaining in the draft. FCH.
>> Yeah, man. um physical press man, long
arms, aggressive, don't care, pins
people to the sideline, great tackler,
um super aggressive in the run game
actually. Like there was this one play I
was watching. He was on the opposite
side of the field and his job is to just
be at home and the runner came all the
way back to the other side of the field.
He was just a heat-seeking miss. I
believe is this play. No, it ain't this
play. But it's but but Cotton Hood was a
guy that he should have gone first
round. I was a big fan of him. If the
Cowboys would have taken him at 23, I
would have been elated. We got Malachi,
and I love Malachi as well. But, uh,
boy, this this hall that the, uh, Giants
are putting together is really making me
sick right now as a Cowboy fan.
>> Got a good draft. They really do with
Reese Ma Noah. I mean, thank them for
allowing the Cowboys to land downs by
taking Ma Noah at 10. But,
>> thanks, Giants.
>> Now, you had Hood. Uh, that's certainly
a heck of a draft class there. I mean, I
I think he is an outside player. Maybe
there was some versatility to kick
inside and play some nickel, but I I
think the physicality with him is really
what stands out. I mean, this is a dude
that's willing to come downhill and hit
you. Really good athlete, runs well. You
look back to his high school days,
played baseball, basketball, multiport
athlete, just physical as all hell. I
mean, this is really I was pretty darn
surprised he didn't go in round one.
Yeah.
>> So, to get him here at 37, I think he
was my 16th best player.
>> So, this is uh this one hurts being in
the division.
>> 19 for me as well. Yeah,
>> that's good good thought there, Nick.
Yeah, when you look at Colton Hood, why
did he slip? What could you could you
just attribute it to
>> teams or rather draft people that's not
as good as him?
>> Okay,
>> that's how the game goes.
>> Is that how it goes?
>> Colton Hood is nice. Everybody could use
value. It's not that type of
flexibility.
>> He's a corner. He can play. He's He's
unanimously everybody's uh, you know,
best corner left over, not named Jamal
McCoy.
>> We've got some fist pumping in the
Cowboys war room here. Stephen Jones was
on the phone for a little bit.
>> Um, so we'll see what what happens
there,
>> but yeah, there was
>> there's no way they're trading this high
unless they take next year's it have to
be what? Next year's three.
>> Do they have a three next year? I'd have
to look at their their next couple.
Here's the Raiders selection at 38. Let
me just say
I would be remiss without bringing up
the late great Willie Brown when he
would tell all of you
>> happy Mother's Day
>> to remember your mother on Mother's Day
is coming right up. All you guys take
her to dinner, grab her some flowers,
tell her
>> appreciate that.
I'm actually writing when
>> it's coming up. That's what he said.
are saying uh not this
>> Vegas Raiders select
>> Traden Stokes.
>> Oh,
>> defensive back Arizona.
>> Traden Stokes. Wow. Couple really good
players flying off the board here. Let
me recap just for a second. 35 TJ Parker
to the Bills. The edge rusher from
Clemson. Uh Kaden McDonald, the
defensive tackle from Ohio State goes to
the Texans at 36. 37 Colton Hood corner
from Tennessee goes to the Giants. And
then at 38, traded Stuke, safety out of
Arizona, who I know Dallas sort of
looked at uh throughout the draft
process and and had some contact with as
well as he goes off the board to the
Raiders. Good pick by the Raiders. First
team all Big 12 honore last year. Tell
me a little bit about him, Tom.
>> Super versatile. Super versatile. This
kid can play basically any position in
the secondary. Safety, corner, nickel.
Um he can really do it all. and he he's
part of an Arizona secondary that had
like Nick likes to call them the the two
trees on the outside, the big corners.
And this was a guy that they could kind
of move around and have him do a lot of
different things. And as the process
went along and there were more events
that went on, the combine was really big
for him. He just starts continuing to
climb higher and higher. Then you watch
the film and you see the coverage
ability. You see that play right there
where he's able to stack and shed a
little bit and make a play in the run
game. Just a guy who has great range.
you can see him kind of turn his hips
late there and still come back and get
to the football. Um he's a really solid
player with a very high ceiling.
>> Yeah, I mean this dude first team all
Big 12 walk- on there uh at at Arizona.
He it's really a great story. He's the
versatility 100%. Can close quickly,
tackle in space. Some of the plays that
he makes in coverage is unbelievable. I
He covers ground, flips his hips, is
able to play the ball in the air.
There's times where he looks like a wide
receiver. The ability to undercut it.
You see it there with the long arm being
able to swat that thing down. He's a
hell of a player.
>> Yeah, this was my most versatile
defensive back in the entire class. Him
and then Jaylen Kilgore was right behind
him for me. The only reason I gave uh
Stokes the the edge is because I truly
think he can play any single position in
the secondary. I do wonder if maybe he's
a uh jack of all trades, master of none.
Uh but I I put him as a safety uh on my
board. I want to see him play in space,
but I I would definitely if I'm a team
bringing him in in the Las Vegas Raiders
in this instance, I am bringing him in
and I'm giving him so many nickel snaps
because I want to see what that
physicality looks like close to the line
of scrimmage. I I am a big Stuks guy. Uh
had him at 20 overall on my board. He
was my fourth uh graded second rounder.
I I I really like trading Stuks.
>> All right, the Browns have their pick in
at 39, meaning that the Chiefs are on
the clock at 40. We're still 52 picks
away from where the Cowboys will next be
on the clock with the 92nd overall pick
in the NFL draft. We're going to step
aside for a matter of moments, but
before we do, roll into your next
tailgate in style with your own Club
Car, the official golf car of the Dallas
Cowboys. Club Car lowspeed vehicles
deliver the performance and quality that
Cowboys fans expect with the features
and comfort that you command. Visit
clubcar.com
today. Hey, you're listening to the 2026
NFL draft on the DallasCowboys radio
network and DallasCowboys.com.
>> All right, back here on the
DallasCowboys.com side of things
>> since we're on the.com side of things.
There's a lot of excitement in the war
room here. Can we take the the war room?
>> Christian Parker just came through. Got
a little bit going to get the
linebacker.
>> There's Scott Simons, the linebacker's
coach, getting fist bumps, too. Jark,
assistant linebacker's coach. So, this
has got to be a linebacker here.
>> That's fascinating.
>> It doesn't look like a a trade up,
though. It doesn't look like they
drafted a linebacker, right?
>> Is this Would this be a possible trade?
>> It could be. It could be.
>> Oh, yeah. They're clapping.
>> Yeah, something's gone down.
>> This is very interesting because Dallas
not on the clock as I just outlined. 52
picks away. Usually, if trade talks are
happening, this is where this is where
draft weekend is just my favorite. I
love this. M
>> you don't get the chance to see the
reaction in the room and the type of
live conversations like this if they're
making a roster move period. Now you get
the chance to kind of get an inside look
and we're we're going to break it down
as it goes along. But that's the
director of PR, Tad Carper. Um apologies
if that's not his official title. I know
he's the just head of Cowboys PR, but
>> senior vice president of communications.
>> Yeah, see there's a way better official
title. Thank you. Uh he's in there. That
means at some point it'll be released
and the news will break. But the Cowboys
making some making some noise in the war
room at the moment. There's Jerry Jones
walking back in.
>> I've got a Tad Carper note for you.
Caleb DS was a big fan of his uh quote
drip when he arrived.
>> All right, there you go.
>> Quote drip. Speaking of Tads
specifically,
>> yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Speaking of I like it specifically.
>> All right. Here's the Brown selection at
pick number 39. Important note there is
drip per se.
>> Hello hello hello.
>> We are here to announce the 39th pick
for our Cleveland Browns with the 39th
pick in the 2026 NFL draft. The
Cleveland Browns select Denzel Boston
wide receiver.
There you go.
>> Yeah. One of the top wide receivers
remaining in the draft goes to Cleveland
and the Browns. Tell me about him. Zack
Walche.
>> I really did love Denzel Boston. from
Washington team captain. Uh this dude
was an all Big 12 uh excuse me, pack 12
return specialist before they moved over
to the Big 10. The body control is
phenomenal with him. I love the way he
can adjust to the football. The frame
that he's got, he's your your
prototypical kind of X body that can
also slide in, play some slot for you.
He can box people out, can work back to
the football. He high points the ball
really, really well. And he's a talker.
He talks and he lets you know when he
makes a play. very competitive, strong
hands, not an easy guy to bring down.
You'll see a lot of drags, you'll see a
lot of crossers with him. He's also used
in the screen game. He threw for a
touchdown in the game against Illinois.
He's not a burner, but he just finds a
way to consistently find a way to get
behind the defense. Super physical
blocker. I I think he's got an
impressive blend of size and speed. He
kind of reminded me the way he plays of
an Anqua Balden, if you want a little
bit of a throwback type of name. I I
love Denzel Boston. He was my wide
receiver for
>> red zone threat. But I think the big
question people going to have for him is
is he a big slot guy or is he going to
be a true outside dude. I think he could
do everything. I just think Washington
chose to uh play him on the inside
there. But uh hey man, fantastic player,
great catches, uh jump ball guy as well,
catch radius guy. Now quarterbacks have
to kind of put the ball on them. So if
you're the Browns and you know and you
you know maybe questioning your
quarterback's accuracy there, Shador and
whoever is going to be competing over
there, that's going to be a question for
you. But uh he is also a bad ball
catcher so that'll help out.
>> So getting close to getting back on the
radio.
>> They also they took Casey Conpsion last
night, didn't they? Yes, sir. They got
Conpion in Boston. It's pretty nice.
>> Nice little duo of rookie wide
receivers. Here's the Chiefs at pick 40.
>> Hello Pittsburgh
and hell to pit.
With the 40th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft,
the Kansas City Chiefs select
R. Mason Thomas, defensive end,
Oklahoma.
>> R. Mason Thomas, edge rusher from OU,
goes to the Kansas City Chiefs at pick
number 40 overall. We are in the second
round of the 2026 NFL draft. Recapping
the last five selections, starting with
the Texans at pick number 36. It goes
Katie McDonald, interior defensive line
out of Ohio State. The Giants take
Colton Hood, corner from Tennessee, at
pick 37. The Raiders take Trayden Stuks,
the safety from Arizona at pick 38. The
Browns at 39, take Denzel Boston, the
wide receiver from Washington. And then
as you just heard, the Chiefs at pick 40
take RMason Thomas, talented edge rusher
out of Oklahoma. Bursty upfield rusher.
Gets to the back hip quickly. He had a
really good fight with Kaden Proctor at
Alabama. Good stuff there. Bunch of
different moves, man. Swipes, rips,
clubs. He mixes everything up well.
Flattens to the to the um quarterback
well. Finishes well. And I I I have him
ranked 18 because I thought he did it
verse like great competition versus good
SEC tackles. Uh so go out there, watch a
film on him. I hate that he that he that
he got this late. I I thought he was
going to be a cowboy guy, but uh hey,
shouts out to him.
>> Why would he not be a cowboy guy?
>> Cuz we ain't draft
but why was
>> I mean
>> why was he never in the same
conversation as Malachi Lawrence and
Kendrick Fall? would love to to text the
peoples over there and figure it out.
But I guess the
>> I don't know if he's like not arm length
guy, but you know he I guess Mal
Lawrence got you know has better
measurables than him I guess. But I'm
more so like production guy and if you
can whoop up on tackles that are getting
drafted in the first round that means
something to me in arms by the way.
>> So that's that seems to be the the move
there. There we go.
>> He's a fun player though. I mean you can
see him switch sides. He'll switch his
stances. Two point four point hand in
the ground. relentless type of player. I
I I think the the first step quickness
with him, very explosive. He can close
ground in a hurry. Uh he's just got a
nasty bull rush. South Carolina, he
dominated that game. I like the power.
He's got counter moves as well. He he's
one of these guys that's just a good
all-around football player. I don't
think he gets enough credit for his run
defense in my opinion. I I like this
value here for Rmes Thomas. I thought he
could have snuck into the bottom of the
first
26 NFL draft. The Cincinnati Bengals
select Cashes How defensive end Texas&M.
>> Speaking of short arms,
>> another short armed pass rusher that
burst really well off the line of
scrimmage. Ben Flattens pass rush fu. Uh
had a another matchup versus another
first round uh talent, Francinoa, you
know what I mean? Some people thought
that Cash has kind of disappeared in big
games or whatnot, but throughout the
year I felt like Cashes was a dude
that's like super competitive, super
feisty. Uh, you know, kind of needs some
improvement in the run game or whatever,
the frame is going to be a question
there. But outside linebacker, you know,
ready to pass rush day one, he gets
sacks. I just trust that if dudes can
get sacks in college, they can get sacks
in the league. So, both these guys back
toback, I would imagine the outside
linebacker edge rush dudes, uh, that
that run's about to happen.
Yeah, might you may already have
started. TJ Parker goes to 35 down.
Yeah.
>> Mason Thomas goes to 40. Cashes at 41.
Yeah. Saints, Dolphins, Jets, Ravens,
Buccaneers, the next five up with
starting with the Saints at pick number
42. Still trying to decipher what's
happening in the Cowboys war room. When
we went to break uh on the radio side of
things, the uh Cowboys war room exploded
a little bit, not as it would for a
possible selection, but high-fives were
happening. Christian Parker walked in
the room, Scott Simons, the linebacker's
coach, was in the room, and there was a
lot of jubilation for the Cowboys
despite being 50 picks away until their
next selection. Nick, are you hearing
anything based off of your connections
and what could possibly be happening? I
know trade up scenarios have been in the
conversation, but this could be a number
of things.
>> Yeah, based on the clapping and the
people that walked in the room and them
not picking up a phone and not
necessarily hearing anything about
movement, I wonder if this is something
for a veteran. Um, and with Scott Simons
walking in the room, we've talked a lot
about, you know, linebacker being a
trade target. Here's a Saints selection
here at 42.
>> 42 pick in the 2026 NFL draft. The New
Orleans Saints select Kristen Miller
dtackle Georgia.
>> So pressure Miller off the board.
Another good defensive tackle out of the
SECC.
Continue on with your your thought
there, Nick. For sure, please.
>> Yeah, that that was mainly it.
>> Oh, okay. Just double check.
>> So, so Nick, let me just let me just
just hypothetically, right? You know,
with the whole uh saga that happened
with the Crosby trade, if we're in a
draft day trading for a player type
situation, like what does that look
like? and like you have to pass your
physical type stuff. Like how does that
work? Do you fly a doctor out there real
fast before we get to one of these picks
and go, "All right, how does he look?"
And then they give you the call and then
the trade happens. Like how does that
how does that work?
>> Yeah, it could happen in a a varying
different ways. Um I I think with uh you
know, a specific around draft time, um
you have conversations leading into the
draft and if you look at it from the
Cowboys perspective, it's like, "All
right, let's see if the board somehow
falls for Sunny Styles and if that's the
player we come away with, then we don't
have to do anything." But if we get to
night two, hey, let's kick up
conversation with a couple of teams that
we've already been working with over the
course of the last couple of weeks and
revisit those conversations. And that
could happen now. That could happen
after the draft. There's some varying
different possibilities now that they
have the extra fourth rounders, too.
>> I almost wonder if they could find a
veteran out there that you don't
necessarily have to pick the third or
trade off the third. And so there's a
lot of different ways this can go.
>> I'm fairly confident, I don't want to
say 100%, but I'm fairly confident
they've traded for a veteran linebacker.
Come get a lot of sense.
>> Your team bad dog. Come get
>> on the phone again. Okay.
>> Who's Stephen talking to?
>> Who is that sitting next to Stephen?
>> Uh where to his right?
>> Both of them. Who them?
>> Yeah. Shbo's on the right. John Steven
Jones is on the left.
>> Okay. What they do? They do contracts.
>> No, they are uh family members.
>> Oh, they just kicking.
>> Yeah, they're part of the Jones family.
>> Gotcha. Got you.
>> They're they're probably the future
regime. It's a good way to put it.
>> Okay. Cool. Cool. Cool. Cool.
>> I never met them. Pardon me. Yeah,
they're they're good good dudes.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Uh you've got Brian Shottenheimer there
at the corner. Jerry Jones just got up
talking. Jerry Junior's on the left side
of the screen.
>> And then you've got
uh couple different individuals
scattered throughout, but in and out of
the room. Not a ton going on in terms of
scouts. I don't see a single scout other
than Will Mcclelay on the right. And
there's Chris Hall there, too. And here
comes Mitchell Point. Applause though.
Like it was a smattering of an applause.
>> Just immediately gets immediately every
single one of them out of the woodworks.
>> Smathering of an applause. I would love
to know what happens.
>> All right. We are we can we can we say
>> Hold on. It's conf It's out there.
>> It Let's say reports are cuz I I don't
know what we're allowed to say. Yeah,
man.
>> But just say reports are cuz if it's out
there,
>> tag me on Twitter.
>> Reports from the Fort Worth Star
Telegram and from NFL Network and from
the rest of the world. Hold on. WAIT A
MINUTE, NICK. WAIT a minute. Poke your
chest out when you say it. No, I'm just
playing. It was NFL Network first on
this Ian Rapa Report. Uh the Dallas
Cowboys trading for San Francisco 49ers
linebacker D Winters. U so D Winters was
a 17game starter last season. It was his
first season in a full-time starting
role. He's had some different roles for
that San Francisco middle level. I think
this is probably a situation where
you're looking at the board, you're not
necessarily seeing a guy you're super
comfortable with being the starting
middle linebacker, and you get a guy
that you at least feel good about the
floor of. And I think that's D. Winters
>> TCU
>> reportedly. Allegedly.
>> Allegedly, whatever it ends up being if
if it's 2023 tape. I know Beamer's got
some in the archives back there. I
wonder if we could find some TCU tape.
Go see what's happening. Uh out of
Brennham, Texas, uh initially went to
Burton High School. Uh was drafted in
the sixth round back
>> in high school.
>> Uh
>> I think he played wide receiver if I
remember correct.
>> He was a two-way player. Played football
at Brooklyn. He was a good receiver,
>> primarily used as wide receiver. He was
a three star recruit, 87th best player
in the state, committed to TCU over uh
Arkansas, Northwestern, Arizona State,
and Texas Tech, according to Wikipedia.
So,
>> wow.
>> Uh, all Big 12 first teamer back in
2022. So, as we continue to sort that
along, that's what the reports are out
there. Welcome in, Bobby Belt. Bobby,
what's going on, dude?
>> Garcia.
>> Chilling.
>> Just chilling. Trading for a linebacker.
Yeah, I uh I was trying to chill. I
couldn't chill. I'm
>> going to try and see if I can pull up
the notes from 2023.
>> What uh what are your thoughts on the
linebacker possibility? We don't know
any compensation yet, right?
>> Uh I don't believe so. I don't believe
that's anything's out there yet. Boy,
these are loud headphones. Nick is deaf.
>> I'll pray for Nick.
>> He took him off, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Um let me see if we figured out
compensation yet.
if we've reportedly figured out
compensation.
>> This is probably really bad radio at the
moment just because we're just trying to
figure out exactly what's happening
across the board. But um
>> this is why you turn into uh tune in to
the draft show though. This is the type
we we saw the war room react. We're the
only ones with that type of access
across the board. But, uh, the pick is
in for the Miami Dolphins at pick number
43 at the moment.
After the Saints take Christian Miller
at 42, what was your audible reaction
there?
>> Uh, nothing. I was just reading that
text.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Yeah, but like what it say?
>> You said who out loud? You want to
>> I didn't mean to. By the way, uh,
reportedly from, uh, Ian Raport says it
is a fifth rounder for Dwinners.
>> Okay. All right, man. Cool. I mean,
started all 17 games last year for the
49ers. Has uh I mean, Nick Sornson's
obviously familiar with him. Um
>> somebody who I think if you're just want
to talk about reliable starting
experience stepping in here to couple
with a rookie, perfectly fine with this
Drake as the Dolphins are coming up.
>> I think he's got some versatility like
he can play in and out. I'm just looking
back at the TCU notes.
>> Football fans out there. With the 43rd
pick in the 2026 NFL draft, the Miami
Dolphins select Jacob Rodriguez,
linebacker, Texas State.
>> That's where the That's where the sigh
was headed.
>> Hey, Zach, you all right, bro?
>> Yeah. Okay. He Hey, here's the thing.
You should feel good.
>> Just traded for a linebacker.
>> He went He went all good. He did. And
you know what?
>> That means he's a good player.
>> Oh, he's a great player. I mean, Miami
is cleaning up. They got a couple of my
guys here in Chris Johnson, the corner
from San Diego State. Jacob Rodriguez is
just a playmaker. They're getting
themselves uh a heck of a player here. A
guy that can go ahead and take the
football away. Probably a future yellow
jacket uh kind of guy, gold jacket guy.
And hey, Zack Thomas was a comp for him.
He's going to play for the Miami
Dolphins now, so that continues. But
this is just the type of guy that you
want to have within your organization.
Leadership, hard worker, tremendous
football IQ. I thought he was a better
cover guy than others did. He does have
some issues, I think, when it comes to
depth at times, but the peanut punch is
out of control with him. Sideline to
sideline versatility. Good blitzer. I
loved him. I mean, I had him as my 21st
best player. Uh, for him going here at
43, I think there were definitely some
teams that were eyeing him. I I thought
even bottom of the first, I know Bobby
was like, "No, no, no, that's not
happening." You were right about that.
But this is a hell of a player in space.
It's a sure tackler. Uh, good for Miami.
They're cleaning up. They're having
themselves a nice draft.
>> Keys well creates turnovers and all this
kind of good stuff, man. I love me in
the run game. I love the linebackers
that don't get fooled easily, man. So,
man, I I I feel for you, Will Chuck.
>> It's all good. It's all good. Hey,
>> I got hope I got gold, but your hope for
Rodriguez is gone.
>> We had no chance to get him with him
going at 43. That that wasn't going to
happen.
>> We I mean, we got Quinn Williams. That's
why we couldn't get Jacob Rodriguez.
>> Hey, that's a good consolation. I And at
least he's not in the NFC East.
>> There you go.
>> So, you're out there. You're in the AFC.
Jacob Rodriguez, you go ball out like I
know you will, my man. I feel like he's
gonna he's gonna play well in that
system, too. And and it he played his
final collegiate game in that stadium.
>> He did. If you think about it, he did in
that Oregon game in the the college
football.
>> Bad memories for him.
>> Yeah. Didn't play quite well. Uh Detroit
just traded up to the 44th pick with the
New York Jets. And here comes Megatron
to make the selection at pick 44.
>> I'm going to say I love how they just
getting these picks out there. Like I I
>> They're rolling. What up do Pittsburgh
with the 44th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Detroit Lions select Derek
Moore, defensive end, Michigan.
>> So there goes Derek Moore.
>> I like Derek Moore. Edge out of
Michigan.
>> Pass rusher bursty off the line of
scrimmage. He got three moves, but he's
really good at those three moves. He
took those three moves to the senior
bowl and whoop people with those three
moves. uh kind of going to uh grow in
the run game a little bit, but fun but
fun player. Him and um Jan Barum at
Michigan was like really chasing down
quarterbacks for fun there. So that's a
pretty good player.
>> He's the bull rush king, man. I mean,
his bull rush was one of the nastiest I
thought in the entire draft. He'll run
right through you.
>> Bull rush, rip outside on the swim.
>> Oh my gosh, he plays with so much power.
You're right about the initial burst at
the snap. He can get on to lineman in a
hurry the first step. Does a good job
attacking that outside shoulder. Then he
gets that bend going. He can stunt
inside, rush the B gap. It's just, you
bring up Michigan defensive lineman.
It's it's PTSD. I understand it. But
this is a really, really good player.
Team captain, three-time all Big 10
selection, 23 starts across 53 games,
team leading uh and with 10 and a half
tackles for loss, double digit sacks.
This is a nice pick here that can
compliment Aiden Hutchinson. Get a
couple Michigan Wolverines on that edge.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. The trade is officially
official, by the way. Tommy Yarish, tell
me about the the official compensation
and what the trade that Dallas just
ended up making looks like.
>> Yeah, Bobby called it earlier. This is a
fifth round pick, 152 overall going to
the San Francisco 49ers for Dwinners,
linebacker uh out of TCU, who just
wrapped up his third year in San
Francisco, had his first 100 yard or
excuse me, 100 tackle season last year
for the 49ers. So, um, this is a guy
that given Dallas's current linebacker
room, certainly raises the floor. Um,
and like Bobby mentioned, he's worked
with Nick Sorenson, the Cowboy special
teams coordinator in the past. Uh, you
know, that's not to say that this I
don't think this takes away a
possibility of Dallas taking a
linebacker at 92 or even in the fourth
round if they get to that point. Um, so
what it does mean though is that Dallas
does not have a fifth round pick
anymore. remember they traded uh two of
them to the Dolphins yesterday to move
up one spot and get Caleb DS. That was
their final remaining fifth round pick.
>> And I'm going to watch film on Dwinners
while we sit right here.
>> You're going to go ahead and just live
watching. I'm going to watch 50 picks
still left to go until the Cowboys. We
ain't got nothing else to do.
>> Got plenty of time.
>> They've already picked sort of.
>> Yeah, true.
>> I mean, but you know, but you know, you
know, while they're making picks, you
can still like popcorn read on me and I
can give a report on whoever got
drafted. But just in the meantime, I'm
going to be watching Dinner
>> and we're going to do that on the other
side of the break. You're listening to
the 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
Radio Network and DallasCowboys.com.
>> All right, internet side of things,
welcome back in. Kind of exciting stuff.
You get to watch a little bit of live
trade negotiations. Wonder if we get
secret audio from that.
>> Kyle, let me just say this. Let me just
say this.
>> Caleb DS. Malachi Lawrence,
>> Quinnon Williams, George Pickkins. You
got a couple of fours and D Wyinners is
your five. Hell of a draft already.
>> Yeah, you feel pretty good about that.
>> Good depth. I like what you're doing
here.
>> It's good stuff.
>> We got to need to figure out a way to
trade with Miami.
>> Hold on. Y
>> can't talk.
>> Hello. Brian brought us tampering. We're
on the DallasCowboys.com side.
>> On the radio side of things, this is us
trying to untangle
>> this tangled web. We weave. Yeah.
>> Did it is it finally taken care of over
here?
>> Almost. We're getting out of there.
>> Hold on, Tommy. Give me two seconds,
Tom. I got
>> You know what? You're a genius.
>> I know. I I know everybody likes to talk
about day three as being the wild day. I
do feel we tend to get the most wheels
off on day two actually
>> of of our coverage.
>> Like, yeah, I feel like us as a
>> You haven't been part of day three for
the last couple years.
>> Well, I mean, I was a I think that me as
somebody who is observing day three
exclusively uh those two days. I I
haven't sense of it. I have a good I
have a good sense of it. Um I would just
say that day two cuz day two was we got
Caroftus a couple years ago.
>> Caroftus.
>> Yeah. I I think it's just because it's
the lull a little bit. Like day three
you know you're digging in. You're ready
for it. Day two
>> you're you're still kind of I think on
first round vibes, but then you get into
it and you're like this isn't quite
first round and you start getting a
little loopy at times.
>> And the the reason I I do agree with you
to a certain extent is because day two
is a long day for us across the board.
You've got radio shows in the morning.
You got to get up and go. All of us are
here at the Star for the first round
draft pick coming in and and doing his
tour of the facility and the press
conference and all that. And then you
turn around and usually when this day is
over, you turn you you finish whatever
you've got to finish after the draft is
over and then you go sleep for a couple
hours and then get back up here quick.
>> Last night you're kind of trying to
figure out what's happening with Dallas
and linebackers and all sorts of stuff
>> or not, Nick. I'm forcing my over here,
Kyle.
>> Yeah, go for it.
>> Welcome in Brian Bratis. How
>> Thank you. Appreciate that. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you. Hopefully I have a
little bit of a scoundy report. I've got
some connections around that would might
know this guy. So, but I heard he is a
really good kid. I'm talking about the
guy we traded. He winners. I heard he
was a good guy and I and hopefully I'll
have a thumbnail for you here in just a
little bit about the player.
>> Do you want to talk about that when we
get back on the radio side or you need
>> Yeah, I when I get I don't have the
thumbnail yet. My guy's running some
stuff down, but he's give me a thumb.
>> Who's your biggest pen throw so far?
>> You know what? I tell you what, it was
the way my board's stacked right now,
it's it's actually I I didn't get these
corners right. I just didn't get the
corners right. And
>> you know, I still have I still with Hood
going off and and guys like that, you
know, that that helps. But I I think
there's I think there's some questions
about with the the speed uh with
Terrell. I I I just, you know, you worry
about that a little bit. the injury
stuff of course with McCoy. I've got the
a do actually a trainer told me what's
we get to McCoy. I got completely what's
wrong with him. I got I got to tell you
exactly what's wrong with the with the
young man and why teams might not deal
with him at all today
>> or at any time.
>> I do want to get back into that here in
a second. Here's the Raven selection and
pick 45.
>> We got a SPECIAL MESSAGE FOR Y'ALL.
Pittsburgh
>> Steelers still suck. Oh boy.
>> That was pretty good.
>> Tell me about that. YOU GOT A PROBLEM
WITH THAT, COME SEE ME. BIG TRUST BLOCK
NATION in the flesh.
>> Oh boy.
>> Yes, sir.
>> All right. All right. All right. Now,
for real, I'D LIKE TO GIVE A SPECIAL
SHOUT OUT TO THESE YOUNG WOMEN STANDING
ALONGSIDE me tonight who HAVE BEEN
PLAYING FLAG FOOTBALL at the high school
level in Maryland.
THANKS TO THE EFFORTS FROM MY BALTIMORE
RAVENS AND THE MPSSA,
THEY LAUNCHED a program in 2023 that can
make this DAY POSSIBLE. THEY ARE HERE
TODAY CELEBRATING A STATE SANCTION that
passed for high school girls flag
football in Maryland, OFFICIALLY making
it a state championship sport.
Congratulations
>> for everybody listening on the radio
side. This is Mark Ingram at the podium
with the Ravens selection at pick number
>> IN THE 2026 NFL DRAFT. THE BALTIMORE
RAVENS SELECT ZION YOUNG. LINEBACKER
MISSOURI.
>> That's a good player going to Baltimore
again. Zion Young, Missouri edge rusher
is now a Raven. Plus, as of a couple
moments ago on the Dallas Cowboys social
media side, we know our opponent in week
three as a part of the Rio game down in
Brazil, the Dallas Cowboys.
>> They're not taking on the Houston
Oilers. They're taking on the Baltimore
Ravens.
>> Oh,
>> in that matchup. So, it is week three,
Ravens versus Cowboys, September 27th
down in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.
>> That's going to be a tough physical
game. It's going to be
>> they have to travel all that way and and
play that game.
>> I'll be fascinated to see how the
schedule around that shakes out. That's
going to be just as difficult as
whatever actually is going on in that
week three.
>> And not only to mention you got to now
play a physical football team.
>> Yeah, you're going to get beat up on the
field and off the field.
>> Well, you're going to beat them up, too.
But man, that's going to be a tough trip
to have to deal with the Ravens. You
know, that's not going to be easy. As we
go into hour number two of our day two
coverage here of the 2026 NFL draft on
the Cowboys radio network and on
dallascowboys.com.
We're here with Vox Lombardi from
YouTube, Crown Global Media, and a
number of different platforms from 1053
The Fan. We've got Brian Bratis in
studio. Welcome in, sir.
>> Thank you. Appreciate that.
>> And then we've got Bobby Belt in studio
as well. We're also joined by Tommy
Yarish, Nick Harris, Zack Walchuk, who
are rotating in and out at the moment.
And I believe Nick Harris uh currently
working on the trade news for Dwinters.
The Cowboys send a fifth round pick to
the San Francisco 49ers to take Winters
who started all 17 games for the 49ers
last year. Here's the Buccaneers
selection at pick 46.
There's Ronda Barber.
>> All right.
>> Could be taken.
>> You don't know.
>> Does one have a mustache?
>> Now there's a lower third there. I've
called games with some parent draft
>> with the 46 parent draft. You could swap
>> 2026 NFL draft. And I am very, very
happy to say this because I might make
some Philadelphia fans a little bit
upset. Never mind. That's right.
>> The Tampa Bay Buccaneers select Josiah
Troder, linebacker.
>> Josiah Troder.
>> So that's a name that Cowboys fans maybe
had circled prior to the Dwinters trade.
But tell me a little bit about Josiah
Troder there, Votch, and what he is
taking to Tampa Bay.
>> Hey man, Josiah is uh physical and
thumpy as hell. Great instincts,
diagnoses the run really well. He's a
true sideline to sideline guy. I don't
say that about everybody cuz I don't
think everybody's a true sideline to
sideline guy. Uh when you watch film and
all these linebackers together, some of
them have, you know, problems dealing
with blockers and things of that nature.
Josiah Troder has no issue dealing with
blockers. I think sometimes he goes down
and he thumps guards on purpose just to
kind of prove that he can do it physical
and he wears these guys down over the
course of a game there. He might get
picked on in in coverage a little bit.
Uh but if you're a team and you got some
other linebackers, you can move him
around and maybe give them some value as
a pass rusher, but I like Josiah Troder
a whole bunch. I had a second round on
him.
>> Yeah, this this the the the brother that
Philadelphia got is plays like mom. This
guy plays like dad
>> when you say that. and uh and and you
know you
>> what a mama athlete is what he say
>> mom is a good athlete but she's you know
she's she's mom this is like old man
this is like the dad I drafted in 98
this guy is a wrap-up tackler uh he he's
got the lateral agility I think he could
beat blockers to space at times you'll
see him take on blockers hands discard
him and other times you kind of see him
dip underneath blockers and get in on
the play I think he's going to like VA
said I think he's going to need some
work on his pass coverage uh when he
gets that opportunity, but is a downhill
player. He plays with some violence.
He's one of those linebackers that reads
it, attacks it. Uh he he plays the run
really, really well and and was against
good competition. Uh that, you know,
when you watch him high tackle games,
Vanderbilt, Texas A&M, Alabama,
Oklahoma, this guy's a really good
football player. Pick is in, by the way,
for Pittsburgh and the hometown Steelers
crowd at 47.
>> They just traded up for this, too.
>> So, they traded up to go get it. Nobody
traded in front of them to go get it.
>> No. Yeah, this is
>> like what happened last?
>> No. No. Well, allegedly. Allegedly. Uh,
this is the Steelers are trading up to
47. They received 249 from the Colts for
53, 135, and 237.
>> So, a good swap there. It's the Colts
off the clock. Pittsburgh with the pick
in. Last couple of selections that you
may have missed on the radio side. Jacob
Rodriguez goes 43rd overall to the
Dolphins. Linebacker from Texas Tech.
Derek Moore, edge rusher from Michigan,
goes to the Jets at 445.
The Ravens take Zion Young, edge rusher
from Missouri. And then the Buccaneers,
one pick later, take his college
teammate Josiah Troder, linebacker from
Missouri, to put the Steelers on the
clock. Now, here is the selection from
the Steel City.
>> Pick in the 2026 NFL draft, the
Pittsburgh Steelers select,
>> Jeremy Bernard.
>> Uhhuh.
Jeremy Bernard.
>> Yeah, man. Um, yak guy.
>> Yak guy all the way.
>> Yak guy. I love I love yak guys a piece.
I thought one thing that I really
noticed from him is on the crossing
routes, anything crossing the field,
crossing deep, slants post, like he has
the ability to put his foot in the
ground and get up field quickly. Uh, he
just outruns guys the more that he gets
going. I thought he was really
underrated as a route runner, too. Brian
Bros. I didn't really see a whole bunch
of drops. Uh but in in traffic it did
kind of get a little get a little bobbly
for him. But for the most part I thought
the hands were like you know you know
really good. But uh crafty route runner
you know probably got a clean I didn't
think he was super fast but I thought he
was explosive. You know what I mean? So
however you want to categorize that but
uh Jeremy Bernard is nice. Had a second
round.
>> Yeah. I had this guy over Cooper believe
it or not from Indiana and but I the the
Vach is absolutely right though. When
you see him catch that ball he is
getting up the field hurry. I think he
runs with some violence. I think he
catches the ball really really well.
Like you're saying, there's there's
times where maybe uh you know, maybe a
little bit of a double catch, but
overall though in traffic, him getting
the football, him getting up field, him
being physical. I I love the way this
guy finished uh finished runs, catches,
routes, all those things I think were
super positive.
>> D Winners is a really good athlete so
far. Go ahead.
>> Yeah, I'm just watching.
>> Zack, tell me a little bit about your
guy Jeremy Bernard.
>> Yeah, Jeremy Bernard, heck of a player.
I'll tell you this was uh better than
Cooper, right? This was a discussion we
had, right?
>> Zachariah Branch, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah, it was. It was. So, Jeremy
Bernard, you know, for me initially, I
had him kind of put down uh the ranks a
little bit. I don't know exactly what
was going on that night, why I would
feel that way.
>> Was that alcohol induced?
>> I'd have been a Miller Light kind of
night for me. And I'm like, you know
what? I got to watch some players. And
then here we go. Here's Jeremy Bernard.
>> Miller Light. The only beer of the
Dallas Cowboys. It's Miller time.
>> Thank you. Uh and then I look back at my
notes and I'm like, you know what? I
actually kind of really liked Jeremy
Bernard. He's actually a really good
player.
>> He was tripping down.
>> He's got good size. I put the last line
of my notes was like, "There's something
about this guy. I don't like him." And
then I read the notes about him and I'm
like, "What are you talking about? You
you actually really liked this guy." So
I I had him below a couple of the other
receivers that are still on the board,
but Pittsburgh was clearly hunting
receivers. They move they lose out on
Mai Lemon and what was embarrassing for
them last night. And then today, they
obviously move up. They go get this guy.
But you talk about a player that just
kind of all around has a very
well-rounded game. The speed element can
go ahead and dig balls out of the dirt.
He's got a wide catch radius. You can
move him around the line of scrimmage.
You see him play out of the back field.
Sherby Bernard's a fun fun watch,
especially under the influence.
>> Uh, real quick, sorry. Do the Falcons
need a corner?
>> Falcons need wide receiver, offensive
line, defensive line, corner,
linebacker.
>> All right. It would be kind of cool if
we got the ter the Terrell brothers in
Atlanta.
>> Oh, that would be cool.
>> That would be
>> They're on They're on the clock right
now. I don't know if that's who they
would take. I literally I'm not tipping
the picks here. Promise. I'm just I'm
wonder I'm sitting here just wondering
like that.
>> Why does nobody believe you?
>> I I dead serious don't know. I'm just
saying I just was looking at the board
of who are the biggest players left and
I saw Terrell and I was like, "Oh my
gosh,
>> you know, I'm going to come across this
table and punch you." What if they go?
>> I would love that. Yeah, I would love
that as a as a
>> just headbutt you on the fly. Come
really
>> guy stop fighting.
>> Uh while we do have a little bit of a
break, they go to commercial break on
the TV side of things. Cowboys fans,
while the team is making big picks, make
the smart pick at home. Call Onime
Experts, the official AC, heating, and
plumbing partner of the Dallas Cowboys.
Fast, reliable, always on time. That's
ontimeex experts. Visit
ontimeexperts.com
and click book now.
>> I don't know about you guys, they
started wiping out my edges here. I mean
the edges in the second round. I mean
Messador went in the first. We had
Lawrence yesterday going the first,
>> but how Mason Thomas Parker Faulk went
first round yesterday and Young. So that
kind of wiped out my second round edge
rushers right now.
>> Yeah, they've been like really cleaning
those edges up
>> from 40 to 45. I really have
>> 40 to 45. Four edge rushers go. Next
year I'm not on the schedule.
>> If even if I come back
>> with He didn't even say nothing, but I
looked at him cuz I felt like
>> I I like it when he goes into silent
mode.
>> What?
>> Cuz he's Texas.
>> It's day three.
>> Yeah. Oh, day three when he just kicks
on us.
>> Robinson from Texas just went.
>> Who got anything to add about?
>> I got to know what happened.
>> I wasn't around. Don't worry about it.
Ask y'all. I'm
>> Neither. Neither was I. I was on.
>> We'll do it over a couple Miller lights.
>> Couple lemonades.
>> Couple lemonades. Couple lemonades.
>> Miller Light, the only beer in the
Dallas. It's Miller time.
>> Uh, yes.
>> Love it.
>> Dwy deals with blocks really well. I
like that about him.
>> So, you're still watching the live
footage,
>> but he's not a He's not a like Bill Dwe.
He's not big. He's a small guy. He
plays.
>> Yeah. But he's dealing with like pullers
and down blockers and these uh tight end
cracks like he's dealing with those in
the run game. Really?
>> I heard this guy's a really good person.
I mean, I know you're going to do the
film and I I'm hopefully get a thumbnail
on this guy, but I appreciate you doing
the leg work on it. show.
>> So, take me through a couple of reps
that you've liked so far, or maybe you
haven't liked.
>> He just chased around Alvin Chimera in
the in the Saints game. He was athletic
enough to kind of keep up with him. Uh,
week one versus the Seahawks. Of course,
Seahawks want to be physical and run at
you. And hey, man, he was running right
up there and thumping and um thumping
Walker. And I know at some point Warner
got hurt and Wyinners took over. So, at
later in the, you know, show, look, we
here for a long time till we get to 92.
I'm gonna dig into how he looked in
Warner's role, but just as of now, good
athlete, looks solid. And
>> smaller guy, you're saying 5'11 or so.
>> Five 5'11, 225. Maybe uh Dan Quinn would
love him as a smaller linebacker type,
but um I'm I'm digging him so far. And
he diagnoses really well so far. Just
just based on what I'm seeing.
>> Do we know if he wore the green dot in
San Francisco? If Fred is healthy, I
would imagine. No way.
>> Let me ask you this. Let me ask you
this. If
>> at a five a 5'11 220 would you say 225
>> 225. Yeah.
>> Real quickly here's the pick for for
Atlanta. I'll come back to you Brian.
>> Thank you.
That's cool.
>> That's nice for him. He looks great.
>> Yeah. I'm representing Atlanta, but
>> it's always both up.
>> Good job getting these.
>> Michael the Burger Ter.
>> And to my no go family at home watching.
I see y'all out there too. Now let's get
down to business.
With the 48th pick in a 2026 NFL draft,
the Atlanta Falcons selects from the
bloodline,
>> Avon Terrell.
>> Wow. Hey. Hey, Bobby. Yes. Bobby.
>> Yes, you did.
>> Come on, man.
>> I swear I didn't know. This is just like
the Atlanta version. This is the Atlanta
version of Deuce Vaughn. Somebody get
Derek Eagleton down here.
>> I swear I was not doing that. Even
though you said Derek, come down here
right now and remove Bobby. Promise I
didn't do it.
>> Yeah.
>> How cool is that for them?
>> I promise. I promise. No, it is good for
them.
>> That's really good. That was cool. That
is cool.
>> Look at Look at the brothers. They're
showing it on the the NFL Network side.
You could tell they're they're fighting
back tears.
>> They look alike.
>> That's really cool. Good for them.
>> They definitely do.
>> They look alike.
>> I Hey, that's I think that's a damn good
pick.
>> It's perfect value for the spot. If they
needed the position like Bobby alluded
to.
>> Yeah, of course he did.
>> Bobby alluded to it.
>> So, Bobby, break down the player. Let's
Let's Let's talk about this. Let's talk
about this instead. Yeah, Bobby, break
down the play.
>> I want I want to know I want to talk
about something really quick. How How
big did you say Dwinners was?
>> 5'11.
>> I'm scared to answer that question.
>> No, no, no. How big did you say it was?
>> He 5'11 225 I think.
>> Uh 229.
>> 229. Okay, cool. But
>> that is the exact same listed height and
weight. Just it's one metric, but it's
the exact same listed height and weight
of Nico Dean.
>> Uh
>> I'm saying size profile wise it fits for
him. And I think they have the exact
same arm length. Nico Dean and Dwinners.
>> Wow.
>> Let me let me let me do this Terrell for
you.
>> Yeah, go for it. Avon Terrell.
>> Yeah, Terrell. Gosh.
>> 31 and 78.
>> Why would I ask you to do something? I
can't get the the computer. Hold on to
said talk a little bit.
>> So yeah, he goes
>> 31 out of 39 games over three years at
Clemson. Total three interceptions, 25
PBUs, eight force fumbles, three force
fumble recoveries, and four sacks.
Dynamic returner in high school as well.
Played both ways.
>> Sold.
>> Yeah, it was very Yeah. 25 35
>> sound.
>> You good, Brian?
>> No, I'm not. I'm
>> Why' you have to go so fast playing big
for his size?
>> Okay, here we go. Here we go. Here we
go. Here we go. Sure. Are you sure?
>> Yeah, I'm sure. Uh left or right corner.
Uh he'll also play in the slot is what
this kid will do. He's not the biggest
guy. We got him at 5'11 180.
>> Uh but he didn't take anything off
anybody. I mean, he's super competitive.
He's tough in the way he goes about his
job. He's a younger brother of AJ. We
talked about this, Bobby.
>> Uh he's a true junior who's played a ton
of snaps for for Clemson. You could tell
he's right, he's athletic right off the
jump. His movement skills, his quickness
is exceptional. He's smooth. He can flip
his hips. He can stay connected no
matter the situation. He breaks on the
ball quickly. He doesn't guess. He does
a really good job of playing with his
eyes. When he sees it, he's on it.
Excellent ball skills, tracks it well,
puts himself in position to defend the
ball. Um, I had this guy in the first
round and then he went out and ran a 46.
And I I think that maybe that's why
people just kind of said, you know what,
we'll pass. But he would be outstanding
in a sk a scheme where he could play
where he could play man coverage, line
up in the slot. I love his toughness. I
love his compete. Atlanta Falcons, I
think they got him a pretty good player.
There were some there were some
questions in 2019 about his brother.
>> I was going to say I like and his
brother turned out to be a pretty damn
good player.
>> I like him better as a prospect coming
out than his brother. Agree.
>> His brother ended up being a good
player. He was wrong about it. But I
like him better as a player coming out
of college than I did AJ Terrell.
>> And why is that? Like why do you like
him?
>> So the AJ was a guy who it felt like
hung his head really easy. I didn't love
the demeanor all the time with him.
Whereas with Avon, I love the demeanor.
you're talking about like just feisty,
competitive,
um, you know, a guy with a lot of really
impressive foot quickness, can play
inside, can play outside. The build's a
little slight, but I mean, I think that
he's pound-for-pound like you want to
talk about like toughness, it was
reminiscent to me of like Jordan Lewis
toughness at Michigan when you watch him
on tape.
>> I was down on his brother because I just
kept seeing
>> you watched that national title game.
>> March was just whooping the hell out of
him. I couldn't unsee it.
>> That was a tough game.
>> I was there. Panthers on the clock.
>> Uh, Panther selection at 49. Can I ask a
question real quick? You're doing this
work after NFC South champions Carolina
Panthers.
>> First time Jake
>> Lee Hunter. Oh, Lee Hunter the Red
Raiders. Yeah.
>> All right. Go back to what you were
talking about there.
>> Okay. I want to ask FYI this question.
>> Takes on double teams. Powerful, strong
as hell. Eastun.
>> No, but
>> medically flagged for some teams.
>> Okay. The the thing with the thing with
the with our with the the young man we
traded for
>> Dwinners. Yeah.
>> Dwinners. Similar to what size you saw
with our guy from Pittsburgh, Lewis.
>> Kyle Lewis.
>> Sure. Sure.
>> And can Okay. Kyle Lewis 51, 220
something.
>> Could we think of Kyle Lewis then as a
linebacker? I mean, is that what we
>> could we think of Dwinners as like a
safety type guy as well?
>> Well, maybe I not a safety guy, but I
was just kind of wondering if maybe
we're maybe I was trying to think maybe
they see that Lewis was a maybe I see
him as a
>> linebacker instead. If they think that
this guy could play linebacker. I was
thinking that I was thinking Lewis was
going to have to play that that safety
position.
>> I think they do have him as linebacker.
>> They have Lewis from Pittsburgh as
linebacker.
>> I think they do, but he is also much he
is still much lighter than uh the
winners by like 10 to 12 pounds, I
think.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. I just I was just saying
>> No, no, no. It's not It's not a bad
comp.
>> Yeah. No, no. I wasn't comparing. I was
just saying
>> No, no. I'm just saying not size profile
comp.
>> Yeah. I was thinking, wow, this guy's
the same size as a guy I think as a
safety, but they're playing this guy at
linebacker. Mhm.
>> But you said it like Nico Dean, right?
>> Nico Dean. Yeah, Nico Dean's a little
So, uh, Kyle Loose is a little taller
than them and he's about 10 lbs lighter
than them, but he So, I mean, his frame
is a little more slight, but he's I I
believe they did view him as a
linebacker.
>> Okay. I'm not certain, but I'm pretty
sure they did.
>> Just want to make sure.
>> Once again, we're we're breaking down a
trade that the Cowboys have made today.
They have uh not picked yet. They will
not pick until the 92nd overall
selection, but they take a fifth round
pick. They send it to San Francisco for
Dwinners, the linebacker who started 17
games for the 49ers last year. Recapping
the last three selections, Steelers at
47, trade up to go get Jeremy Bernard,
the wide receiver from Alabama. 48, the
Falcons take Avon Terrell, brother of AJ
Terrell, who is now a teammate with the
Falcons, the corner out of Clemson. And
then the Panthers at 49 take Lee Hunter,
defensive tackle from Texas Tech. We're
going to talk about Lee Hunter, some of
these other picks that are rattling off
the board. The Jets have their pick in
at pick number 50. You're listening to
the 2026 NFL draft on the Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com.
>> So like Dwyers is in here stacking up
against offensive line and stuff.
>> He had a really good year last year.
He's bending his knees and thumping with
linemen and he's like smaller guy
>> playing hands. Hands look good.
>> Also covering I feel good about this and
I know I'm going to sound like a homer
because I know how Cowboy fans can get
sometimes like I haven't heard of
Dwinners. He's not a da da da v why you
hyping him up. I'm just simply looking
at the film like maybe this may work out
a little better than if you never heard
of D. I never heard like I don't watch a
lot of film, you know. So I just I just
didn't have a good picture for him. But
just me watching him,
>> sir.
>> Slacking.
>> You don't I don't fool with them people
though.
>> He was he was a Fiesta Bowl defensive
MVP. Led the Frogs in tackles for loss.
What was a career year for him?
>> 23.
>> 23. uh high in tackles, tackles for
loss, sacks, and uh PBUS that year. Uh
are the
>> Yeah, my notes from 23 were pretty good
on him.
>> I had a sixth round grade on him where
he ended up going in the sixth that
year.
>> So, he was my he was my 20th linebacker
back in 2023.
>> I wasn't taking notes in 2023.
>> He's playing in and out. I thought the
biggest question for him was being able
to shed and get away when linemen get to
the second level. It sounds like he has
really done a great job.
I mean, he had to fill in obviously for
Fred Warner last year in San Francisco.
I I've been trying to figure out the
green dot stuff. He might have taken
over that responsibility when Fred
Warner went out. Just don't have that
confirmed yet. But I I I think he can
play multiple spots for you at
linebacker. You know, if you can move
him around a little bit, this would not
be I would still draft one. If one falls
to you at 92 that you like, I think he
needed multiple anyway. I mean, Demarian
Overton we all love, but he needs to
prove he can stay healthy. uh Shamar
James, Justin Baron. I mean, you need
some more depth there. So, I love
getting the veteran and Dwinners. I
think it's a great move, especially for
a fifth round pick. You're getting a guy
that's had over aundred tackles and is
super productive. But, I'd still
absolutely look to try and uh fill and
fill that need and get another one.
>> Why couldn't we have just done this with
the Oso Diggiza trade and just like
saved us a little bit of time? We're
already trading picks and trading
players. We might as well just
>> We'll have to see who's throw
with for that pick because here's the
thing. You look at the the the this
draft capital that you still have later
for Dallas. They still have 92. They
still have all three fourth round picks,
112, 114, 136.
>> I was trying to get them to use one of
those for a veteran guy, but they did.
Yeah, they did.
>> And then and then they trade the first
fifth round pick. They still have the
two comps at 177 and 180s.
>> I don't think they have any fives left,
do they? Oh, excuse me. No, they're
done.
>> Dolphins. Yeah, they they've lost all
their fives. Yeah, they out all the
fives. So they they've got a couple of
options there with those fourth round
picks. Here's the Jet selection at 50.
While we're waiting,
>> I grew up in a little town not too far
from here called Homewood.
>> This is Curtis Martin.
>> And so what a player.
>> I just want to take a brief moment to
thank many of you in this crowd tonight,
but the entire city of Pittsburgh for
all of the love and support that you've
given me throughout my career. Thank
you.
Waver.
>> Now with the 50th pick
of the 2026 NFL draft, the New York Jets
select D'Angelo Ponds.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Who said the Jets draft bad?
>> Yeah,
>> it's a pretty good player
>> at this spot.
>> History.
>> History says they draft bad.
>> Bobby wanted to tell us who the pick
was.
>> I didn't know who it was. He's only 5
foot8, 182 pounds. Why is this
>> He's his head coach.
>> Well, let me let me get to it again. You
know, I have these I have to do
something with my way. I move my notes
around, but I'll
>> Well, he's looking for that. How How
heavy is he? He said
>> I I had him at 591 I had him at 59182. I
know the I need to update
>> Aaron Glenn was 5'9183.
>> This guy's a transfer. He was James
Madison. A lot of these kids, the good
players came from James Madison.
>> He's competitive. He's athletic. He's
one of those guys who plays bigger than
his listed size.
>> That was
Welcome back in to our continuing
coverage of day two of the 2026 NFL
draft. Steps away from AT&T Stadium, the
National Medal of Honor Museum showcases
the stories of the ordinary Americans
who took extraordinary action in the
service of others. Real people, real
courage, real close. Plan your visit at
museum.org.
Back with Fach Lombardi of Crown Global
Media. We've got Zack Walchuk, Bobby
Belt, and Brian Bratus of 1053, The Fan.
I'm Kyleman's of Dallas Cowboys.com.
Last couple of picks off the board. Lee
Hunter goes 49th overall to the Panthers
out of Texas Tech. D'Angelo Ponds, the
corner from Indiana, goes to the New
York Jets at pick number 50. Brian, you
were just breaking him down. Yeah, this
guy, he's a 5'9, he's 182. He plays a
lot bigger than his listed weight and
height. I mean, he was in an allout
battle uh in this Ohio State game. You
can watch him play and he's not backing
down from Smith at all. He's got great
footwork. He's got a feel for space.
He's one of those corners who makes
plays on the ball. He's a great example
of did a great example of this against
Oregon with his pick six to open the
game.
>> He plays like a guy who studies in order
to provide himself an advantage. You can
see him in pregame preparation. And you
can see this guy in zone. You can see
him at man. He's just as effective. He
lines up tight, then he'll turn and bail
to put himself in position. His
instincts and uh are tied to strong eye
discipline. He plays really well with
them. He's physical in man coverage. He
trusts his mirroring skills and he's
good at recognizing route combinations
and still being able to be in position.
So, he just doesn't panic when the
ball's in the air. He does a really nice
job of attacking the catch point. He's a
willing tackler. I felt like he only
missed two tackles. I think I saw that
he missed two tackles in the season. He
just got better each game in the
playoffs. So, uh, really nice pick there
for the for the Jets. Maybe they'll get
an interception this year with this guy
playing. This guy is a ball
draft. The Minnesota Vikings select Jake
Gold.
>> Oh, Cincinnati.
>> I was I really I really thought that was
going to be McNeel Warren.
>> The Vikings have not addressed that spot
like everybody thought they would. Mhm.
>> I do want to give Zach a little credit
here. You said that that was a team you
earmarked for Jacob Rodriguez. If if
>> Yeah. Minnesota was a team that I
thought was interested in him. Uh
>> and go with a different linebacker.
>> Carolina's one.
>> Yeah. JRod's off the board.
>> Yeah.
>> Just to answer everybody's question, I
fast forwarded to the Texans game. That
was the game after Warner got hurt. It
seems like uh number 48 uh Bthoon. It
seems like he's doing more of the
talking than Wyinners. Okay. So, I don't
think winners is a green dot
>> in terms of green dots.
>> In terms of green dot guy, but he but
he's still whooping feet though.
>> Tell me a little bit about Jake Gold
here,
>> man. Uh Jake Jay Gold was a guy that I
thought diagnosed really well. Some
really good size on him. Uh Cincinnati
moved him all around. He was in four
spots. I don't think they should have
did that all too much.
>> How about that film where he was playing
detached?
>> They had him They had him playing a
bunch of nickel. I didn't think that was
best for him. I thought his his best
stuff was playing the mic. Yeah.
>> Diagnosing verse the run. playing
downhill and then every now and then
getting on the line of scrimmage, pass
rushing, getting up field. I I think he
was a former like edge or something like
that. But
>> he was he was at at what central
Arkansas with the school.
>> Yeah. Sure. So him him pass rushing
every now and then playing Mike. I think
that's where his value really um showed
up and I thought that he was uh I
thought he was going to be next up. He
was very high on my board and this hurts
me a little bit but we got Dwinners in
the fifth round so I'm straight.
>> All right, Brian, I know you know the
answer to that question. What is the UCA
central Arkansas claim to fame?
>> Matt.
>> Oh, I don't know.
>> Oh, the the the field.
>> No. Is it uh is it
>> is gray and purple?
>> Oh, gray and purple every five years.
That's right. That's right. That's
right. That's right. I've seen this
field before. No, no, no. You're right.
So, the Eastern Michigan is the one
that's got the gray field. It's like
you're watching a game in black and
white.
>> Yeah. Gross.
>> I just wanna um I want to circle back on
something because once I once I got it
in my head, I had to go look. I kind of
made it as a joke. D'Angelo Ponds is
Aaron Glenn in terms of size.
>> They are the same height. They are the
same weight. Glenn had a 40inch
vertical. Pons was 43. Glenn ran 439.
Ponds ran 437. And they have the same
arm length.
>> They're sitting there in the war room
and they're looking at a guy and they're
saying, "Hey Aaron, we need to go get an
interception. We don't have one like
that.
>> Are you are you worried about the size
at all? A little bit." And Glenn's like,
"You know what? I'm not worried about
>> that's what I'm saying. If you're going
to talk, if you're going to talk about
like a team that could take a smaller
guy, it would be a team where the head
coach is guy like I made.
>> How about how about a team that plays
the ball?
>> How did you uh what did you do? You
remember what you thought of Aaron
Glenn?
>> No, that's what I'm saying. I mean, they
needed that. That was a big wieners.
>> That's what I'm saying. They they they
got rid of S Gardner and all of a sudden
they they're not playing the ball.
>> Fourth nationally in passes defense per
game. Also special teams. I mean, he was
he was the only one of 12 active players
that had multiple punt blocks returned
for touchdowns. I mean, he's a guy that
just gets around the football. I mean,
everything you said about him earlier,
attitude, toughness, just an allhart
player that's a really good pick. Gold
Day is interesting, though, with with
Minnesota. I mean, this dude's come he
comes from a family full of athletes. I
wonder where they're going to put him. I
think he's more of an outside linebacker
than he is a mic linebacker personally.
>> That's where I I list him as an outside
line.
>> Yeah, I did too. I did too. But he plays
with his eyes really well. He can read.
He can fight off blocks. Super athletic.
Takes good angles. Uh, I mean the
multiple thing, he's a guy that
certainly is a chess piece that you can
do a lot with. We did not give Lee
Hunter his due going back a couple of
picks there. Defensive tackle from
stack.
>> Defensive tackle.
>> You want to go ahead and break him down?
>> May.
>> He was one of the best players at the
Senior Bowl, I thought.
>> Was he how he was awesome?
>> Where was he in your defensive tackle
stack?
>> Mine give me over to
>> Right after K McDonald.
>> Yeah, I've lost all I've lost all three
of my I I had three second round. Yeah,
they're all gone now.
>> Defensive tackles. McDonald Miller and
Hunter. All gone. Same way.
>> They called him the fridge. Lee Hunter.
I mean, this guy's just super
disruptive.
>> How about have his known nickname?
>> Former Malachi Lawrence teammate there
at UCF. But I I loved his hands. He can
play head up over the center as a nose.
Incredibly difficult to move.
>> He is a zero technique.
>> 100%. Tremendous power, but he's
slippery for his size. Like for how big
he is, he can get up field. Bobby, you
need to grow the hell up.
>> I'm listening to your evaluation. relax.
>> You can watch him in that game against
or you can watch him against uh Oregon
in the in the Orange Bowl game. That
thing I mean he that poor Oregon center.
>> Oh my gosh. It was it was game over.
Yeah. He penetrates really well. The
ability agility with this kid is
fantastic.
>> That was against uh the the Oregon tape
was against your guy Pregnon, right?
>> Yeah.
>> And he was still playing was playing
guard.
>> Oh, you're right.
>> And he was over center, right? So if
they if they might have should have
moved Pregnon over to center, he'd have
handled him.
>> He probably would have been just fine
there. Uh I was looking to see if that
center was in the draft and he doesn't
look like he is.
>> Great ability, agility.
>> He's in the others as Votch likes to
say.
>> Ah, there you go.
>> Right. Voty.
>> Who's that?
>> Others if players others.
>> Here's the Packers at 52. Pass the fifth
round. you.
>> It is my esteemed pleasure to make this
second round pick on behalf of Ed
Policy, Brian Gunnik, Matt Laflur, and
the millions of Packer fans across the
world.
With the 52nd pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Green Bay Packers select
Brandon Cece.
>> Defensive player
>> guy the Cowboys like Yeah.
>> Raw.
>> Yeah. Great athlete. Uh long can cover
really well man cover guy press man. Uh
carry routes inside very well. Wasn't
very technical but I thought he did a
great job for not knowing how to play
corner for real for real. Um, you know,
if you do a bunch of double move stuff
down the field, you can catch him
looking around, spinning spinning back
was all up on the sideline and stuff
like that. But, uh, as as long as it's
in front of him, he was uh pretty decent
there, but I didn't think of him as a
zone guy. I thought he was like a pretty
good mate.
>> You know who he reminded me of a little
bit. Kyler Gordon,
>> I could see that.
>> Yeah. Is that Washington? Yeah.
>> The the thing about Cece, too, is
remember he started at San Diego State,
got up to
>> North Carolina State, or excuse me,
yeah, NC State. uh put on 17 lbs, got up
to 2011 at one point, but he's more
comfortable around that 190 to 195 mark.
Then he goes to the combine, puts up 41
in verticals, had it a formal with the
Cowboys at the combine, and they were
really impressed with his interview, the
film breakdown, his knowledge of the
game, and kind of the conversation that
they had there. He he uh also calls
Stefon Gilmore a mentor. Said he's
mentored by by Gilly and and one of the
guys that the Cowboys have had in the
past. So, uh, good value, I think, for
the pick for the Packers there at 52.
Yeah. Here in the second round,
>> this guy wasn't talked about a whole
lot, the process as we were going
through it. I mean, it was he was kind
of a forgotten guy and he's only 20
years old when he's, you know, selected
in this draft. He's got an element of
speed to his game and you can see he he
knows how to move. He knows how to run.
There's a burst, there's catchup speed.
He's a hard guy to run away from. LSU,
Vanderbilt, Kentucky, Alabama all saw
that. Um, the one thing the South
Carolina coaches will tell you though,
they'd like to see him more make more
plays as a tackler.
>> That was something that really, you
know, that maybe they felt like that he
turned down some opportunities and maybe
the NFL guys watched that tape and said,
"That's something we we don't want a guy
that can't tackle." Here is Pat McAfee
with the Colts selection of 53. He's
about to be alone.
>> We've already missed half of it.
>> Congratulations.
>> Ken's ready for this.
>> He about to take his time with this.
NOW, THE INDIANAPOLIS COLTS FIRST ROUND
DRAFT PICK WAS SAUCE GARDNER, AND HE'S
BETTER THAN ALL OF YOUR FIRST ROUND
PICKS for sure.
>> He didn't win a lot of games. The
>> Indianapolis Colts HAVE NOT WON THE AFC
SOUTH IN 12 years. THAT CHANGES THIS
YEAR. JIM MERCLES FROM THE FOOTBALL
HEAVENS CURED DANIEL JONES'S TORN
ACHILLES. MICHAEL PITMAN GOT SENT TO THE
STEELERS AND IN RETURN WE GOT man with
the
>> over the last uh all the
>> 26 NFL draft
>> the AFC South Kings Indianapolis Colts
select
>> CJ Allen linebacker from Georgia.
>> And that concludes your third or your
second round linebackers Georgia. all
off the board here. Look at the How
about this? Rodriguez, Troder, Gold A,
and Allen all go from pick 43 through
53.
>> And that is why the Dallas Cowboys
traded for Dwinners.
>> That's exactly
>> Anthony Hill Junior still hanging
around.
>> He is, which is odd.
>> He is. That was Yeah, I had him over the
other two. I mean, he was the As you
stacked him, as I stacked him, Hill,
Allen, and then Rodriguez.
>> Th with Philly here. Look for a mellow
height. We had some reports earlier that
this might be where Texas Tech Edge
could go. They were interested in him.
But CJ Allen, I mean, we heard early on
a lot of connections with Dallas and I
mean, you got a coach on the staff here.
The testing, I mean, a lot of people
made a big deal about, oh my gosh, that
proday workout. If you watch him play, I
don't think that was really a surprise.
He's a downhill thumper. I mean, he was
so good in the Auburn and the Florida
game. Super smart, super instinctive
type of player. It's just when he has to
cover the coverage is where he's really
lacking. But CJ Allen is a good player
and he fills a big need in which they
needed there in Indianapolis.
>> Cool moment for him to at that point.
You talk about an instinctual player.
Impressive first step reaction time. I
think he recognizes the blocking schemes
and gaps really quickly. I I would say
he's one of the more secure s tacklers
that I watched in the SEC this year,
too. Really rarely misses those tackles.
You talk about the way he called
defenses for Georgia. You have the the
ability to read and react and that sets
him apart over some of the physical
gifts that he might have. I I think when
it comes to change of direction coverage
that could possibly be a downturn at
times, Brian, but he's still a guy that
will come in and be NFL ready. But
>> yeah, he he will be NFL ready. And and
man, it's weird about these Georgia
kids. They kind of play like some days
they play like two gap and other days
they they you know they like their
scheme's kind of weird and you kind of
feel like man maybe they're not this pro
ready but this kid is one of those pro
ready players. Maybe some questions
about the knee you need to, you know,
figure out there. Eagles here at 54.
>> With the 54th pick of the 2026 NFL
draft, the 2000, excuse me, the twotime
champions and reigning NFC East
champions, Philadelphia Eagles select
Eli Sters, tight end from Vanderbelt
University.
>> They've been trying to get rid of poor
Dallas Goddard for a while now. Yeah,
>> Eli Sters, Denton Guyerone, former
quarterback. I mean, this dude is a
receiving tight end, is an outstanding
player. He transferred with Pavio from
New Mexico State.
>> Did you see there were certain teams
that were looking at him as a possible
uh uh a possible wide receiver,
>> I believe it. I mean, he's got the size,
the frame, he moves really well. He
plays like a wide receiver as a tight
end. I mean, you could line him up all
over the formation, in line, in the
slot. I think play strength is something
he needs to add as a blocker, but he
held his own against some quality
competition uh at the point of attack.
He can fire off the ball, really good
hands. I mean, for only playing the
position for three years as a route
runner, he creates separation. He's got
a good feel for working open in zones.
He struggled a little bit against
Alabama when it comes to contested
catches. Uh when I watched that game, I
thought he would fit really well with
like a Ben Johnson type of scheme uh
with, you know, in Chicago. But this
this could be this could be an
interesting fit in Philadelphia. Uh
that's that's going to be a pain in the
butt to have to play every single year
there. But they've been looking for
another w for another tight end and this
is a dude who can really stretch the
seam, can make plays at every single
level of the defense. Eli Sters is a
heck of a player.
>> He's athletic enough to play receiver.
If team like like if teams wanted to do
that, he could. Um like like is he going
to be a burner or whatever? No, but I
mean he could be a big ex receiver. Um,
and yeah, he's still relatively raw and
new at the position, and yet he has
turned into a really solid route runner
with really strong hands. I mean, I I
like Sters a lot. I I think it seemed
like pretty unanimous from everybody I
talked to that this was number two tight
end behind Sadiq.
>> Yeah, I had him as the number two guy. I
I former high school quarterback, right?
>> Yeah. Guy and&M and then he moved.
>> Yeah. And you know, he this guy extends
for, you know, extends for the ball. You
could you can watch him in the Texas
game. I mean, he did a really nice job
of taking the ball and then getting up
the field quickly and then getting the
ball in the end zone. He doesn't have
the frame of a traditional tight end.
And I say that as 6'4, but the 235 I
think is something that they're going to
have to work on with him. But he's kind
of a get in away or a shield blocker.
That'll hit.
>> Yeah. He just doesn't have the power to
blow anybody off the ball. But the way
he's able to navigate routes and make
big- time receptions is impressive to
his game. All right, so that's the pick
at pick number 54 for the Philadelphia
Eagles. Last five selections, D'Angelo
Ponds goes 50 to the Jets. 51 is Jay
Gold, the linebacker from Cincinnati to
the Vikings. The Packers at 52 take
Brandon Cece, corner from South
Carolina. 53 CJ Allen, linebacker from
Georgia, goes to the Colts. And then the
Eagles at pick 54 take Eli Sters, the
tight end from Vanderbilt. We got to
take a break. When we come back, it'll
be more of the second round. Day two
rolls on. You're listening to the 2026
NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com.
>> Is this where we're going to start to
see the tight end
>> run a little bit here? Claire, maybe
Delp, Jolly. Those are the guys I'm I'm
looking at.
>> Chargers just traded this pick, by the
way.
>> Did they really? This is to the Patriots
for 63, 131, and 202.
>> Interesting.
>> Patriots. The Patriots. My man Elliot
Wolf not wanting to draft.
>> The good news is that Beam, I cannot tip
this pick because she deleted her
account and won't tell us what the pick
is.
>> Oh no.
>> At least we're not on the radio. I guess
>> I waited.
>> And we got we got we got part of it
taken care of.
>> Look, there some there are silver
linings everywhere. Beam.
>> Yeah. the uh Patriots. Geez.
>> Trading up to this slot. If you're
talking about the the tight ends, we
haven't talked a lot. They love tight
ends in New England.
>> Offensive line, defensive line, tight
ends, wide receiver.
>> Yeah. Would an offensive player be in
play at 92? We haven't really had that
conversation quite yet.
>> I think I mean I think they're coming
out of here with a receiver. Yeah.
>> At some point. Not not today
necessarily, but out of this one of
these next two days, they're going to
get a receiver somewhere. If if a re if
they were willing to take a receiver at
12 if the board fell that way, I could
see the board falling a certain way that
they're sitting there at 92 and they go,
"You know what? We just drafted a
linebacker. We've addressed a number of
other positions. Go ahead and get the
top rated player here."
>> Would you possibly see another
linebacker? Could you draft another one
and be okay with
>> I I mean, depending on who's there,
we're starting to run out of linebackers
here to that makes sense, I think.
>> Um, let's see here. Who do we
>> Anthony Hill is the best one on my board
for for sure. I would still be surprised
if Hill fell another 30 picks is all.
>> Yeah.
>> But I mean I didn't think he'd be here
by now. So
>> might be in that that Harold Perkins. H
he's probably a little bit later.
>> I think that Elliot Elliot from uh
Arizona State
>> Mhm.
>> would be in the I think
>> RER at Michigan.
>> Rder. Yeah. See,
>> that's the guys we were kind of talking
about going in. I know in the couple.
>> Yeah. We were we were talking about you
couldn't think about the the top guys.
You just kind of had to think about the
guys. Maybe even a round down. Maybe
you're looking at fourth, fifth round
guys for some of those linebacker spots.
Pick is in, by the way, for the Patriots
at 55,
followed by the Jags, the Bears, the
49ers, and the Texans. Then the Bears
pick again at 60. Uh they have two picks
over the next five selections
themselves.
Brian, who are the top players overall
on your board as we get ready to go?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we're talking about the guys
like Hill from Texas is is up there. I'm
trying to go down real quick.
>> Maybe McCoy still.
>> Yeah, McCoyy's still there, but we I if
we get to McCoy, I'll tell you exactly
what everybody's thinking, but Anthony
Hill at uh the 29th best player on my
board is still available.
>> I got Melo Height, Wheatly, Jaylen
Farmer, McNeel, Warren, Serat, and
Preon.
>> Daniel Jeremiah apparently just said
Aaron Glenn just drafted himself. Well,
maybe he was listening to you.
>> Yeah, that's that's what I say. You be
>> He's smart.
>> Maybe you should be doing the NFL
Network.
>> They fired me.
>> Defend our country's freedom.
>> Welcome back to our coverage of the 2026
NFL draft. Here's the Patriots selection
with the 55th overall
>> draft. The New England Patriots select
Gabe Ais, linebacker, Illinois. Another
edge rusher off the board. He hasn't
made a pick in a while. Why did he make
that one for the Patriots? I wonder that
was that just seemed kind of in his box.
>> I thought he was done for the night.
Okay.
>> Right now, you know, they got a lot
going on.
>> They need somebody to to step up and and
be the face of the program. Maybe the
Patriots make the selection. Gabe Jacus
out of Illinois is the pick. Wrapping up
the last five selections. Jay Gold,
linebacker from Cincinnati, goes 51 to
the Vikings. Brandon Cece, corner from
South Carolina to the Packers at 52. CJ
Allen, the Georgia linebacker at 53 to
the Colts, Eli Sters, tight end from
Vandy, goes to the Eagles at 54. And
then 55, the Patriots tape. As we just
said, Gabe Jacus out of Illinois.
>> That's his dude. That is Vot's guy.
>> You really liked him from the
>> I don't think I'd been vouching for Yak
cuz I'm
>> No, no, not vouching for him here. You
wanted to throw him in the end of the
first round as your wild pick though
because you said you said you said I do
like him so I'll throw him here.
>> I'll talk about him. Uh yeah. Uh long
arm, big body. When you look at him just
based on his size cuz he's humongous,
you would assume that he's a hand in the
dirt guy, but then he stands up and he
starts to move him around and they start
to gap exchanging them, stunned him a
little bit. You can see the athleticism.
Uh and that really gets to uh look good
there. He's good versus the run. uh can
really identify blocks and counter
blocks, but I thought as a pass rush,
he's still kind of raw and he runs down
the middle of people, but he still gets
sacks run down the middle of people. So,
as soon as he refineses his uh his
hands, there's a lot of upside to him
there.
>> Yeah, this guy has got a little bit of a
burst and he can give some blockers some
problems with his speed, speed to power
rush. He's just he's just not going to
wow you with moves and stuff like that.
I think that things he had 12 sacks for
the season which led the Big 10. Mhm.
>> He had six and a half sacks in his last
four games. Ruters, Maryland, Wisconsin,
and Northwestern. I looked at the Ohio
State Washington game. He didn't have
any sacks.
>> Ohio State wasn't letting him beat him.
I mean, they were putting like two or
three players on.
>> I mean, he but like I said, I think that
I think Voucher's right there. I mean,
the flexibility for him, guy, he's got
some power to him and some strength.
Here's the Jags at 56. with the 56th
pick in the 2026 NFL draft.
>> The Jacksonville Jaguars select Nate
Boracher, tight end, Texas A&M.
>> There's the second tight end in the
second round.
>> Borcure go. I'm shocked he went above.
>> That's pretty high. Couple of those
other guys.
>> That's definitely a little high, man.
But a physical player, uh, as a blocker
and as a runner, uh, when you see him
line up, he is trying to move edges off
the ball. I think he's quite qualified
to move edges and linebackers off the
ball for sure. When he's out and uh you
know dealing with corners and safeties,
he's really trying to finish and whoop
those dudes. He didn't he didn't make a
a bunch of catches. I think every year
he had like right around 15 to 20 or so
catches, but when he made those catches,
it was some tight window catches and he
always tried to run people over and I
was a fan of him. But I had him like in
day three somewhere. It's a little high
for
>> I was going to say I talked to a scout
uh last month about him, not a Dallas
scout, it was an AFC scout. I talked to
somebody about him. They said they put
him in the fifth round.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's where I had He's
kind of clunky as a route runner a
little bit. You know, he he he had that
nice game-winning touchdown against
Notre Dame. Uh he can make some
contested catches. He has a field of
where to sit down and zone, work the
middle of the field, but I kind of look
at him as a tight end, too. I don't know
that he's really going to be a starting
tight end for you. Certainly a good
blocker. I mean, you're right, Vaude. He
had 19 catches for 198 three touchdowns.
That was his entire season production.
transferred from Nebraska. Um, but man,
it's it's a little rich for me, but
hopefully it turns out to be a good
player.
>> I'll tell you, I think this could have
been a day three consideration here in
Dallas.
>> Yeah.
>> But but not here. This is very very
high.
>> Yeah. 56 is is a little early. Bears,
49ers, Texans, Bears coming up here over
the next couple of picks. Gentlemen, we
have a trade
>> and it's a trade within the division
>> that is not great if you are a part of
the Dallas Cowboys. Here is the recent
uh trade from Adam Shfter online. He
says Vikings are sending former Pro Bowl
linebacker Jonathan Grinard.
>> Yeah.
>> To uh or Grinard, excuse me, to the
Philadelphia Eagles in exchange for a
third round pick.
>> Two3
>> tonight and a third round pick next
year.
>> Yeah. I'm I'm not mad at this now that I
saw the details.
>> $100 million contract
>> two/3s and he's getting $100 million
extension. That's way too much for
Gernard.
>> Wow. It's a lot.
>> Personally, I would I would not have
done Oh, yeah.
>> I would I would have been hesitant to do
a third.
>> They They're sending one this year, one
next year, and then they're giving him
50 million guaranteed.
>> Four years, $100 million. That includes
50 fully guaranteed. Drew Rosenhouse is
the uh is the the agent. And the trade,
by the way, saves the Vikings 34 million
in cap space immediately. your defensive
line coach was just with him for the
last couple years and was not telling
you to jump all over that. So
>> that says a lot.
>> I think that is steep. Personally,
>> I kind of thought on the field was
>> personally I mean like in a vacuum I
would have liked him here.
>> He's a good player.
>> Yeah, I would like him.
>> I thought the film was good.
>> Yeah. No, I was about to say in a vacuum
I I I would like him here. Yeah.
>> Um I think last year he had a little he
was not playing to the level that he had
in Houston or the first year that he was
in Minnesota. But I mean he was still a
good player. I don't know that like for
instance
I think the Giants would a lot of people
were I think the Giants would give up
like maybe one of their pass rushers for
>> Tibido
>> I don't know I wouldn't anybody
>> I'm sorry we can't do that apolog I
would think that somebody else would
potentially give up theirs for less than
that
>> forget what platform I'm on sometimes
>> it's okay
>> we just talking there's millions of
people in the world whose last name is
that
>> yeah it could be a guy from Louisiana
you LSU It's a city. Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's just a place.
>> Good restaurants, by the way.
>> Not even a person. Good.
>> Who's Who's your favorite LSU player
this year, Brian
>> in the draft?
>> Delane.
>> See, but I mean like like outside of
like the the top one, like who would be
your like that's a guy I'd love on day
two or three?
>> You like Perkins? You like Perkins?
>> Perkins. Yeah. Would be Perkins would
>> I would still I would still love I don't
care if he's there in the third round. I
would still take
>> NM.
>> Oh, I I mean Yeah.
>> I I would still I would still take him
no matter what team I was. I just like,
"Yeah, I'll stash him one."
>> I think I think if he was healthy, I
think if he's honestly healthy, like if
you go back and watch the 2024 tape of
him playing,
>> he did some really good things for LSU.
>> He the
>> But he was not healthy.
>> There are times where he when he throws
the ball on that tape, it's
>> Yeah,
>> it'll it'll drop your jaw.
>> Yeah. Where are you hoping he goes?
>> Me or Ryan?
>> You go ahead.
>> Uh I mean, it'd be cool if he went to
New Orleans, actually.
>> Yeah. Play with his dad.
>> Yeah,
>> that would be cool. I'm not tipping
picks here. I don't know if that will
happen.
>> We're Yeah, we're at the same
>> I'm just making family connection.
>> Uh we've got eight picks remaining in
the second round and then we flip things
to the third.
>> It's been a long little Man,
>> this feels like it's gone longer than
the first round.
>> It I certainly agree. And maybe part of
that is because we've been trying to
break down the trade. Dallas trading for
for D. Winters, linebacker that was out
of TCU initially, but spent the first
couple years of his career uh after
being a sixth round pick to the uh San
Francisco 49ers.
>> Lots of edge rushers here, Brian. Lots
of linebackers. Yeah. Here in the second
round, we've seen more edge rushers,
more linebackers than we saw in the
first round. Not a ton of linemen going.
Really, the the trenches have been
ignored a little bit here in the second.
>> Well, the the offensive linemen all went
yesterday. Sure. For some unknown
reason,
>> the tackles did.
>> The tackles all win.
>> There's only one offensive lineman
that's gone today, and that was Chase
Basantis.
>> Basantis. You know, there's we're going
to get to a point in time probably in
this third where you'll see guys like
with Dunker from Iowa, Farmer, a guy
Slaughter, uh, Florida, Hec, uh, Kansas
State,
>> uh, Lou from Auburn. You know, I I I
think you'll start to see that. Maybe
you'll start to see some of these backs,
too. I know Price went yesterday, but
you know, what about Johnson and Coleman
and guys like that,
>> Washington Jr.
>> We've and we've got a bunch of these
edges now. We finished off all the
second round edges on Brian Brous's uh
book or stack,
>> you know. Now we got Height, Llewellyn,
uh Dennis C, uh Dennis, excuse me,
Dennis Smith from Penn State, Crawford
from Auburn, I think Joseph's from
Tennessee.
>> We've seen a couple here
>> with with more and Yakis is going. those
two guys
>> real fast. I must say Dwinners played
better when Warner was on the field with
him. Take that as you may.
>> Okay, here's the Bears at 57.
>> Jerry Font.
>> Where's those Bear fans at?
>> I'm guessing they're picking
you just Jay Hildenberg or something
like that.
>> Mark Carrier.
>> I'm liking those cheese grater hats, my
man. Grate that cheese right up. I love
it.
>> With the 57th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Chicago Bears select Logan
Jones, center Iowa.
>> Ah,
here we go. There's a center.
>> Took a little bit of time to get
offensive lineman, but
>> that's a guy who might come in and be
your your day one starter there for the
Bears.
>> Your Remington award winner, best center
in the country. Can sense it's all
American, first team, all Big 10. He's a
squatty guy and he will give up some
size. I mean, this this center class is
not your your biggest center class, but
if you're going to play at Iowa, you
better run block. And this dude does it
at a very very high level. He actually
kind of reminds me a little bit of Tyler
Bottish uh coming out. So, I mean, Logan
Jones, good hand fighter. I think that
saves him from being able to win against
bigger, stronger players. He can climb
to the second level. Not always the best
puller. You can see him get caught in
traffic. Doesn't always reach the mark.
I do think he can lunge a little bit
sometimes, but he's super competitive.
four-year starter, played a lot of
football, could add some power, but uh
he he can sustain his blocks pretty
well. I like some other centers better,
but
>> I named three of them.
>> Yeah.
>> Who are the three?
>> Well, the guys I just did, the the
Slaughter and and and our guy from
Kansas State.
>> Also, Lou from all
>> Yeah, Lou. Yeah,
>> I This guy This No, this guy's a tough
guy.
>> I thought he has some decent movement,
too.
>> Yeah, this this guy is Let me Let me Let
me get to get to my notes on this guy.
But yeah, this is this is a one of the
Gosh darn it, Brian. If you weren't so
old sometimes you do these things,
right? Um but yeah, this is one of those
guys when you watch him play,
>> he gets away from the line well. I mean,
he's got good base. He's got a good set.
His athletic ability to pull when
uncovered. He gets in space. His base
could get a little narrow on some dry
blocking stuff he does, but you can see
him get off the ball quick and onto the
second level, climb blocks, engage. Uh
there's some power to his game. Um, you
know, he's a little bit of an older guy
here, which for offensive linemen ain't
always bad. You know, he's one of those
guys that, but uh, this this group was
this was the offensive line that was a
Joe Moore winning offensive line. So,
>> and the Browns just took Emanuel McNeel
Warren Toledo safety number 58. I was
just going to say if we got around to
it, best players available. He was
probably one of the top ones on my board
outside of Jeram McCoy and some of the
Romela height and the injury concerns.
>> I just been texting people asking who
were the best players left like who some
people were surprised are still on the
board. McNail Warren was the most common
answer. Other guys were
hold on I wrote them down. Uh Zachariah
Branch, Ted Hurst, Pregnon
uh look like they're
>> something must be wrong with
>> I'm surprised. I mean maybe I was just
way wrong about him. And Hill Hill,
Hurst, Branch, pregnant.
>> No. Wheatley.
>> Not at least on the couple responses I
got.
>> Yeah,
>> I like Wheatley a lot. Be a sicko and
just take Wheelie and put him with down.
>> Oh, that be kidding me. Play him over
the top. You got You got an umbrella and
a heat seeeking missile.
>> Who cares?
>> Let's go. Uh, Emanuel McNeil Warren.
Tell me a little bit about him, Brian.
>> Uh, if somebody else grabb him real
quick. I'm
>> probably going to be doing some house
cleaning here. That's probably probably
going to be a uh be a box safety for
you. Uh ran around pretty decent. He's
another guy that's more explosive than
he was fast, but that's just me me
personally looking at him. I didn't
really like to see him on the roof a
bunch. They they put him up there.
Shouts out to him when he's when he's
doing robber stuff. I thought he was
cool. I think as long as he gets to like
play free and roam, but I thought he was
best around the line of scrimmage.
Active in the run game, physical. Uh
probably not a man cover guy, but uh
throw him out there in the zone and see
what he does. And uh good length. They
uh they liked him here in Dallas.
>> He was a 30 visit. He's
>> the first Toledo Rocket to be named a
Thorp Award semi-finalist since.
>> Oh, Barry Church was a Barry Church.
Yeah, how about that? I I I've got him
now here for you if you would. I mean,
he plays the for a tall guy, he plays
with a little burst
>> and you can see him. He matches up on
tight ends. He can athletically stay
>> every They're getting you, Brian.
>> They're trying to move a little bit.
That's good.
>> For the best team in Texas.
>> I want to go to hell, bro.
I don't know about that one.
>> Oh boy.
>> You get to a conference championship.
>> Last time the commissioner
>> even Rich Eisen's like, "Oh boy, bad
idea." I think the winners is kind of
getting targeted and covered.
>> Later in the season, maybe they saw
something.
>> Last and not least, um Bushwood elite
and the winning edge
>> could have finished. This is
>> special for me because I know this kid
personally, which is ironic.
>> Gaffne,
>> the 59 pick for the Houston Texans.
They select Marlon Klein, tight end,
University of Michigan.
>> Yeah. Here we go.
>> There are a couple tight
>> in a weird order of tight end.
>> Yes, it is all over the place a little
bit here. Uh we're going to put up some
some highlights here of of Marlon Klein.
But Bronnis, I want you to finish, man.
You'll make me warn and then we got to
take a break.
>> Yeah, real quick though. I will do that.
This guy's no fear when you want him to
come forward and attempt to fill. He's
got to be careful sometimes with his
angles which can cause him to overrun
some plays. I love the way how loose,
how flexible he's able to play for being
as tall as he is. Exceptional length and
size for the position. Has a history of
being a really big hitter and tackler,
but there was some missed tackles uh
this year, but for someone this size,
he's he's got some fluidity to his game.
>> They just showed five plays of Marlon
Klein catching passes.
>> He probably only got eight more. So So
they really had to dig to find them. I
thought he was more of a blocker,
though. I thought that's really where he
kind of shined a little bit. He was he
was comfortable blocking edges and I
thought he was a really good move like
move blocker like a puller or like you
know pulling out open space and things
like that uh zones and stuff. I I didn't
think he ran a bunch of routes but per
the highlights he did run the uh the uh
scene uh two times out of his 20some
catches and he did seem to have a little
bit of yak on five of his 20some
catches. I had him down in the extras. I
thought he was going to go like in the
sixth or the seventh round. I thought
there was much better
>> sixth round. Yeah, I thought they were
much better pass catching uh tight ends
and much better blocking tight ends. I
thought they were more better complete
tight ends. So, uh Shashad who just
drafted them?
>> The Texans take him over.
>> Texans been doing weird stuff all day
though.
>> All weekend.
>> I got to be honest. It feel it feels
like every year tight end is the one
position nobody ever stacks like the
league does. Like like they all first or
second. Yeah. I feel like tight end
after the first round is the biggest ice
cream flavor position that exists in the
NFL where they'll just grab some. It's
like, "Okay, I thought that guy was
going in the sixth." And then you'll
like see some that you're like, "Well,
why is that guy fallen to the fifth
round?"
>> Yeah. I mean, Klein is a Big 10 tight
end. They've had success uh drafting Big
10 tight ends in the NFL as of late. So,
maybe that's something to it.
>> Take Claire, Jolly, Trig, Dope. You can
go ahead and do your thing.
>> All of those I would take both of them.
>> Yep.
>> Royer Raran injuries.
>> The last four picks. Nick uh Nate
Boracher, the tight end out of Texas A&M
goes to the Jags at 56. Logan Jones, the
interior offensive lineman, the center
out of Iowa, goes to the Bears at 57.
The Browns at 58, take Emanuel McNeel
Warren, the safety from Toledo. And then
the Texans at 59, take Marlon Klein, the
tight end out of Michigan. And the pick
is in for the Tennessee Titans at 60. As
we continue on our second round
coverage, about to be the third round
coverage of the 2026 NFL draft on the
Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
So Fred came back, right? So what I can
assume is that Fred is like, "Hey dog,
watch the counter." So when the counter
gets here, maybe D Winners is a step
ahead on the count. But Dwinners is
still doing a decent job. He was just
much better when um Fred was on the
field
>> that So, you said he was being targeted
in coverage a little bit there.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I uh just watching the
Texans uh Saints and like the Cardinals
game, the second Cardinals game a little
bit. I thought that they were finding
finding ways to get tight ends on them
and like uh running backs out the back
field taking passes downfield. Not just
like a swing or a hitch from a running
back, but they were running wheels with
him and they was kind of giving that
space. uh he would eventually catch up
and make the the tackles which is good
which is good for his athleticism but it
ain't like he breaking up the passes on
him. You know what I mean?
>> Well, he's got a Caleb DS that he's
gonna play next to.
>> Caleb D is going to tell him exactly
what's coming or Jaylen Tom's going to
tell him exactly what or Christian
Parker is going to come up with some
calculus where it don't even matter.
>> You know what that's not that that
sounds I think ridiculous to some people
sometimes like oh that's such an absurd
suggestion. We did Cowboys cross talk
with Leighton Vanderes back in October
and Leighton was talking about a lot of
times he's like it just takes one guy on
that defense especially at linebacker
knowing what they're doing
>> and if they're on their P's and Q's they
can tell everybody where to go then go
there you're going to go here you're
going to go here you're going to go here
and he said honestly it makes those
linebackers play better because they're
more on top of what's going on.
>> Yeah.
>> And you could do that at linebacker you
could do that at safety. Yeah
>> if it's I think right now Jay be that
guy. Yeah Jaylen Thompson's there. You
got Caleb DS depending on how quickly he
can pick up systems in the NFL. Maybe
he's in that confluge
part of a lot of modern defense's
communication systems and and I think
specifically for what Parker wants to
do. One thing I do want to touch on when
we get to maybe the start of the third
round is we've heard a lot of about the
brain works side of things and Christian
Parker and I want to kind of give maybe
the the casual NFL draft listener a a
little insight on what Christian Parker
means when he's talking about that brain
works and what that's supposed to to
mean moving forward. Um I want to get to
the end of the second round before we
get there. We're getting closer. Here's
the Titans at 60.
Bryant mix
>> with the assistant pick
>> in the 2026 NFL draft.
>> Oh wow.
>> The Tennessee Titans select
>> Anthony Hill Jr. Texas.
>> And there goes the final linebacker for
me there in that second round.
>> All ran ran off a linebacker run over
these last 12 20 picks.
>> Oh, that's sad.
>> Tommy.
>> All right.
>> Talk about your guy.
>> Making a making a little bit of a
switch. Yeah, Tommy Yish right on time
for Anthony Hill Jr. there, bud.
>> Like I just got caught in the bullpen.
>> Yeah, get get on in here. I'll
make the call of the pin. The uh the
Rams are on the clock, followed by the
Broncos, the Chargers, and the Seahawks
to wrap up the second round of our
coverage.
>> Well, nice being back.
>> Oh, yeah.
It is hour number three of our day two
coverage from inside the Star in Fris in
the SWBC studios here just a couple
steps away from the war room where the
Dallas Cowboys are currently sitting but
drafting at the same time. No picks made
for the Cowboys quite yet here on day
two, but they did send a fifth round
pick to the San Francisco 49ers for
linebacker and former TCU Hornfrog D.
Winters who will return to the Dallas
Fort Worth Metroplex as a linebacker
possibility at the starting side for
Christian Parker and company. Cowboys
fans, while the team is making big
picks, make the smart pick at home. Call
Onime Experts, the official AC, heating,
and plumbing partner of the Dallas
Cowboys. Fast, reliable, always on time.
That's on time experts. Visit
ontimeexperts.com
and click book now. Last couple of
selections, we will rattle them off in a
moment. Here's the Rams at pick 61.
>> Tavon Austin making the pick.
>> Ram select.
>> Here we go, man. These tight ends are
starting to go.
>> And that one was finally in order after
seeing some odd order of tight ends.
We'll start with one of them. The Jags
take Nick Boracher, tight end out of
Texas A&M at 56. The Bears at 57, take
Logan Jones, center from Iowa. Browns at
58. Emanuel McNeil Warren, safety from
Toledo. Texans at 59, take Marlon Klein,
tight end from Michigan. At 60, the
Titans take Anthony Hill Jr., linebacker
from Texas. We'll talk about him in a
moment. And then the Rams take Max
Claire, who was my number two tight end
on my board out of Ohio State. Tell me a
little bit about Claire as he goes to
LA. Try and give a little help here for
Tai Simpson. Maybe little help. Yeah, a
little help. Uh geez, I messed this up.
Uh where' my guy Claire go? Oh, there he
is. Uh, he's a transfer from Purdue and
he is a very smooth player. There's a
not a lot of wasted movement or motions
to his game for a guy his size. 65 243
is what I'm dealing with right now. Very
loose in the hips and the way he plays.
Best when he can play on the move. He's
not going to line up and hammer you as
an inline guy. He's going to do things
as a wing, a slot, wide guy. He they use
him in motion quite a bit and I like to
mot him across the field and throw him
the ball in the flat. He's super
reliable catching the ball on the move.
Good body control, balance in the way he
plays. Sticky with his hands, uh, good
focus. He works the middle of the field.
He's going to find soft spots in zones.
Blocking technique remains a work in
progress. He tends to be a little high
in his technique. I would not call him
the strongest blocker. He tends to get
in the way and tempt to tie up his man
is always trying to move in order to
find a block. He had an ankle injury in
the past that slowed him down some. and
he plays more like a big wide receiver
than a tight end. That someone I think
someone that's going to take advantage I
said that in my notes here and it looks
like to the LA Rams of that team just to
do that. So that means there are three
picks remaining here in the second
round. We are now rejoined by Tommy
Yarish of DallasCowboys.com. Nick Harris
of the Fort Worth Star Tele Telegram. Uh
Brian Bratis of 1053 the fan and Bobby
Belt of 1053 the fan as well. I'm Kyle
Yman's.
>> How are you doing, Nick? I feel like we
haven't seen you since the trade.
>> Yeah, I know. It's been It's been kind
of a wild night, huh? Um Yeah, I think
that was unexpected, but um you know, if
you're asking me, I think this is a very
safe starting spot for where you build
the linebacker position from here as the
weekend goes along. You still have to
draft at linebacker, and it doesn't
prevent you from drafting one at 92
either. Uh you need depth. You now only
have four offball linebackers on the
roster. You're going to need more than
that going into Oxnard. Uh, but I think
this is a really safe starting spot. Uh,
you know, and and Dee Winters is a very
capable NFL starter. He showed that last
year. He's shown it over the last two
years as Fred Warner has battled some
injury. Um, you know, can he be the lead
mic? That'll be the question we have
for, you know, Jerry Jones and and
Steven Jones and Will Mcclelay tonight.
Um, as as they kind of, you know, give
insight on their evaluation. But
overall, I feel like it was a really
smart move at this point. If you you're
only giving up a fifth round pick, man,
that's easy. That's easy work.
Do you remember scouting him? That was
your first year, I believe, on the draft
show.
>> It was not.
>> Oh, that was it was
>> okay. So, that was a little bit before.
Um, when when it came to the the the
breakdown that Vach was giving just a
little bit ago, he was talking about how
he's rolling downhill, making hits. He's
he's a sure tackler, one of those guys
that that you can kind of maneuver, but
he's maybe not going to be a green dot.
We I asked the question to Bobby a
little bit earlier. Does this take you
out of the running for a linebacker at
92 or is the run on linebacker taking
you out of a run uh at taking another
one at 92?
>> Yeah, I still think there would be some
some options potentially. Depends on how
high they feel about like uh you know
Jimmy Holder out of Michigan. Again, I'm
a big fan of his. Um he's not
necessarily a mic, but um again, you're
just looking for depth. You're not
necessarily looking for a mic or a will
or whatever. Um so I have, if I'm
looking at my board, Jimmy Roler out of
Michigan. I like Bryce Bcher a whole
lot, although I think most teams view
him as a day three. Uh Kyle Lewis still
on the board.
>> Yep.
>> Kyle Lewis still on the board out of
Pittsburgh. Uh get the hometown kid to
walk up on stage. Um and Caleb Armsor
out of TCU. And those are the uh those
are the three linebackers left in my top
100. So yeah, you're kind of um or four,
excuse me. You're kind of slim pickings
at the moment. But uh man, wouldn't it
be something if they walked away with
two TCU linebackers after the day if
they got Elon Zor and Winters? That
would be wild.
>> Yeah. I I I pulled up my Dwinners report
is what I did from the TCU days
>> from the 23 draft.
>> Yeah, from the 23 draft.
>> What did you have on him?
>> Yeah, this is what I said. Shorter
prospect, but does a really nice job of
finishing the plays. He's played both
inside and outside during his career. He
made a ton of starts. Was all big 12 his
senior season. Always flying the ball.
Downhill player in the way he attacks
the ball care. Has a sense for how to
get through the gaps in order to make
plays. Reads very quickly then is on his
horse. physical wrap-up tackler. Does a
really good job of bringing the ball
carrier down in space. Want him as a
forward player, but has had a nice
interception against Michigan where he
dropped in coverage and secured the
ball. He does a good job of creating
turnovers. Not best when he's coming
when he comes toe-to-toe with blockers.
He'll need to play on the move. Reads
the play with bent knees, ready posture.
He turns the run inside out to play
contain. He flashes the second gear to
chase the ball. ball care explodes from
the hips into his tackle attempts. Might
be a little short and a little slight,
but plays with toughness, emotion, can
be all the field. I like him with the I
had my when he came out of TCU.
>> Yeah, it's good stuff. Here's the Bills
at 62
>> and Buffalo.
>> They traded up for this pick, by the
way, with the Broncos who still haven't
made the second pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Buffalo Bills select
David Ignosum,
DB Ohio State.
>> Vindicated, Nick.
>> Yeah, I am vindicated. Damn it.
>> Davidson Egg Benosen. That's your guy.
>> It is. Um, yeah, I I'm I'm such a huge
fan of Davis Igbonosen. Um, the the the
stuff that he had in his junior year at
Ohio State, I loved. The one thing I
didn't love was the penalties he had. uh
I believe was it 16 in his junior season
at um it was 12 in 2024. That was
whittleled down to four in 2025. He
plays physical and he's long off the
line. So that's where you probably saw
the penalties really come into play, but
he understood how to control that
physicality a little bit more here in
25. Route the route matching reached an
elite level in 25 as well. Strong
tackler tackler. Rarely sees a matchup
that overpowers him. Uh and I just think
this last year saw him finally put
everything together. He had a sevengame
stretch, Kyle, in this last season where
he only gave up five receptions for 43
yards.
>> Wow.
>> And that's the type of presence that I
think you get from Igbonos on the
outside. I had him a CB5 in this class.
I'm a big fan. I'm bullish on Ibenos and
I am vindicated not only because he's in
the second round, but because Jim
Leonard took him. I will take it from
here. Uh if you're curious and you want
to go back and look, if you want to see,
you know, some bad tape from this last
season that I thought he could have uh
done better uh with, it was in the Texas
game. I thought his best tape from this
last season was against Illinois.
>> You were asking about him at one point.
Like why is it that like there's not
more chatter about him? Like like you
felt like you were Yeah, because you
loved him. I did have one person tell me
first off there was one person told me
that there was some maturity questions
with him.
>> But the other big thing about his play
is and I thought this is kind of an a
damning quote. Somebody had said that
what what what did I do?
>> What did I do?
There's a side convers you
>> uh somebody said I thought this was a
Damon quote they said I've never seen a
single clean game he's played on tape
>> that they just felt like there was just
sloppiness mistake like everything on
tape there was just always something
where it's like I don't know that the
guy can consistently play clean
football.
>> Yeah. The the what we were laughing at
is there was a a point during the senior
bowl process where he rejected me twice
for an interview on the field after.
>> Is that where the character concerns
came? So, initially I thought, okay,
that's kind of weird that it's the
Senior Bowl. It was open media and it
was part of it. Apparently, he just
doesn't enjoy public speaking. Like, he
he's a little
>> So, he has a stutter
>> and and it's it was a speech impediment
and which I would have 10,000%
understood at the time. Didn't
understand it until later in the
weekend.
>> Completely made sense. But we were we
were joking when you said uh a character
concern. At first, I thought that's what
it was. I was like, why would you why
would you make a a a mention of that and
just reject it? It was it was very stout
when it happened.
>> I I don't know. But I mean that was
something that years ago taking it to
basketball, Bill Walton coming out of
UCLA, a lot of people thought that he
was a like sirly individual at times or
whatever and it was just he was afraid
to speak because he had a stutter. So I
don't know. I didn't get a whole lot of
detail. I was just told told some
maturity stuff, but very well maybe
maybe there's just something connected
to he's uncomfortable around people or
or speaking with people and and that has
led to some some incorrect thoughts on
him. completely understand that you're
saying
>> I'm sorry Brian here's the Chargers at
>> Stan Humphre
>> West Chamber of Sean Mar
>> Sean Marman you saved us from that Brian
>> pick in the 2026 NFL draft
>> Geles Chargers select Jake Slaughter
>> ah there's your center
>> there you go
>> it's just like Jim Harbaugh to go and
get a really good center just kind of
bulk up in the trenches a little bit
here, huh?
>> Yeah. Can I go back with the Igbing
Nosen if I could?
>> Absolutely.
>> Did
Did I see the He you were talking about
the number of penalties. Did he have 30
penalties this year or for his career?
>> Probably. That would have to be career.
He did have 12 last season. It was
whittleled down to four this season.
>> Career for 30 for his career.
>> Okay. But this guy's made a ton of
starts and I do I do I like what you're
saying about him. the 6'2 192 is what I
have him as what I probably a little bit
bigger than that.
>> But man, the thing is I thought he was a
little bit grabby, but I love the way he
battled.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> I love the way that he was able to kind
of fight. Like I say, he's played in a
ton of games. He's always holding hand
fighting. He just stay with this guy. Um
I think somebody could try and coach him
out of those things, but man, he he is
he's such a willingness to come forward
and make plays in the running game and
the way he wants to tackle. he wants to
throw his body around uh you know he
like he's playing a lot of big time
games because like he was a transfer
from uh Old Miss and then so as you said
and now at Ohio State but I like the guy
I think if you could kind of coach him
out of the grabiness of him this the guy
with the length and the and the size is
I think really really good
>> playing bill of health too didn't miss
one game
>> and that's Davis Benosan that Brian's
talking about here we're taking a look
at Jake Slaughter who just goes to the
Chargers at pick number 63, the
penultimate pick of the second round.
The pick is in for the Seahawks, which
means we're officially into the third
round now. Uh, as the Cardinals are back
on the clock to begin the third round.
Tommy, tell me a little bit about Jake
Slaughter. I thought he was one of the
best centers in the draft.
>> Yeah, I think I thought he was too. You
talk about clean bill of health. 25
starts at center over the last two years
for Florida. This is an offense that
really struggled throughout a majority
of the season, but this past year with
the addition of Jaden Ball, you saw them
kind of take the next step. And I think
Jake Slaughter was a big reason for
that. He's good by himself. He works
well in combo blocks, too. He's got a
good strong base when he's anchoring and
pass protection. He can go up and get to
the second level like you see there to
create those big lanes. Uh, I think he's
a solid player.
>> When it uh when you look at Slaughter
specifically, I I thought he just had uh
the the good pad level, ability to
anchor against even the bigger defenders
that he went up against in the SEC. I
liked his footwork. I think he's got a
strong lower half. I thought the
technical side of his game needed a
little bit of work. Hand technique,
ability to reset were a little bit off
at times, especially timing wise. gets
his hands outside the defenders, get off
blocks that way, and it affected him,
especially against some of the better,
more technically sound defenders that he
went up against in conference play
especially. So, uh, I think he's a good
pick. I had him in the second, back half
of the second, so this is right where I
thought he would go. Uh, now with the
Seahawks on the clock, they took
>> Is there a running back on the board?
>> I was just going to make the joke. They
took the running back and uh and Jarian
Price in the first
>> first round to finish the first. Do you
think they take Emit Johnson here from
Nebraska? Just go ahead and keep
>> Mike Washington.
>> Yeah, Mike. They they already take the
running back, offensive line,
cornerback, edge, wide receiver. You
guys got any money in mind for they've
already taken the running back. So,
>> they'll take Branch.
>> Yeah, they got the the offensive line,
cornerback, edge, wide receiver.
>> Chris Brazzle,
>> deny Dennis Sutton. He could probably
fit that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Some fun fun names there.
>> By the way, I was just asking somebody
about Slaughter. They said they had him
in the sixth. They said he didn't move
anybody.
>> Oh,
>> this is another team, correct?
>> No. Yeah, I would not be sharing those
quotes from here.
>> From here.
>> Wanted to wanted to help you there.
>> Yes. Yes. No, this is another team.
>> You'll take all the other conversations.
>> Tad, I'll give you my phone. Come back
here.
>> It was from Pittsburgh. They're still
mad about last night. Apparently,
the uh final pick of the second round.
And it looks like we're about to get the
selection here from the uh Pittsburgh
stage as the sun has finally set in
Steel City.
We'll take a break after we hear from
the Seahawks here and then we will get
you ready for the third round which the
Cowboys, yes, they do select in at the
92nd overall pick. Still a ways to go.
Just under 30 selections away. Here are
the Seahawks at 64 to end the second
round. Ah jeez.
With the 64th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the world champs, Seattle
Seahawks select Bud Clark, DBTCU.
>> Really good pick out of TCU. We'll break
him down on the internet side of things,
but we got to step aside on the radio.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
So, Dallas just traded for a TCU
defender or former TCU defender and the
Seattle Seahawks close out the second
round with one Bud Clark, safety from
TCU.
>> You know who he got comped to? Because I
was asking about Bud Clark when I was in
Indie and I was meeting with some
people.
>> I got the same comp from two different
>> What is it?
>> Kirby Joseph.
>> I love it. I love it. Uh I had him as a
bat out of hell on the back end in the
sense that he'll attack the catch point
and anyone that gets in the way uh along
the way. He leads it leads to high ball
production. He does have a lot of
penalties because of that
aggressiveness, but that kind of ball
hungry style of play is obviously
desired here at the NFL level. I think
with a bit of control, he could really
be good at the next level. Uh and
there's some nickel versatility here. I
think that's very real. His run game
ability proves that. I think it's strong
enough for him to play closer to the
line of scrimmage. Although I would like
to see him beef up just a little bit
more if he were to actually slide into
that nickel role. But man, in this
Seahawks secondary with Bud Clark, throw
him in that mix with Witherspoon and him
and Worry. Uh that is a physical AF
secondary with Bud Clark in there now.
Bat out of hell.
>> Nick, you see him more as a free or
strong?
>> Uh strong. I want to see him fly
downhill and just lay a hat, you know? I
I I really like what he brings uh in
that sense. um injury history, missed
two games in 25, three in 22, and then
eight in 21 with all with undisclosed
injuries. TCU keeps that pretty under
wraps, but maybe that's something to
keep an eye on moving forward. But, uh,
overall, uh, I'm a huge fan of Bud
Clark. I think he can cover man, cover
range, and he can step up and play in
the box.
>> 313 snaps in the slot, 250 snaps in the
box, and 160 snaps deep. So, but yeah,
he is always around the ball. The ball
production is outstanding. He's got a
feel for the game when it comes to
seeing the play and being able to react
to react to it. His reactions are very
good. Run or pass. There's just no
hesitation in the way this guy plays. I
mean, when he sees it, he's going to go
and react. Movement skills, I think, are
good. He doesn't appear tight or
restricted in the way he plays. He's
very fluid uh in that plays with a
burst, and he wants to be a part of the
action. I love
>> We have some action in the war room
going on. Is that
>> Every time Brian talks, something
happens. We need to get you get you
rolling again. Yeah, there's a This is
even bigger of a conversation and a
celebration than after the trade was
made. Steve Shimco the quarterback.
>> That was Shimco.
>> They're going to take Garrett Nesmire
here.
>> Uh I don't know.
>> This is very interesting.
>> Will's on the phone.
>> So they made a trade. Somebody made they
made a trade then.
>> Who are they making a trade for whenever
it's Shimco coming in? Cowboys war room
looking live as another move has been
made. We don't know what it is quite
yet.
But they are uh they're excited about
something.
>> You're saying that Shima is quarterback
coach, right?
>> Yeah.
>> You think they traded for Nusmire here?
I mean, not trade, but do you think they
traded for him?
>> Drew traded up.
>> Drew Aller.
>> Still on the board.
>> I love Drew Aller, by the way. I know. I
take a lot of crap about him.
We are now through two rounds of the
2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
radio network and DallasCowboys.com.
Bud Clark, the safety out of TCU, was
the final selection of the second round
going to the Seattle Seahawks. The
Cardinals pick is in to begin the third
round alongside Tommy Tommy Yarish of
Dallas Cowboys.com. Brian Bratus and
Bobby Belt of 1053 the fan and Nick
Harris of the Fort Worth Star Telegram.
I'm Kyle Yman's of DallasCowboys.com
taking you through every single pick
this weekend over the 257 selections.
Cowboys have had a a busy day already
welcoming in both of their first round
picks from yesterday. Caleb DS and
Malachi Lawrence. They made a trade
earlier in the day, taking a fifth round
pick, sending it to San Francisco for
the 49ers starting linebacker last year
in, excuse me, Dwinters, the former TCU
Horn Frogs, uh, linebacker was the trade
there. We're looking inside the war room
here at the Star in Fris and there's a
lot of celebration.
>> It says that Arizona's pick is in at 65.
The Denver Broncos then are on the clock
and I wonder at 66 if they've done
something with Shawn Payeyton here.
Maybe that maybe it's going to flip here
and it's going to say Dallas is on the
clock. But uh right now it's saying the
pick for the pick for the the Arizona is
in that puts the Broncos on the clock at
60 at 66.
>> So again, kind of like what we saw from
the live reaction in the war room when
they made the trade for D. Winters. It
doesn't look like a pick has been made
yet. It it usually if that's the case,
everybody's standing up. They've got a
player on the phone. They're passing it
around multiple times and it's kind of a
a big kuruffle of people in the room.
Everybody's still situated in their
respective chairs as we're looking at it
at the moment. There's been plenty of
celebration. The one give that we've had
so far was quarterback's coach Steve
Shimco coming into the room, which could
tip us off on what they're possibly
looking at. Here's the Cardinals at pick
65.
>> Quarterback Miami Percy Beck with
>> Maybe they're just celebrating how
hilarious that pick is.
>> Do you think that could be the case? Was
that big of a selection?
>> I mean, that's hilarious to me.
>> Oh, man.
>> Carson Beck.
>> Is there a Shimco connection with Beck?
>> I don't know.
>> No, not at all.
>> I didn't know if that
>> I've never seen a quarterback more
easily rattled than Carson Beck.
>> I'm And that's not me trying to be
funny. I'm dead serious.
>> Why? Why? I just I think I think he is
broken between the ears and I would just
never
>> I'd never touch a quarterback like that.
What is it? He has like five losses in
his college career and I think the the
most wild stat out there's five losses
in his college career and I think on
every single one of them he threw an
interception with a chance to take the
lead.
>> There's there's been whispers too about
that UCL injury that he suffered uh at
the end of his last season at Georgia.
>> Yeah, teams are worried about his arm.
>> Yeah, it really took Zip off of his
>> It does not there was not a lot there.
Yeah, and Miami really did a really good
job of hiding that this last season and
putting him in positions where he just
had to drive the bus to what, you know,
he was comfortable doing and what he was
capable of doing. But I I will say he's
got a ton of starting experience. It
didn't It's funny because like what is
it? Uh I think it's 46 starts for uh
Carson Beck. 43 starts with Carson Beck.
you'd probably feel better about the 23
starts that Nusmeer had just because I I
feel like you got more out of the NUS
starts, but overall I this makes sense
for Arizona. Um he'll he'll head into a
competition with um Jacobe Brassette if
Br shows back up uh in that facility and
they will have the most mid quarterback
battle of uh the 2026 season.
>> I I got to call a game of Carson's this
year and got to talk to him a little
bit. He he is experienced and he sounds
experienced when you talk to him and the
way you you he he he carries himself is
as a veteran quarterback. The one thing
you you guys mentioned in terms of late
game scenarios, there are some times
where he's going to make the incredible
play and he's going to get hot. That's
why they go to a national championship
game. That's why they play and and are
down the wire trying to compete to to
win a national championship. All of that
is possible because he can hit a hot
streak. But in the game I called was
against SMU. He could also throw an
interception in the end zone in the
middle of overtime and end up really
giving the game away on his arm himself.
Kind of interesting. He had incredible
supporting cast around him. Uh but I
agree with most of what you guys are
saying. I don't know if I would arm
>> just isn't there and Bobb's right.
There's limitations.
>> You watch him and I hate being body
language guys. He always looks like he
is just struggling out there when it's
when it comes to making plays.
>> Here's the Broncos at 66. their first
pick of the draft.
>> Hey, on behalf of Super Bowl 50
champions,
>> Little
Penner family with the 66th pick in the
2026 NFL draft, the Denver Broncos
select Tyler on
>> D&
like
>> tell me about him a little bit. He's
somebody who like you that's a dude who
I think is really explosive and can
really shock with his hands and play
with a lot of power. That's that's a
typical of what we've seen of a lot of
these Texas Tech defensive linemen in
recent years whether it be Walter Nolan
or um you know Texas&M Walter Nolan who
then ended up at Old Miss. Uh Bobby
Brown like some of these guys who just
are explosive first step big dudes. He's
he's part of that. Although I think he
is a much more steady reliable player. I
think here, if he would have been picked
here, that would have been alongside
Kenny Clark, Quinnon Williams, he would
have been playing that, you know, four
technique head up on the tackle.
>> Uh, by the way, in the war room, they
are passing out new uh new trade charts.
>> New trade charts. Yeah.
>> Could this be another veteran?
>> It might be.
>> Maybe.
That's what it looks like to me in my
opinion.
>> I'm trying to figure out trading up.
>> I'm trying to figure out the Shimco
angle. So maybe you know a former Boston
College
>> Boston College guy
>> can't rack my brain at the moment.
>> What did he coach at Boston College?
Remember me? It was still QBs
>> OC for a year as well.
>> He was with the Seahawks in 18 and 19.
>> Is there a wide receiver out there
that's Boston College former?
>> Yes. That plays for the Ravens that I
don't think we'd be able
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> I don't think it'd be that big.
>> Yeah. Oh, that would be a wild change.
Here's the Raiders at 67.
>> NFL draft. The Raiders select Kron
Crawford, defensive end, Auburn.
>> He was the highest rated player outside
of Javon McCoy on my board remaining.
Edge rusher from Auburn. Kron Crawford.
Tommy, I know you were really high on
him.
>> Yep. If you want to watch some really
good Kieran Crawford tape, go watch the
Iron Bowl this past year. I was texting
Nick while I was watching it and saying,
"Man, Kelrick Faulk is nice and all, but
who is this 24 kid? He is just
consistently getting into the backfield.
He's a freak athlete, built like a
monster. I still feels like he's kind of
learning how to rush the passer and
needs more of a plan, but he's got all
the tools to really develop into a
strong starter because he can close
quickly. He's got all the intangibles
and measurables that you want. And yeah,
if this guy lands with a good coaching
staff and and we'll see what the staff
in Oakland does, he he can be a really
strong player.
>> You like uh you like Kiron Crawford
there, Brian? 67 to the
>> Yeah, let me let me do some housekeeping
here real quick and I'll get back with
you on that.
>> I'll I'll do some housekeeping while
you're doing housekeeping. How about
this? Last couple of picks to begin the
third round. Carson Beck, quarterback
from Miami, 65th overall to the
Cardinals. The Broncos finally make a
pick. They've been trading back and back
and back all the way through uh the
draft. They take uh Tyler Onion,
>> Bill Walsh of them.
>> Yeah. Interior defensive tackle from
Texas A&M at 66 67. Then it's Kron
Crawford, the Raiders.
>> Yeah, I got you covered here. Thanks for
that time. Uh yeah, this is a guy could
play he he's like a a guy that could be
like a standup rush linebacker prospect.
Plus with the you know with his athletic
traits, he's twitchy. He rushes with
ideal energy. He's like a quarterback
hunter. I like the way that he gets off
the ball. I way like the way he gets up
the field, the change of direction,
quickness. I mean, he can he's kind of a
bendy guy. The lower half is good.
You'll see him sink. You see him trim
the edge. Uh good pop in his hands to
attack the blocker. He gives a like he
can reroute tight ends when you put him
over the top of this guy. Uh, you know,
there was times where you see him though
when when you watch him play the
Vanderbilt game, they ran the ball by
him a couple of different times where he
just didn't appear very aware. I think
he's got the physical makeup you love to
be on the edge. Uh, you'll see him drop
into coverage occasionally. He doesn't
look out of place. This guy's best
football might be ahead of him, though.
But again, the the the athletic ability,
the length, all those things, the
twitchiness, but where where's the
instincts on this guy and where's the
awareness, you know, when you're
watching a game and all a sudden the
ball's kind of going by him a couple of
different times like he didn't react all
that well. But I love the way this
player physically looks.
>> Doesn't sound like anything happened in
the Cowboys war room.
>> I'm going with they thought the Carson
Beck pick was hilarious.
>> You think it was something like that?
Either that or they're messing with us
and they're faking like something
happened. They heard how we were able to
watch the war room reaction whenever
they made the trick the
>> I have that happen enough. I don't need
them to do it, too.
>> Yeah. And they're just they're just
messing around just being in a silly
goofy.
>> It was it was an animated
>> It was more animated than the trade.
>> I bet I bet you what happened I bet you
what happened is they had bets when Beck
was going to get picked
>> and some people won a bet is what
happened.
>> Do you ever have one of those in the war
room?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Do you remember one?
>> Oh, off the top of my head. I'm not
kidding. I know of a couple years ago,
>> but we've had where it's like somebody
just yells pre-draft. They go
>> a hundred bucks. Carson Beck doesn't get
picked until the And then everybody
jumps in
>> 100 Reese's pieces.
>> Yeah.
>> What if they said the third cup?
>> Are we allowed to Oh, that's right. I'm
sorry. We're not
>> I don't work with this group. But the
but the thing the thing about it is the
Sorry, Derek. I do work for you. But the
the thing about it is Yeah. We we fil
that that thing.
>> Well, this might be the last.
>> You guys might be on your own after this
one. But uh but yeah, there in the in
the room you have friendly wagers. Okay.
>> I'm
>> not like Bounty Gate or anything like
that.
>> No, no, no, no, no. I do know that there
was a
>> I'll say AFC West.
>> Okay.
>> Team.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh sometime within the last 10 years.
>> Go ahead and say the Broncos.
>> No, I'm going to be broad.
uh within the last 10 years at AFC West
team that when they got to Indie, their
personnel department was taking wagers
on how heavy a receiver was going to
check in at the comb.
>> I know
that's unfortunate.
Yeah. I I mean it could have been
something as simple as hey I I don't
think Carson Beck will
>> I I bet you bet somewhere in the
>> I bet you Simco said that he said this
guy is going to go
>> is going to go in day two and and now
and they and
>> it's like the last pick, you know.
>> Yeah. And and here they are. Everybody
now has to pay
>> or first or the third.
>> Everybody this Philadelphia Eagles at 68
>> the 68th pick of the 2026 NFL draft. The
Philadelphia Eagles select Markeel Bell
tackled from Miami.
>> Speaking of getting to Indie and wonder
how overweight somebody will be.
>> Yeah, this is the biggest player in the
draft almost.
>> Yeah. 6'9", 346 lbs. It's enormous. Now,
I think he's got some real potential.
But you pair him with Cameron Williams
and that Philadelphia offensive line,
you have you have a refrigerator store.
>> It's two mountains.
>> You have a refrigerator factory. Oh my
goodness. Their strategy is going to
throw a bunch of power forwards at you
and hope that it works in the run game.
>> You think Markeel Bell's a power forward
at 346?
>> Well, he's 69. So, yeah,
>> that's insane.
>> Still, I'm still thinking he's a center.
He's he's a shorter shack is what what
you're playing at the on the on the
hardwood. Anyways, tell me about him
though, Tommy.
>> Yeah, I you know, I think the the size
is evident. Obviously you look at the
measurables and because of that when he
gets his hands on you it it's going to
be really tough and you know
unfortunately on that as we're watching
here we looked at D'Angelo Ponds being
the receiving end of that 5'9 against 69
that's not even fair over and over again
>> that's that's just kind of typically
what what you've seen with Bell when he
gets his hands on you. The issue is when
he's going up against quicker maybe
twitchier guys that can take advantage
of the fact that he's not the best
athlete for his size. obviously at that
size and that weight, he he's not going
to be the best mover. So, that's what
really worries me about him is, you
know, you think about the the pass
rushers that he's going to have to face
twice a year. I mean, you think about
the New York Giants alone, Arl Ree and
Abdul Carter, Brian Burns, those are
guys that because of how they play, you
might he might struggle to go up against
just because they can get around him and
he's not going to be able to kick out
quick enough. So yeah, the size is one
thing, but there still needs to be an
element, I think, of development and
technique and and being able to hold up.
>> And here's the pair, the the Bears pick
at pick number 69. Nice. Nice.
>> They're representing Friends of the
Children, an incredible organization
that focuses on the importance of
mentorship and empowering youth.
The NFL and the Bears work with Friends
of the Children as part of our inspired
change initiative. Tylen and Timothy,
it's time to announce the pick.
>> With the 69th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Chicago Bears select
>> Sam Roses.
>> The tight end.
>> Nicely. Yeah. Sam Rou.
>> Yeah, that is not Roses.
>> Yeah. Sam Marouch, Stanford tight end.
>> There was a I had a a a thought that he
might have been a cowboy tomorrow.
>> Wow.
>> Tomorrow, huh?
>> Yeah. Didn't work out obviously, but
like I think he would have been if he
were around when they were picking in
the fourth, I could have seen him be in
contention.
>> I had him in the fourth. Decent player.
>> Gosh, add him with Colston Level.
>> I I don't understand that one. I don't
know if I I don't know if I get that
one. I tell you, he's one of the better
philosophy. He's one of the better
blocking tight ends in the draft,
though. I mean, if you if you look at
how he played, let me
>> So, this is just Ben Johnson, 12
personnel.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's just gonna he's going
to pair him together.
>> Run 13.
>> He's gonna he's going to he's going to
just try and beat you up.
>> Oh, jeez. I hate when I do this.
>> He'll line up fullback, too.
>> They have another tight end on that
roster outside of Loveland, right?
>> Yeah. This guy This guy's like a This
guy stands out. He's one of the few
plugandplay tight wide tight ends that
inline blocking guys. Uh, I think he can
make cut off blocks. I think the combo
blocks, the gap scheme stuff he's good
at.
>> The pass protection as a receiver, he's
not stiff, but he he's not the most
elusive guy.
>> Uh, he needs to apply more of toughness
into his playing style when it's about
the catches. I don't think the toughness
is there for a blocking, but maybe some
of the stuff with the contested stuff is
a little bit of a of a problem for him.
But I'll tell you what, his size, his
toughness, I think he's pro ready as a a
blocking uh guy. So, he's he's not going
to run away from you in the open field
or anything like that. Here's the 49ers
at 70.
>> San Francisco 49ers
>> Romelo Height
by San Francisco.
We just had a out of Texas Tech. That's
all I was going to
>> Real quick, Brian, what I was gasping
at. What I was gasping at was you missed
it. Merlin Olsen is the great uncle of
your boy Roush from Stanford.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Like Merlin Olsson. Little
House in the Prairie.
>> Uh
>> and a defensive tackle.
>> He was an edge.
>> Was he?
>> Merlin Olson. Yeah. Deacon Jones the
Fearsome Forsome, right?
>> Yeah, he was on Fearsome Force. I just
thought he was the tackle.
>> All right. Romelo Height goes 70th
overall to the San Francisco 49ers. Sam
Ro, the tight end from Stanford, goes
the pick before that to the Bears. And
then at 68, Markeel Bell, offensive
tackle from Miami, goes to the
Philadelphia Eagles. We are right now
with the Commanders on the Clock, the
71st overall pick. You're listening to
the 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
Radio Network and DallasCowboys.com.
Romelo Height. Oh, he's a defensive
tackle. Merlin.
>> Oh, thanks for the research, Kyle.
>> Sorry, dude.
>> Yeah, thanks. Good call.
>> I thought he was an edge. I thought he
was an edge, too. I think with I was
thinking of Deacon Jones Merlin. Yeah,
he's played inside. You're right about
that. You're right.
>> Congrats, Bobby. Yeah, good job being
right today, Bobby.
>> Thanks for researching that.
>> Me and Tommy don't know anything about
preforward pass days.
>> Man, come on, man.
>> I'm just playing.
>> All right. Can I uh you want to know
what my You want to You want to hear a
fun inside joke that uh Nick and I were
or not an inside joke, an inside
conversation Nick and I were having when
we were thinking something was happening
in the Cowboys war room?
>> Yeah.
because you sit there and you start
trying to connect dots and you go
Shimco's in there and then I saw Jon
Steven Jones looked really hype and so
then I was asking Nick I was like god
this would not be trading up for Ton
Green what
that's but that's probably what they
wanted they would be they wanted us to
start asking things like that
>> Green's my guy I that's the crazy state
we get to with this stuff we start
looking at like well why is Steven Jones
super excited is this Arkansas and
Shimco's there
>> the uh I I do have a feeling that at
some point they will try and get us to
go off sides just because they know
they're being consistently monitored on
the stream side of things. And I know
for a fact because somebody stopped me
yesterday prior to the first round
that's in the camera shot as we're
talking about right now. Somebody in
that room, I'm not going to say who, and
they said, "Hey, I've been watching the
podcast. I watched your last episode uh
before the or from Tuesday going into
the first round." There are people in
there that watch the coverage here. And
if that's the case, I wouldn't be
surprised if they did try and find a
fake moment to catch us off sides
because how much we do uh end up
>> making if that's the case
>> making the most out of it.
>> Tip of the hat, fellas.
>> I don't know if that's what happened
here, but
>> when you when you don't have a pick for
60 of them, you have to create might as
well get bored and and have some fun
with it.
>> When you look at that screen, let's say
that's what they were doing, whose idea
would that have been, do you think? Who
do you think was like, let's screw with
them? Stephen.
>> Yeah, I think that's Stephen and Will.
Either I was gonna say Will, but Stephen
is fair. Shotty would say it, too.
>> Yeah, they all would absolutely. Do we
>> Do we have some thoughts about height,
by the way? Anybody have any thoughts
about
>> I was kind of hoping to get back to the
>> Just because he's a Texas Tech guy. I
want to make sure as much. Sorry. No
problem. The uh
>> Commander,
>> they are about to pick.
>> The commanders are on the clock. That's
what's happening.
>> Uh
>> Kyle's nickname used to be different
about five years ago.
>> Oo. Then I became commander.
>> No.
>> What?
>> Talking about the the nickname,
>> the moniker from Washington.
>> You did spend a lot of summers in West
Virginia.
>> So I was the the football team.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes.
>> Oh,
>> it's not even day three.
>> It's not.
>> This is my day two theory.
>> Something's wrong with Pernome.
>> Really? I think.
>> All right, we are six picks into this
third round of the 2026 NFL draft in
Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Carson Beck,
the first pick of the third. He goes to
the Cardinals, followed by the t
defensive tackle out of Texas A&M, Tyler
Uny uh to the Denver Broncos at 66 67.
And the Raiders take Kron Crawford, the
edge out of Auburn. Markeel Bell, the
offensive tackle from Miami, goes to the
Eagles at 68.
>> And then Sam Rous, the tight end from
Stanford, goes to the Bears at 69,
followed by Romelo Height, edge rusher
from Texas Tech, 70th overall to the San
Francisco 49ers. The commanders pick is
in at 71. But I want to talk about
Romelo Height a little bit here, Brian,
because
>> Go for it.
>> He was one or you I was wanting you to
go for it because he's one of the best
edge rushers I had left on the board.
>> Yeah. The thing about him and I know
here we're gonna they're gonna about to
announce the pick, right? I can see
walking on stage.
>> You got it.
>> I can feel it. But absolutely feel it.
>> All right, here's the commander and then
we'll talk about Romelo Heights. Don't
throw up B- roll quite yet.
>> Hello Pittsburgh
tonight.
>> Leslie Shepard Bryant
>> first and foremost to an amazing amazing
town sports town and fans Pittsburgh.
Thank you for being a great host of the
2026 draft. You guys are amazing.
As much as I am into introducing our
next pick, I want to say this first and
foremost. Tomorrow I get a great
opportunity for you Pittsburgh to pass
the torch to myself and my fellow crew
in Washington DC.
Is that Mark's 2026
27 NFL draft on the MALL IN WASHINGTON
DC WASHINGTON THE SPORTS capital
>> it's just the capital actually
commanders haven't picked since sunny
Styles by the way it's been a minute
>> got some information today earlier today
it's getting any quicker either
>> the girls
>> they still haven't picked
>> flag football became an officially
sanctioned
high school varsity sport in Maryland
paving the way
>> creating access.
>> Mark Ingram literally already said all
this earlier Harris and the commander
organization for making this possible.
It'll also be great for my
granddaughters Malaya Merrick and Macy
Grace for their opportunities to thank
you so much for GIRLS FLAG FOOTBALL A
HIGH SCHOOL SANCTIONED event in
Maryland. Thank you so much
>> honor with the 71st pick in the 2026 NFL
draft.
Sunny Styles was a a character,
>> a great football player. He's gonna be
one of the top football players for our
organization for years to come.
>> He's getting booed.
>> Dan Quinn and the Washington Commanders.
I want to say we select
>> Oh my god.
>> We don't go defense pick, we go offense.
>> Antonio Williams, WIDE RECEIVER,
University of Clemson. It's
>> Clemson University.
>> Hakee Mazdor is now 30.
Welcome to the 2027 NFL draft coverage
from Washington DC. Appreciate
>> Do we have to rethink this? Do we have
to rethink the announcer people?
>> Yeah, we have to rethink that.
Absolutely.
>> Yeah. Who used it? Was Gene Upshaw on
day two? Typically,
>> I was I want to go back to the days of
when Bert Bell was commissioner in the
60s and we're at a hotel and people were
smoking while we were doing this. You
know, they were smoking cigarettes.
>> Were you scouting in the 60s? I'm just
telling you, they had it they did it on
a chalkboard and the guy and there was
one guy and you just everybody just
yelled their pick and we went on that
way and we didn't have all this.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm I'm sorry.
>> No, I'm with you.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Unless it's Drew Pearson. I love it when
it's Drew Pearson.
>> No, you you need to we need to rethink
this. We absolutely as a league. Okay.
Romelo Height.
>> Yeah. Uh so we're taking a look at
Antonio Williams on the screen. I want
you to
>> You guys could talk about him. I want to
talk about height.
>> Do it. Give it. You guys can talk about
height. I'll talk about height. You talk
about the receiver. This kid transferred
from four schools. Uh, basically Auburn,
USC, Georgia Tech, and now is at Texas
Tech. He is an older guy. He's a
25-year-old guy, but this is an
explosive guy. The first step quickness.
He can get up the field. He can get
around blockers in a hurry. He is a
great job of putting stress on blockers.
Impressive change of directions. Does a
really good job of setting up pass rush
moves. Is very effective using his hand,
shoulder fakes to keep the blockers off
balance. Unbelievable. They about to
pick again.
>> Yep. The last guy took two.
>> Really really good motor for the
position. This guy deserved his due.
Like I say, there's some things you
probably need to know about off the
field, but here we are.
>> Honestly, it's fine. I I I will add
>> they picked a David Fulture, by the way.
>> Yeah, I will add that the age is
obviously going to be the concern with
Romeo height, but I think it comes with
experience with him. I think he's going
to give you a high motor and that
athleticism is going to be thrown out on
the edge. Man, I love him as a deployed
pass down pass rusher just to keep fresh
over the course of games and really
allow him to go pin his ears back and go
attack the quarterback. I I I like
Romelo Height. I was surprised he fell
this much as a draft process.
>> I do too. And maybe maybe
>> interviews weren't great there. That's
probably was it
>> and and that's you know I understand
that but um you know I think he's going
to be a really talented pass rusher.
>> Uh all right, Takario Davis corner from
Washington goes to the Bengals at pick
number 72. We're now 20 selections away
from the Cowboys. We're getting closer
there, guys. 40 down, 20 more to go from
where we started the day in terms of
Dallas picking.
>> Can I speak on Takario?
>> Absolutely.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Let's do Takario Davis. Uh
out of looked at him, you speak on them.
>> Or excuse me, out of Washington
formerly.
>> Speak on them until we pick.
>> Um so
Washington had these two palm trees at
cornerback. It was Takario Davis and
Ephesians Pryock. And it was really
tough for me to kind of discern which
one was better. And I had Takario Davis
as 16 and Price sock at 17 on my board.
Uh both at the top of the fourth, but
he's the tallest corner and the long
longest wingspan in the entire class. 80
and 78 inches. I he is a uh he he's
incredibly long out on the boundary. Uh
it gives him natural advantages that
make even the biggest of missteps and
coverage nonfatal just because of how
long his limbs do uh stretch. I like him
in a in a zone scheme where he doesn't
necessarily have to cover step for step,
but can use his instincts to anticipate
and his length to attack the ball. Uh
size and physicality. It leads to
penalties and he isn't necessarily a
short tackler. You would like to see
that with that size and I want more ball
production there with that size, too. Uh
bad tape last year, Michigan. Good tape
Ruters. Um I I would uh he only played
seven games last year. There was some
injury concerns, too. Um dealt with rib
and hamstring injuries last year. Li
limited his availability. Uh, so many
people felt great about Takario Davis if
he was to come out last year. He was
probably going to get picked in the
second round if he had come out last
year, maybe even back in first. Um, but
he transfers to Washington. Uh, and um,
you know, it battled some injury and
didn't have the best tape in the world.
He eventually ends up slipping to the
third, which isn't, you know, terrible,
but uh, I I I liked Davis just not as a
day two prospect.
>> By the way, Oscar Delp just goes to Kell
Moore in the New Orleans Saints. 12
overall.
>> Yeah, how about that? Georgia tight end
goes there. And then the Giants just
traded into the 74th pick as they're on
the clock and their pick is already in.
We're moving here in round number three.
>> About time.
>> 74th pick is on the way from the Giants
momentarily. Anybody want to talk about
Oscar Delt?
>> Uh yeah, well-rounded receiving threat
with good speed and change direction to
get himself open quickly. He's got soft
hands to pluck the ball out of the air.
Can turn up field for larger gains after
the catch. might need to add a little
bit of weight to grow a little bit
stronger as a blocker. Not really an
ankle breaker when he's in the open
field. Uh only 70 career catches in four
years at Georgia. Uh he can get held up
against physical defenders early. That's
what I had on. Oscar Delp, tight end
from Georgia.
Tight ends off the board now so far. Of
course, Sadi who went day one. Lots of
day two tight ends though. Max Clair,
Eli Sters, Sam Rous, Oscar Delp, Nate
Borcature, Marlon Klein. I mean, there's
a run on tight ends.
>> There's a run on tight ends for sure.
>> One note on Delt. Uh there are teams
that think he's uh not just pure tight
end that he's a lot of Hback trades,
too.
>> Oh, okay. Just a ball carrier in the in
general. Here's Giants at 74.
>> The New York Giants select
>> Mark
>> Malachi Fields wide receiver Notre Dame
>> Malachi Fields. this. Are are people
upset with the Zachariah Branch arrest?
>> No, there's no way.
>> I wouldn't think so. But
he's a body catcher. He's tiny and he's
a body catcher.
>> Like when we're talking about like
argued that all day.
>> Sure. 100%. But like this draft is like
the draft has shown us in recent years
like they love electric with the ball in
his hands and that's him. Yeah.
>> I'm I'm just surprised that he's getting
passed over to this point. I I thought
he was going to go in the second. Are
teams tired of trying to find the
smaller wide receiver that replicates
what Tyreek Hill was able to do? Because
there was a point in time where
everybody was looking for the next
Tyreek Hill and a lot of teams fell
short in doing so. And not to say
Zachariah Branch is a comp directly to
Tyreek Hill, but just those smaller
receivers that are electric and screen
plays.
>> Boys, I'm just telling you, the guy is a
small guy that body catches. That's I
mean that's that's something I mean you
you could see him go across the field,
he'll catch it, but man he will contort
his body to make like all kinds of
catches. Give him credit for that, but
you can't be that small and be a body
catcher. And I know he's explosive, ball
in hand, all that stuff. But I I I kept
watching him like I can't see this with
this guy. I can't see it. I can't see
it. How do you have a guy this small
that's a body catcher? It's one thing
for him to extend and catch the football
and get up the field, but if he's having
to stop and then contort his body in
order to make plays, I I I could see why
teams are not like
>> I I may be misremembered. Didn't Percy
Harvin body catch?
>> Yeah,
>> Brandon Cooks.
>> I mean, Harvin survived in the NFL as a
similar skill set,
>> but Harvin was Harvin was he picked when
he picked super high uh with Okay,
Harvin was Minnesota then Seattle or is
it Seattle and Minnesota? I'm trying to
think. He was uh Minnesota then Seattle
and I'm trying he had one more stop
>> which like Austin turtle I mean uh
Austin
Cooks Brandon Cooks is very much a body
catcher.
>> I
>> but I the limited route tree is is I'm
>> and he's and he's big look look and and
Harvin's bigger than Branch is but it's
it's still to me like if you're just
talking about like
>> people fell in love with the highlight
tape on that cat that's
>> Tavon Austin. No, the uh the branch.
>> Well, Tayon Austin, too.
>> Yeah,
>> if they fell in love with the teams
didn't fall in love with it.
>> Yeah. See, Wooluk's outside. He's waving
because he was one of the guys was
arguing for a tiny body catcher.
>> Yeah. I I like Zachariah Branch. Now, do
I like him more than some of the other
receivers on the board? Now,
>> did you have him higher than Brennan
Thompson?
>> No, I actually had him in the fifth
round.
>> Okay. Brennan Thompson higher.
>> I had all those tiny guys.
>> So, you had Sunny St. I had Thompson in
the fifth. I I I like Thompson in terms
of speed and explosion, but
>> Where's your board?
>> Does Bobby have a board? That's the
question.
>> I don't have I don't have I don't have
it stacked by How about this, Nick?
Let's have a bet.
>> Let's do it.
>> I'll bet. And I I signed the gambling
waiver. I no longer work here. Let's
have a bet when Bobby quits on all of
us. How about that?
>> Well, there's no one here who would make
me do that.
But I'm going to ask you I'm going to
ask you this question though, like I
said about have you have you have you
like your board. I want to see your
board.
>> I don't have it like that. I don't No, I
never do it like that. I don't ever
stack it up as a board. I stack it up. I
go position by position grades.
>> Okay.
>> I rest,
>> man. Mine.
>> I rest. I rest.
>> I don't do it that way.
>> Malachi feels what a great player.
>> Do we have the ding ding ding?
>> Ding. Yeah,
>> guys. Is German McCoy still out there?
Brian wants to know.
>> Oh man. Uh he is he is still on the
board.
>> All right.
>> Big week at the Senior Bowl.
>> Yeah, he did have a great week at the
Senior Bowl. You want to talk about his
time in Mobile, Tommy?
>> He as well. Let's get away from me.
>> Smell away.
>> Bobby just walked across the table to
give Brian a hug live on air.
>> The I think Keelin Robinson just went
>> from Texas.
>> The thing with the the thing with the
thing with McCoy.
>> Yep. Did Did you know about all the knee
the knee the serious knee problems he
had?
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, like I mean
>> he's out there as of like a couple days
ago, right?
>> Yeah. But I mean like you know certain
things it's just like
there there's obviously and and even now
I don't know how much I would even want
to say specifically about it. Why not?
>> There because there's there's just
dealing with medical information. Um
>> all of a sudden if we listen to your
show
>> No no no no no. I I think I think I
think you can say the medical is bad. I
just don't know that I would want to get
into specifics. Like I wouldn't want to
necessarily get into like the exact
specifics especially
here on this spot. Um just because of
how that that's typically viewed. Um but
I I do think that no the medical has
been bad. I don't think the Cowboys
specific like we can just throw out
this. I don't know that the Cowboys
would even take him
I don't know like it may have to be on
day three sometime.
>> Wow. Jer Daniel Jeremiah's top 200 uh
best remaining available just popped up
on the screen.
>> He's number one.
>> He was number one on the remaining. He's
19 overall. The next highest player.
>> Yeah.
>> 53.
>> Yeah,
>> that's that's
>> here's the Dolphins at 75. Sorry, Brian.
>> In the 2026
NFL draft, the Miami Dolphins select
Kale Douglas, wide
>> receiver.
>> Another Red Raider. And that's a bit of
a surprise. Wow. Okay. This was somebody
that the Cowboys maybe thought would be
available on day three is like
>> late day three.
>> Yeah, he's a physical receiver. Uh he
has special teams experience, so he's
going to bring you a uh a high floor. Um
but wow, third round. That's that's
pretty surprising. He had a good he had
a good process, I will say, and
interviewed really well, but wow, this
is crazy.
>> He's not the Texas Tech wide receiver we
talked to at in Mobile, was it?
>> Did we talk to him on on radio row?
>> We did. Yeah, we did. We did. Had him on
the draft show. Oh my goodness, I'm
blanking.
>> Forbidden High Tower.
>> Yep. For High Tower legend.
>> Tell me about him, Tommy.
>> Yeah, big body uh contested catch guy.
You saw the the the clip in the red zone
and you'll probably see a bunch more of
him, but uh I thought he was nice at at
Proday. You know, obviously routes on
air. It's different, but you could just
kind of tell general chatter along the
sidelines where we were standing out
there in Lick that people kept an eye on
number five. Uh yeah, this is like like
you guys said, this was maybe a day
three kind of guy that Dallas would have
been interested in. I'm surprised that
it's this early, but and I wouldn't be
surprised if it ends up paying off. It
might just take some time. This is, you
know, remember it's a new coaching
staff, entirely new offense. Malik
Willis is probably their starting
quarterback.
>> There were some in the league who
believed he was a free agent.
>> Yeah, that's
>> that is that's a surprise. I looked at
220 players and he was not one of them.
So, he'll probably end up being an allp
pro like Tuka.
>> I had him pretty far down the list
myself even after we talked to him at
the Senior Bowl. I liked his his
interview that we had with him, but
still not not a a day two pick as we
would anticipate. All right, the pick is
in for the Steelers at 76 as Steel City
gets ready to swing the terrible towels.
Couple guys walking on the stage. Tough
to see from our angle as here's the
Steelers selection at 76 here in the
third round.
>> This is a pick from the George Pri. How
we doing? Notable
>> in the building, man. We here. We here,
>> man. It's an honor. It's a blessing. I'm
glad to be here with all y'all.
LET'S GO STEELER NATION.
>> I love this. I do too.
>> With the 76 pick in the 2026 NFL DRAFT,
the Pittsburgh Steelers select, Drew
Aller.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Quarterback.
>> He stays in PA. He's going to play for
the Pittsburgh Steelers. Penn State
quarterback Drew Aller. The 76th overall
pick to the Pittsburgh Steelers. All
right, we've got to step aside. You're
listening to the 2026 NFL draft on the
Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> That seems like the best trade or excuse
me, the best pick you could have made
for that team here, right?
>> Yeah.
>> One of the best values, best needs.
>> I had him over Simpson
>> on my board.
>> Don't disagree.
>> I had him on my board over Simpson. And
I'll tell you why. I mean, maybe it's me
because of my old school, you know, way
quarterbacks look and Penn State
probably not a great history of this,
but man, he has got an elite frame and,
you know, he looks like that he's one of
these guys that came out of a factory
the way he is. And maybe that's fitting
to my eye. He's got experience. Um, he's
got velocity. I mean, he he could drive
the ball into windows. And I I mean he a
lot of these passes he throws are hot
with very little effort. I mean he's
kind of a flick the wrist and the ball
gets down the field. I could he stands
on the right hash, throws it all the way
outside left hash. I've seen him kind of
all of a sudden pressure. He climbs
slides inside the pocket. You know you
could look at some games like in 2024 if
you want to go back Oregon Washington
very capable in those games. Um he's
complete capable of stacking up a lot of
yards uh you know throwing the football,
but you know sometimes there's some
things pre- snapped that he you know he
he kind of gets a little bit locked on.
But I I I'll say this though, he's
willing to throw the ball up sometimes
and and make big plays. And I I admire
him for that. But man, this is one of
those guys the size, the arm talent and
I think that somebody works with him. I
I think Penn State, there were a lot of
things that happened to him injury-wise
that kind of hurt him and that, you
know, Penn State was a team that was
highly thought of uh going into the into
the preseason and all and it just didn't
work out. But like I say, the size, the
arm talent, I think somebody's going to
work with him on his mechanics. I would
not be surprised if we see this guy
starting in a couple years. All of the
good and all of the bad with Drew Rowler
is very similar to Christian Hackenberg
who was also a Penn State quarterback
from your I mean it's a lot of the same
stuff and Hackenberg was such it felt
like such a good opportunity to get a
future starting quarterback on day two.
>> With Hackenberg I didn't feel like to me
that he had the the arm talent.
>> I I think I think I think Aller I think
Aller's arm is better.
>> I think Hackenberg processed better.
>> Yeah. I think that they're very similar
in that they regressed as they went
along. It didn't get better. Everybody
kept waiting for it to get better. Now,
obviously, there was a bigger thing
related to Hackenberg with Bill O'Brien
leaving that was tied to that. A lot of
people felt like um but man, it's I I I
really like all the traits with Aller. I
just don't know if he's ever going to
put it together.
>> Well, if there is a place that
>> Here's the Packers at 77.
>> I would have taken Nesmire over this guy
though.
>> I would too. Me too.
>> Me, too. 7th pick in the 2026
NFL draft. The Green Bay Packers select
Chris Mlen, defensive tackle, Missouri.
Rolling into hour number four of our day
two coverage on the Dallas Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com. I'm
Kyleman's back with you. We've got Tommy
Yarish of DallasCowboys.com, Brian
Bratus of 1053 The Fan, Nick Harris of
the Fort Worth Star Telegram, Bobby Belt
of 1053 the Fan along with Zack Walchuk
as well, and then Botch Lombardi,
YouTube superstar and crown global
media.
>> Glad you're here. What's up, Votch? as
he walks back in the room getting ready
for the next hour. The Cowboys are going
to pick in this hour as they are about
15 selections away from where they sit
at the 92nd pick. Last couple of
selections off the board. Caleb Douglas,
wide receiver from Texas Tech, goes to
the Dolphins at 75. 76. This is an
interesting one. The Pittsburgh Steelers
take the quarterback from Penn State,
Drew Aller, the experienced QB from the
Nitney Lions, goes to the Steelers. And
Mike McCarthy gets another quarterback
to try and mold into the future. Chris
Mlen, the defensive tackle from
Missouri, goes to the Packers at 77. And
the Colts have their pick in at 78.
Falcons on the clock at 79.
>> Can I ask you specifically, man? What's
that?
>> Absolutely. What did y'all think about
your player Sam Rous going up there and
our Texas Tech wide receiver not named
Reggie Virgil? What did y'all think of
those?
>> Caleb Doug Douglas.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I didn't get a chance to
watch them. But what did y'all think
about those picks and the placement of
them?
>> They were both early.
>> Yeah,
>> very early.
>> I feel you, bro.
>> Douglas, that high is wild.
>> Yeah, I was listening to the broadcast.
They were uh talking about Rash. They
said, "Yeah, man. Rash going to catch
the football. He's not a good block."
And I was like, "Damn, I think the
opposite."
>> Hey, I thought so, too.
>> Better be a bad day for them boys on TV,
man.
>> That's why you turn on the draft show
instead.
>> Turn on the draft show, man. We get it
right.
>> Probably a good idea. Watch a lot of
film over here.
>> Catch my board up.
>> All right. Like you said, the the next
couple of selections is right around
where it wouldn't cost Dallas a lot to
make a move and at least get rolling
back toward the the top of the draft
board. Are there any possibilities here
in terms of who's left on your board
that would interest Dallas in moving up
a little bit instead of staying put at
at 92?
>> I tell you what, uh has ke been taken?
>> He's not been.
>> Nope.
>> Let me tell you what, man. from Miami.
>> Um, safety
>> Wheatley
>> or safety. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> Kilgore.
>> Jaylen Kilgore. The highest player on my
board is Malik Muhammad. Uh, and then
it's Jaylen Kilgore, Keonte Scott. Um,
Kante Scott's a fascinating one. He's a
guy that uh was reported as a 30 visit
uh for the Cowboys. Um, they
Shottenheimimer, Christian Parker went
to his proday. Uh, would be would be
very fascinating.
>> Nick, would you
>> 30 visit and a formal at the combine?
Would you take Keonte Scott after
drafting Downs and signing um Thompson?
Yeah, that's
>> because that's exactly where I would
play him. You know what I mean? So, it
kind of eliminates him a little bit.
>> Great surplus. Um but I don't know. I
don't know what a surplus gets you right
now.
>> I'm a sicko. I just take them all the
>> I'm with you. I I I'm going to take the
best player here. Um I think they're at
a luxury right now after trading for D
Winters where they're at a luxury of
taking BPA. And that could be offensive
line, that could be receiver, it could
be doubling up in the secondary. I know
they said no, they don't want any red
shirts. They don't want any guys that
are that are banged up, but Jamal McCoy
following the 92, does that interest you
at all?
>> I don't know what the medicals look
like. And based on what I've heard
around the league Yeah. based on what
I've heard around the league as far as
what the um how scary the medicals are.
Uh I'm probably good. I I think I' I'd
probably look at
>> uh Malik Muhammad, Jaylen Kogore, Keonte
Scott. These are all DBs I have higher
than Jama. Nick, um, is there a bad
medical on Wheatley or is he like a bad
dude or something? Uh, the safety from
>> We liked Wheatley a lot more than the
rest of the world did. I think I think
we just kind of got No, like we
>> I think we got in a bubble about
Wheatley.
>> I like him a lot
>> and I I think we're going to be right.
>> Teams really suck at drafting, Nick.
>> I think we're going to be right about
Wheatley. I love Wheatley. I'm with you
100%. Wheatley's like,
>> did you like Wheelies? I did. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> He's the number one side of McCoy left
on my board.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And AJ Holly there, too. Lot of good
safeties here.
>> Kamari Ramsey.
>> All my guards are here too. Like former
pron. Um I got Connor Lou as a center.
Um
>> I love Conor.
>> Chris Bell is an injured guy. So I
wonder like when the injured guys
coming, but he's a second round pick and
I love him to pieces.
>> Here's the Colts. Pat McAfee at 78.
>> Negativity about the Indianapolis Colts.
It's going to take you all right. What
you need to do?
>> How are you? What yall doing after you
crush it up?
>> I just uploaded.
You got you got a sport on Got to do
some films. I got to make some bread. I
got to make up for lost time.
>> THE FUTURE IS THE only deal going. Hey
man, what y'all Malachi feels man? What?
Hey man, how they take him so early,
dog? I thought they would have taken
>> Caleb Douglas was he's not even the best
receiver from his own Reggie
>> Virgil BETTER THAN YOU BUMBERS FANS.
>> Hey man, Chris Brows is about time to
see him too, huh? What y'all think?
>> Ted Hurst. Hurst. I'm a little shocked.
Ted Hurst.
>> I love me some Ted Hurst.
>> The receiver in THE 2026
DRAFT LIVE FROM PITTSBURGH,
PENNSYLVANIA.
>> GOT IT. THE Indianapolis Colts select AJ
Huly DB OUT OF LS.
>> I'm just sitting here tipping picks.
That's all I'm doing. Safety out of LSU.
He's a good player.
>> Safety, man.
>> You were the first one that brought him
up on the draft show, Nick.
>> Yeah, I'm I'm I covered AJ Hollyy back
in the day, so there may have been a
little bit of a um
>> inside trader.
>> H may maybe. No, there's some just some
little bit of bias there. He ended up as
I looked at the safety class, he ended
up as my safety nine, actually, but I
still love him. Uh, I had him in the
third round. Uh, game slows down so much
for him. His IQ is really strong on the
back end. When you talk about brain
works, I see it with this guy. He
anticipates ball action really well
before it arrives. His compact build
makes him an intimidating presence to
have to fight at the catch point or an
open field tackling. I almost wonder how
much slot flexibility he would have with
that build, especially with his
physicality and instincts. I think that
would be a fascinating development for
Indianapolis as they look at shopping
Kenny Moore as maybe like hey AJ Holly
could be the nickel of their future. Uh
who knows? But um tackling will need
significant work and that's probably
where you you uh get worried about the
um about the nickel placement. He had 16
of them in 2025. It was among the
highest in the safety class. But ball
hungry safety who'll thrive in a man
scheme where it's seball get ball or in
his own scheme where he can command a
large large range and bait quarterbacks
in the turnovers. And then my last note
was uh the verified speed is a slight
concern 452. But I I think he plays with
so much downhill hard hat uhness that um
it allows him to uh to to allow more
physicality and and pursuit.
>> Fascinating player, box safety, but he
get picks as a box safety. Fascinating.
We going to keep this thing rolling with
the 79th pick in the 2026 NFL draft. The
Atlanta Falcon select. I guess we going
to keep it red and black.
>> Zachariah Branch.
>> There you go.
>> Do it again. Brian.
>> Gosh. Brian couldn't be more wrong about
that.
>> Did he put a thumbs down?
>> Is that what it was?
>> Something like that.
>> Yeah. Go ahead, Zach.
>> Zach. I mean, you brought up Tyreek Hill
earlier and and I do think Zachariah
Branch has some Tyreek Hill like traits.
I mean, yes, he is a body catcher, but
you also see him in a Florida game go
and snatch a ball with his hands, get
absolutely blasted, get on up and ask
for more. The problem is Pause. Uh, the
problem is with him,
>> say every single play we're about to see
on this, it's going to be a screen or a
slam.
>> Yeah, they they don't they don't run any
routes with him. It's all about just
getting the ball in the face.
>> I felt like that was notable.
>> 100%.
>> Good returner, too, though.
>> Really good returner. I mean, he's just
a playmaker with the ball in his hand.
So, I mean, I think that if you're
looking for somebody that's explosive,
they can win downfield. I I think that
there's untapped potential for him as a
route runner. I don't think it's his
fault. That's just how Georgia decided
to use him. But, I was a big fan of
Zachariah Branch. I think getting him
here is really good value.
>> Got to see him live in person. And I
will say just watching him cuz I had
their game against Mississippi State.
Watching him in person, his acceleration
is as bad as
>> crazy. He's a human joystick element,
though. One thing I will say is he
torched Mississippi State, but I also
pregame thought he looked smaller than I
even could have imagined. I mean, he is
very 5'8, 177 lbs, and that might be
after bulking up a little bit. He is
super small, but they can use him in the
red zone. They can use him in the flats
a little bit. They will use Zachariah
Branch in space. I'm I'm interested to
see the fit there with Atlanta. He
doesn't have to be their number one guy.
He can be a third or fourth option for
them with Drake London and company
already as their primary pass catchers.
I like this fit for for the Falcons and
where they could possibly utilize him.
>> Fellas, I obsessed over this. I don't
think he made one catch over his
shoulder.
>> I looked at all of them.
>> Probably agree.
>> I looked at them all. I think I think he
was facing the quarterback every single
time.
>> He had the second most yards after catch
among power four receivers last year.
642.
>> It's cuz they were all yards after
catch.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Here's the Ravens at 80. Mark Ingram
with the call now. making his money too.
>> Oh boy.
>> Hey, but I LIKE PITTSBURGH. EVERY TIME
I'VE BEEN TO PITTSBURGH AND PLAYED IN
Y'ALL STADIUM, I'M 2 AND 0. OVER 100
YARDS IN THE GAME, two touchdowns.
>> Spot
of Tim Big.
Harold Jackson
>> court stay
>> with the 80 PICK IN THE 2026 NFL DRAFT
BALTIMORE RAVENS SELECT JACOBE LANE WIDE
RECEIVER USC
>> wow
>> that's another big nickel with some
versatility man he can he could play
high he can play strong he can play at
the nipple got some picks got some hands
on the football physical in the run game
man
>> who are you talking about
>> Jacobe
>> Jacob Lane USC wide
>> receiver I'm thinking about our Miami
guy.
>> Jacobe Thomas.
>> I'm thinking about the safety. I'm think
about Jacobe. Yeah. Okay.
>> I was like I realiz Well, I mean I do
think good fluidity for a 6'4 200lb wide
receiver.
>> Big wide receiver, catch radius guy, all
this kind. Pardon me. Pardon me.
>> And there's and there's like one other
Jacobe, too. So, pardon me.
>> We do. We got several Jacobies.
>> Got a lot of Jacob.
>> Jacobe Lane, wide receiver, USC.
>> Red zone target and all that. My fault.
Hey, man. We sleeping, man. I ain't go
to bed, man. My bad, y'all. But Jacobe
Lane, uh, jump ball guy, contested catch
guy, red zone target. I wanted to see
him, you know, run some routes a little
bit better, but I like, man, good
player. I
>> I'll say this. If there's like one
single game that stood out among my wide
receiver study, it was literally this
one against LSU in 2024.
>> He was unbelievable.
>> This was a torch fest. And it made Brian
Kelly like have an in the post game.
Yes.
>> Oh, he went off in this game.
>> Yeah. Brian Kelly, the postame presser.
Yeah. Uh yeah, Jacobe Lane. I like the
big body here. Um and it's funny that
you mentioned the slot before you didn't
realize he he uh
Yeah, he he actually has some slot
versatility. I think you can move him
around on the off on in in an offensive
scheme. I like Jacobe Lane. I do. And I
think in this scheme in Baltimore, it's
going to be quite fascinating. Uh with
Rashad Baitman, Zay Flowers, Devontes
Walker. I wonder how he kind of mixes in
with that uh with that group. But uh
hey, the Cowboys will see him in Rio de
Janeiro, Brazil in week three.
>> They're not going to see him.
>> It's one of the story lines of
>> You don't think you should see in the
field?
>> You're not going to It's all right.
Don't worry about That's one of the
storylines of today. Just to recap for
those that that may be just joining us
for the first time, the Cowboys pick at
92 overall. They're now about 12
selections away as the Jacksonville
Jaguars are on the clock at 81st overall
here in the third round. They haven't
made a pick, but they did make a trade.
They go and get D. Winters, the
linebacker from San Francisco with a
fifth round pick on its way to the
49ers. former TCU Horn Frog and a
starter for 17 games last year for San
Francisco is now a part of the Dallas
Cowboys. So, they haven't made a pick,
but they did use a pick to go get a
linebacker that they anticipate has
starting potential. And then also the
announcement, the Ravens are the week
three opponent for the Cowboys down in
Rio de Janeiro on September 27th. Here
are the Jags at pick 81.
>> Regis, defensive tackle, Texas A&M.
>> Albert Regis, defensive tackle, Texas&M.
>> I didn't love him. catch radius, runs
fast down the field, touchdowns.
>> That's good. I like it.
>> Uh kind of a rundown guy. Takes on
double team, but man, but in the in the
big picture, like you know, Texas&M kind
of guy ran on a bunch. He he looks a lot
bigger than what he is. I think he like
what 290 or something like that.
>> He's wide.
>> Yeah, he's he's wide. You would think
that he's 320 or something like that,
but he knows how to technically deal
with doubles. Uh I think he's either
going to be like a three ter like a big
end type guy. Uh it's interesting cuz
they'll even put him on the edge and let
him rush a little bit. So, like he plays
all over the line of scrimmage, but uh
he doesn't have like one spot that he's
like fantastic at, but uh you know,
interesting dude. I got him in
>> That's why I was a little worried. Like
I don't know where his fit is and
Jacksonville needs to have a really good
plan for him.
>> Four, I would say.
>> Yeah. Is he athletic enough?
>> I don't know. You know,
>> I think he moves really well laterally.
I think he is a solid athlete, but he's
like a rotational type of player.
>> Rotational. Four.
>> Yeah. I just feel like in the third
round it's rich.
>> I just feel like there's better on the
board, but that's just me.
>> Yeah. I got Regis in the fifth. So,
>> hey, here's some Robert Henry film. Um,
>> that's my guy
>> against uh
>> Hey, look. He don't need to be
celebrating nothing against Robin Henry.
Robert Henry put hands and feet on
Robert Henry. Robert, he almost broke
it.
>> Robert Henry put up a buck 77 against
Texas A&M in that game
>> and no,
>> stop it. You don't have to talk about
that one.
>> I actually watch that film live on the
dry show, man. My bad.
>> Yeah, I know you did. I want to hear it.
>> The people that maybe they didn't know.
>> Go mean green. Stop it. The pick is in
for Minnesota at pick 82, which means
the Cowboys are now 10 selections away.
Uh, from their next pick, who are some
of the names that you'd be looking at
here, Tommy? I've got one that I'm I'm
kind of eyeing here, but I want you to
go first.
>> Uh, just best available on my board is
the first one's McCoy for me. Keonte
Scott, Miami, uh, Pon, Oregon. Joshua
Joseph's Tennessee. Keith Abney, Arizona
State. Zaki Wheatley, Penn State. Um,
Kyle Lewis from Pit. That that'll be an
interesting one. Uh, and then, yeah,
Malik Muhammad from Texas, too. That I
think you look at Mohamd as a guy that
if he's still there here in 10 picks,
>> that can probably be a guy that in this
scheme where I think you see some more
press man and aggressiveness at the line
of scrimmage could be pretty good for
what Christian Parker's looking for.
>> Guys, can I put in a call?
>> Yeah, man.
>> Is it Emma Johnson? It's not Emma
Johnson. I like Emma Johnson a lot. The
running back from Nebraska. Are you like
calling your shot or what?
>> Is it Ted
>> Hurst? It's Ted Hurst.
>> I love it.
>> I think if he's there at 92, he's the
pick. I even would think Dallas would
consider trading up to go get a guy like
Ted Hurst.
>> Ted Hurst would be my second receiver
available behind Chris Bell. And Chris
Belly
there, so I get it. I I mean I I love
Ted Hurst. I even said watching him
play, he's got a little Dez Bryant to
his game in my opinion. his ability to
high point the football, make 50-50
catches, really, really good down the
field. What about Chandler Rivers from
Duke?
>> I think it's too small for this team. I
love Chandler Rivers, but I think he's
too small for this team.
>> Gosh, talk about
>> Elijah Sherro maybe. I do. I do, too.
>> Uh, but I mean, would you have Sirat
there?
>> Sure.
>> Please. No, I'm not like that.
>> I I think
>> Skyler Bell, Chris Barzel from Yukon. I
I think we could all separate from uh
opposing DBs better than Elijah Serat.
>> No, that's fair.
>> I I did not love his separation.
>> He does He doesn't have good separation.
>> And you need that at the NFL level.
What' you ask, Zach? I'm sorry.
>> Uh who what did I Oh, Skyler Bell from
Yukon. It's a little bit different from
what you currently have on the roster.
>> I think you can maybe get him in the
fourth.
>> Maybe. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
At one remember when it when it happens
here at 92, it'll be toward the back end
of the third round. But then you've got
three picks tomorrow that Dallas can
kind of maneuver and shake and see what
happens. And they haven't given up the
uh the any of those fourth round picks
yet.
I'm interested if they even say see a
player that's worth going up to get at
this point or if there's enough names on
the list that they feel good just
staying put at 92 and taking all three
of those selections.
>> I think you just wait. I think there's
good enough players to where you can
wait.
>> And honestly, I think there's so many
wide receivers left, I'd rather just
throw another dart at defense right now
and just take a wide receiver later.
Just my personal opinion.
>> What about Denny Sutton from Penn State?
I would love that
>> for another. Yeah. And you kind of need
I mean, if they considered Kendrick
Folk, you didn't really feel that.
>> And if they consider Lawrence stand up
outside, then there's your there's your
four eye.
>> I would say Vikings. I don't know if you
won that. Here's the NFL draft. The
Minnesota Vikings select Dominique
Orange.
>> Oh, there's Big Citrus.
>> Best nickname in the draft.
>> Okay, if you want one of the best
defensive tapes in this entire class,
look at the game that he played in
Ireland against Kansas State in week
zero. It was unreal. It was pouring
buckets of rain in Dublin, Ireland, and
he absolutely dominated uh the Wildcats
Ireland.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Oh, yes. We got the tape.
Thank you, Chris Beam. Look at Look at
Big Citrus just go crazy in this game.
He He goes bananas. Uh that that big
physical frame that he has. Uh does
anyone have a height weight in front of
him uh in front of him? It's
>> It's 62 32 six tall big as hell.
>> Yes, exactly. 300.
>> He threw all that weight around in
Ireland and uh yeah, I I'm I'm a big
fan. He's not as consistent as you would
maybe want and I think there's probably
some conditioning things that play into
that that he would have to, you know,
see through at the NFL level to play
through a 17 game season, but you
actually see him line up in different
spots as you saw in that play right
there. And he can line up uh inside the
tackle and and make some things happen
in in the pass rush as well. Uh I love
Big Citrus. Is he, you know, uh you
know, do I think he's going to wear a
gold jacket one day? Probably not. But I
think he's going to be a lot of fun to
watch develop along the way. I picked
two and 38, 322 lbs, 33 38 inch arms,
and 10 and a quart.
>> Give me all that citrus.
>> He uh he was a Cowboys fit for me. I I
thought he could have been a cowboy.
>> I mean, he can chunk people around.
>> All right, we've got to step aside. When
we come back, Vatcha is going to give us
his best Irish impression uh when we
return. You're listening to the 2026 NFL
draft on the Dallas Cowboys Radio
Network and DallasCowboys.com.
I also like Mason Reagan. All right,
here's Jake Delhomme and the Panthers.
>> Once again, your reigning NFC South
champs
Panthers select Chris Brazzle the
second.
>> That's an interesting pairing him and
Tedoa McMillan in Carolina. That's
actually really fun.
>> Tell you what, I love Chris Brazzle. Um
there were some concerns that popped up
during the process about uh off the-
field stuff and I remember texting Tommy
earlier in the process and I was like I
think I'm going to end up with a first
round grade on Chris Brazzle. Wow.
>> And uh I I ended up backing off of it
just because of the mass concerns about
what the off the field looked like. But
nevertheless, I think if we're talking
about the talent on the field and I know
what you're about to say, Vot, he's a
Tennessee wide receiver and you're
scared about it. I completely get it. I
completely get it. go back and look at
his tape at two lane and uh I I think
you'll see and look at the tape at
Tennessee compare it with each other and
I think you're going to see a player who
actually has a route tree to his game
and it's not just hey uh run down the
field and we can maybe get the ball in
your hands. They had to do a little bit
more with Joey Aguilar this year. And I
I think it actually helped the
development of this Tennessee offense in
the sense of like, okay, Nico Yanava, he
left and they had to figure out the
quarterback situation in a pinch and
they had to play toward Joey Agalar
strengths. And I think that actually
helped put some things, very systematic
things into the Tennessee offense that
they lacked over the course of the last
four or five years. And I think it
helped a guy like Chris Brazzle more
than anyone. So, you see the route tree
from Chris Brazzle, the big frame, the
athletic uh presence to go up and get
the ball, his 50-50s or 8020s. I think
this is going to be one that we look
back on uh in a couple years, and you're
like, damn, how did they come away with
Tedoa McMillan and Chris Brazzle in
back-to-back drafts. This is such a good
target for Bryce Young. It's going to
give him a huge safety net on both
boundaries. I I like Brazil and I'm
going to bet on him 10 times out of 10.
>> He also stepped up against top 25 teams.
25 catches, 402 yards, four touchdowns
against top 25 teams this year. He
played really well in big games. I I
agree with you. I don't think he fits
the mold of your typical Tennessee
receiver. Like the Jaylen Hyatt was one
that burned me. I liked him a lot, but
you can see this guy. He's a willing
blocker. Uh he'll work over the middle
of the field. The burst, the
acceleration, can make plays in space.
I'm a fan. I mean, how many games at
Midland Legacy did did you see him play?
>> Uh three.
>> Yeah, three. They played they they loved
coming to DFW to play DFW competition. I
called one of his games. I think they
played here one time at the start.
>> They did. Um, now one thing I will say
about Chris Brazzle, it's hard for me to
scout the helmet because of Tennessee
and what he did, but let me tell you, he
was doing the same thing he did at
Tennessee at two lane.
>> At two lane,
>> he was doing the exact same thing. He
was flipping people
>> at two lane. So, what was it?
>> It's a great point.
>> No, you're right. And and if that's the
case, I I also put in a comp in the
magazine. I comped him to George
Pickkins. Not the same level. Okay.
>> But same play style in my opinion. He's
a step down. He's just a a junior
version in my opinion.
>> Did you say the same thing about Tain?
>> No.
>> It's all right. It's all right.
It'll happen to all of us.
>> The fan.
>> Continuing on as the Buccaneers pick is
in 84th selection in the 2026 NFL draft.
Some of the recent picks, Zachariah
Branch, wide receiver from Georgia, goes
to the Falcons at 79. Jacobe Lane, wide
receiver USC, goes to the Ravens at 80.
Albert Regis, defensive tackle from
Texas A&M, goes to the Jags at 81. And
then Big Citrus, Dominique Orange, Iowa
State defensive tackle, goes to the
Vikings at 82. Chris Brazzle, wide
receiver from Tennessee, goes to
Carolina at 83. We're just breaking down
Chris Brazzle. Nick made a phenomenal
point about how he was really good at T
Lane before going to Tennessee and you
shouldn't be scared that he's a
Tennessee wide receiver only uh and that
he he's not one of those other Tennessee
wide receivers that have struggled to
make an impact at the next level. The
Buccaneers pick is in Steelers on the
clock and then of course the Cowboys are
coming up here in the next couple of
selections. They've got about 10,
actually less than 10 now until they
pick at 92. Jam McCoy still on the
board. Corner from Tennessee. Keonte
Scott, corner from Miami there. Kyle
Lewis, linebacker from Pit. Emanuel
Pregnon, the Oregon guard, is there. If
you need some offensive line help,
>> could you maybe take a guard? Is that
too much?
>> Can I tell a really quick Brazil story?
>> Sure.
>> It's a hilarious Brazil.
>> I knew he had Is it at two lane or
Tennessee?
>> Uh, it's from his high school days.
>> Okay.
>> So, I used to cover recruiting and um he
uh he was at Milan Legacy. We had a
five-star corner that um I won't mention
the name, but he was going up against a
five-star corner in a game and he played
really well and he DM'd one of our
ranking specialists after the game and
he said, "I'm saying this respectfully,
I promise. At this point, it's overdue.
I'm I'm at least a fourstar. Just played
blank and absolutely estar
the whole game on my sister." They had
to double team coming out of halftime.
had two TDs on this man. One got called
back. Ask about me. He literally
couldn't do nothing with me.
>> Ask about me.
>> That's a first round pick right there.
That's tough, man.
>> The confidence is insane. I love
>> I take it all back.
>> Yeah, sir.
>> Absolutely
's five stars quarter on my on my
system.
>> Guys, this is really cool. Just the
Buccaneers selection. This is Jean
Deckerhoff. He spent 30 plus years as
the playby-play announcer for the Tampa
Bay Buccaneers. Just retired. and he is
the one making the pick for the
Buccaneers.
>> This is really cool. So, I I do want to
hear from Gene Deckerhoff here. He's a
legend in the broadcasting community.
>> Tampa Bay
with the 84th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Tampa Bay Buccaneers,
>> select Ted Hurst,
>> wide receiver.
>> Boom. Cut ballard him far
>> state.
>> What a voice,
>> dude. He's got an incredible
>> Florida. He did Florida State and the
Bucks at the same time and then retired
from Florida State. Finished. I mean, he
was one of our favorites. We do TD
Tuesday. Oh, yeah. During the football
season, Jean would be a weekly staple.
But he would he would speak like that.
It's like boom.
>> And I know they're going to miss him
down in Tampa Bay, but they're not going
to miss Ted Hurst. This guy's awesome.
One of the best mid- major group of five
players in the college football ranks
this past year. He was awesome at the
senior bowl down and and like I said, if
he's there at 92, I think he's the pick
for Dallas.
>> I'm going to use a term from from my
buddy Votch here. Uh he was whooping
feet at the right
>> the entire time. I know that's typically
I know that's typically reserved for
offensive line. He was whooping feet the
entire week. Damn
>> straight he was. He He was unbelievable.
>> Whooping feet.
>> He was whooping feet. You ain't lying
though, Tommy.
>> I didn't have I didn't have the G in
there. I was trying, you know.
>> Don't worry about it.
He was whipping feet.
>> Knock it out, Tommy. Go ahead.
>> No, you go ahead now. Go ahead.
>> N man, Ted Hurst to be a tall receiver,
man. Got some good bend to him. I like
when them wide receivers can bend and
you know, most of the time leggy wide
receivers don't turn that well. I
thought Ted Hurst turned really well,
man. I also thought he was a really good
route runner for his size as well. Uh,
you know, good good yak guy. I had
concerns about the competition, you
know, like we all should. You know, the
the bowl game stuff kind of clean some
up a little bit, but I just wanted to
see more of it. But Tommy, you're right,
dog. He was whipping feet, sir.
>> He's wiping feet.
>> You ain't wrong, dog. I love Tommy,
>> man. I I was trying to give you a shout
out there.
>> I am corrupted.
>> Oh, man.
>> Tommy going to be like, "Hell no,
>> we're going to we're going to make it
happen one way or the other."
>> Say that clip, please.
>> Oh, that was good.
>> Tommy, tell uh actually here's the
Steelers selection at at 85.
>> We're moving pretty quick.
>> Can't get them rolling.
Porter and son. Now here comes Cam
Haylor.
>> Whoopi.
>> Whipping.
>> I got to hear you with this.
>> I don't like y'all, man.
>> Say whip.
Say
>> with the 85th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft.
The sixth time Super Bowl winners,
soon to be seven,
>> the Pittsburgh Steelers select Dalon
Everett.
>> That's a good
>> defensive back.
>> He's a good pick.
>> That's another Oh, good running
character.
>> And if he was there in ' 92, I think
that would be in consideration, too.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> Tell me a little bit about Dalen Ever
here. Georgia corner.
>> Yeah, let me pull up my notes really
quick. I had him uh fairly high CB11. Um
he has the nickel versatility at 611
196. Could very well be a boundary guy
at the next level, but his frame and run
defense knacks uh could make him an
effective nickel as well. Speed is top
tier in the class. He he showed out at
the combine. Could allow him to take
deep routes downfield as a boundary or
stick with the speed demons in the slot.
Uh I would like to see more
explosiveness more in like short area
stuff with his lower body. Uh especially
if he's going to play that nickel spot.
um gave up more than the comfort level
uh in in this range, but I'm banking on
the physical and athletic traits here.
Uh I I think that's really going to pan
out. Bad tape I had Alabama. Good tape I
had Mississippi State and specifically
Mississippi State just because I talk
about those speed demons that he's able
to to play up against. Anthony Evans and
Brennan Thompson for uh Mississippi
State last year. I thought he did a
really good job in that game. Kyle, you
called that game. And here's some tape
from that game. I thought he did a
really good job.
>> I wrote every It's exactly what I want
my corner to look like. good frame,
fantastic change of direction, ability,
still feels wrong in a lot of elements
and has his best football in front of
him.
>> Um, he didn't really work in the slot
too much at Georgia, but he did a little
bit more at the Senior Bowl. He was
telling us that when we were there. Can
he do both?
>> I think only if he improves as a zone
coverage guy, but I still feel like,
like I said, his best is yet to come.
>> Fresh man all day, every day.
>> Yeah, he's got some good patience, too.
And the recovery speed's there.
>> Here's the Browns at 86 pick in the 2026
NFL draft. The Cleveland Browns select
Austin Barber tackle Florida.
>> They traded up to go get this guy, too.
>> They traded a lot to go get this
>> because you lot of tackles.
>> What was the What was the
>> Travis Burke was on board. I would have
liked Travis Burke out of Memphis.
>> I know. I like Travis Burke more, too.
>> I didn't even really love him, but I I
liked him more than Barbara.
>> I like him more than Barbber. I I wanted
to like Barber.
>> This is probably experience. Probably
experience at the power four level. And
Okay. Well,
>> just don't just don't watch him.
>> Wait a minute.
>> Don't watch him. Don't watch him play
Miami. It's just not good.
>> Yeah, that was that was
>> the Miami and looked Miami sound like
that. I want that to be noted. It was
just
>> This is This is V Hayden on me.
>> Huh? What happened?
>> He was whooping.
>> Turned into Stewie Griffin all of a
sudden when I'm talking about whipping
say whipping.
>> I I don't know, guy. I liked Austin
Barber.
>> Talk about he was my second highest
remaining uh offensive tackle so far.
You talk about production, performance,
high level competition. He was crafty
with his hands. His placement was
usually pretty spot-on. I thought I
thought his explosive side off the line
of scrimmage was interesting. Yeah. Oh,
wow. They did give up a lot. Two fourth
round picks and a sixth round pick to
come up here to 86.
>> That's why you're not seeing the Cowboys
trade back into the a trade out.
>> Yeah, that's a high price there. If
that's the the the going rate. I do I do
want to say about Barber, he allowed too
many counter moves against finesse edge
rushers. There were a couple times where
he got beat against Mississippi State,
against Georgia, got stiff there. uh
against power edge rushers, he he didn't
sink his hips enough and anchor, then
that's something you can't really teach.
You either have it or you don't at
different times unless you really get to
uh somebody that that knows what they're
doing at the next level. We'll see if
the the Cleveland Browns can find
something out of that. They're looking
for depth there. He's not at the im
immediate starter. Here's the Dolphins
at 87.
>> Will
I don't know who that is,
>> man. He's the second best off. Hey Nick,
who that is
>> what is wrong with Max Claire?
>> Did I miss Max?
>> This is the best blocking tight end in
the draft perceived by some. And so this
is Miami wanting to get into 12
personnel. I This is wild. We've seen a
couple of these blocking tight ends now
go on day two in the last couple of
years. Like I just don't see the huge
value in that.
>> I think Miami wasting all their good
picks on the
>> miscellaneous stuff.
>> I don't see the huge value.
>> He is nasty though. I mean he he is a
nasty run blocker. I mean, I think he's
a solid tight end, two slash3, but he
just he does not have any ability to
really catch the football.
>> This team got Brevin Span Ford as an
undrafted free agent,
>> you know, and I I think about that a lot
when I think about tight end value. And
sure, should Brevin Spanford have been
drafted? Yes, absolutely. I I think I
had a fourth or a fifth on him that
year.
>> But if you're just going after a guy for
for blocking tape, I don't know. I I
wonder how much uh Jackson Haw Haw or
Daws Jackson Haw I think uh for Buffalo
last year. He was drafted out of Georgia
Tech in the sixth round I believe and he
provided a lot of value for Buffalo in
the run game. James Cook had a really
good year and they really credited that
entire upfront unit, but they include
Jackson Halls in that. Um I uh I wonder
how much that maybe influences teams
around the league. I don't know. That's
just me theorizing about, you know,
wanting to go get these tight ends that
allow you to play in 12 personnel a
little bit more. Miami is really hurting
my spirit because I wanted to keep up
with their draft because their team was
bad. They had a bunch of picks.
>> They're all over the place.
>> And back to back to take Caleb Douglas
and Will, how do you say it last night?
>> Cuz
>> there's no way. Cas just back to back
like that with these with with what I
would consider like 75 and 87 are some
picks that you can do some real stuff
with. And we and we talking about the
guys left on the board. I I don't think
this is a good uh use of resources here
by the Dolphins, but that ain't my team.
Team
>> they've drafted well defensively. He was
my 11th
>> because Rodriguez
>> 11th Johnson. Yeah.
>> 11 tight ends on the board and he was he
was my 11th.
>> I mean he was
>> out of all of them. He was seventh on
Dne's board and he was projected to go
in the early fourth.
>> You want you want me to make you even
sicker about this pick?
>> This was the Dolphins exchange for
Jaylen Phillips in that Jaylen Phillips.
>> Oh.
>> Yeah. I just
>> Oh, that is pretty. That's
>> got a tweet in from Smalls HD. Shout out
to Smalls HD. He He always said
absolutely walloping feet.
>> Walloping. Walloping feet. Come on.
>> Walloping feet. Smalls.
>> Smalls. I thought we were I thought we
were cool, man.
>> No. Not shouts out to Smalls.
>> Walloping feet is hilarious.
I'll give you that.
>> Shouts out.
>> I don't like any of y'all, man.
>> You did.
>> Hey, Cowboys are up here soon. Hi.
Pretty cool.
>> You did quite the number fields. What a
great look at this war room. Yeah. Looks
like some conversations are being had.
>> Brian Shottenheimr's in there. Steven
Jones.
>> We got some good options here. Here
comes Mr. Vaughn back in the building.
Chris Vaughn talking.
>> His feet are engaged in fists.
>> Brian Shottimer.
>> Gurfuffle.
>> Hey, I did use that earlier.
>> Kurfuffle.
>> Uh oh, wait. No, I think what did I say
about the room? We were talking about
the room. This exact shot. Uh I thought
I said a kurfuffle. might have been when
they were reacting after the uh
>> Yeah, I was trying to do playbyplay on
what was happening and they were faking
us out. Who's your best linebacker?
>> Oh man,
>> Kyle Lewis got probably Kyle.
>> Yeah, Lewis and Jimmy Rder.
>> Yeah, Jimmy Rder for me.
>> I love Jimmy. I'm with you, man.
>> LB5.
>> I have Lewis, Betcher, uh Alarmzor,
Elliot. Yeah. And then Walder.
>> I also have Jan Baring York in the
fourth.
>> My bad.
>> No, you're good. You're good. You're
good. If I'm going through my um I I put
out 10 players before the day started um
about guys that I think can make sense
for the Cowboys here.
>> Um the ones that are left, Jaylen
Kilgore, South Carolina DB, TCU
linebacker Caleb Belarms or
>> um Gold Aw. Yeah. And uh and Kentucky
interior offensive lineman Jaylen
Farmer. So those are
>> Farmer's there. I mean there's there's a
couple of good interior linemen.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean Pregnon, something's got to be up
with him.
Sam Heck. Yeah, that could be one of
those.
>> Did you like Connor Lou? I know he's
center specific.
>> I did like Connor Lou. The injury that
injury sucked,
>> but otherwise he could have been the
best center in the draft. I I'm with
you.
>> I still had him as the best. I had Heck
there, but Connor Lou was fighting.
>> Here is the Jacksonville pick at number
88 here in the third round.
>> Jagger Bird is nice, too.
>> Yeah,
>> I've been calling him Joerger. I hope
it's Joerger.
>> It is Joerger.
>> It is.
>> It is. with the 88th pick in the 2026
NFL draft. Jacksonville Jaguars select
Emanuel Pregnon guard.
>> I wonder what happened there.
>> Adam is my 19th best player, so I either
got him super wrong or he was hurt. I
don't know what happened.
>> Out of 44, but still still that's a
slight even from that. I I'm I'm curious
what happened there.
>> Yeah, he goes 88th overall. That's the
same selection Jaylen Tolbert went a
couple years back. I mean, he's good
poll. He's at the back end of uh of the
third round for the Jacksonville
Jaguars. We're going to step aside
because the Cowboys are now five
selections away at 92 overall. We are
coming up on their one selection here on
day two of the 2026 NFL draft on the
Dallas Cowboys radio network and
DallasCowboys.com.
All right, tell me a little bit about
Emanuel Pregnon there from Oregon,
offensive guard. He does have heavy
feet. I mean, I'll say that, but he
plays with power. I mean, he he's
>> Is that enough to make slide, though?
>> No, I don't think so. I mean, I think
maybe there's a medical reason. There's
got to be something. I mean, the grip
strength is there. He can maintain
blocks. He can be dominant in the run
game. Mer type of play temperament that
can drive defenders off the football.
The anchor's there. He can quickly pass
off stunts. I like the hands, the
strike. I mean, to me, I I I was really
a big fan of his, but something's got to
be up to why he fell this far.
>> Yeah. Plays with a really good base,
too, and decent knee bend to be that,
you know, few months
>> for how big he is.
>> It's the Bears, 49ers, Raiders, Cowboys
all on the clock here as we get into the
back half of the third round. Here's
Chicago at 89. Thank you, Tommy.
>> You're welcome.
Okay, Chicago
>> Jimbo Covert
>> with the 89th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Chicago Bears select Xavian
Thomas, wide receiver, LSU.
>> Xavon Thomas goes
>> fast.
>> Yeah, a couple of wide fast.
>> Yeah, really fast.
>> Is that is that all all that's there?
big return guy. I mean, I I think he is
a good character. This is a little early
for him.
>> Special team is really early.
>> I thought these wide receivers are
running early.
>> Yeah,
>> I thought there were better small route
running. Well, not like small bursty
dudes is is I I thought it was better
guys.
>> If that's what they would have wanted, I
think Brennan Thompson's your guy here.
>> Agreed with that, too. State.
>> Yeah.
>> But yeah, Xavon Thomas 510, 38, 190, 30
and a half inch arms and 9 in hands.
>> He just feels like a gadget kind of
player.
>> Gadgety dude. Yeah. They were better
small guys for sure.
>> What are we thinking? Malik Muhammad.
>> I'm thinking team suck at drafting dog
and people and people like to look at me
and be like, "V so Eric saying that."
>> Players that they definitely seem to
have interest in. They were at a EMTT
Johnson proday. I don't know how long
you can wait. I'm surprised that no
running backs have gone. Mike Washington
Jr. from Arkansas. If you want to go
with the runner,
>> do you wait on the run since you have
three picks early in the fourth?
>> Kind of and just kind of wait.
>> Maybe one of those guys will slide to
you. I mean, Germa McCoy, this would be
very Seone Revelike. be a fantastic time
to just pick up the phone for Jama.
>> I just if you think he can come back
from the knee, it's worth it.
>> So, it wasn't ACL. It's a a a procedure
thing that happened to him or something.
I don't want to speak on it. I don't
really know.
>> It's the way it's healed.
>> Yeah.
>> But it's a whole ordeal.
>> They got to pull out a screw.
>> So, it's something with that Oats
procedure that OATS.
>> It's very similar to like the condr
defect that we've seen. I don't know
what that is.
>> Oh, wow. You're It's like a cartilage
situation. That's not good. I bet it is.
Here's Niners.
>> 49ers selection at 90.
It's Kaylin Black, the running back from
Indiana. Fascinating.
>> I'm surprised you went over some of
these other guys.
>> That's fascinating.
>> That's a Niners pick, though.
>> Yeah.
>> What was going on, though?
>> Welcome back in to our 2026 NFL draft
coverage. Cowboys fans, while the team
is making big picks, make the smart pick
at home. Call On Time Experts, the
official AC, heating, and plumbing
partner of the Dallas Cowboys. Fast,
reliable, always on time. That's on time
experts. Visit ontimeexperts.com
and clickbook. Now, we are just closing
in on the Cowboys selection at 92
overall. Caitlyn Black, the running back
out of Indiana, goes 90th overall to San
Francisco. A fascinating pick, as Vot
Lombardi calls it. Kyle, I thought he
was a cool one cut contact balance try
to finish you run guy, but man, I got
Johnson, Coleman, Washington, Clayborn,
Singleton, Taylor, Moss, Allen, Henry,
McGawan, all kind of better than him.
So, shouts out to San Francisco, man.
>> Kind of been a weird day, too, in terms
of reaches.
>> San Francisco would draft a dude like a
like they would draft a running back
high, but the running back that they
draft late is better than them.
>> So, they may have, you know, like like
Keelen Black may be like fantastic. We
just don't know. They might think he can
just he can fit the scheme, you know,
like and you mentioned the one cut and
go, that kind of zone Shanahan scheme.
He can work there. The juke, the cuts
are there, contact, if it's blocked up,
he's going to get it, you know. I don't
know that he's a differencem type of
back,
>> but solid play. I mean, I I'm surprised
that he went ahead of some of these
other running backs that are still on
the board.
>> I just consider like we're in the we're
in the portion of the third round where
like it's still a ton of value on the
board and the last few picks have just
been puzzling. I'm a Cowboys fan so I
don't particularly care. Mhm.
>> Knock yourself out. Take all these dudes
that I thought was going to go six,
seven undrafted. Like, you know, do your
thing. But just some of the names on the
board, who they picked over some of the
names that I have available still is
just kind of interesting.
>> I tell you what, if the draft keeps
going this way for Dallas,
>> I feel good, Tommy.
>> Three, fourth round picks.
>> I feel great.
>> You're going to have some eyes there.
>> In your mind, Tom, right?
>> This is Yeah, this has been really
surprising.
>> All right, so the Raiders pick is in
here at 91. That means the Cowboys are
officially on the clock for the first
time here on day two. who they did send
a fifth round pick to the San Francisco
49ers for a linebacker uh bringing in
and bringing home a linebacker former uh
TCU product as a possible starter uh
moving forward at the second level. If
that's the case, maybe takes him out of
a conversation here for a linebacker
Brian Shottimer making a point here. Do
you feel like there's any chance this is
an offensive player or are they sticking
defense for the majority of the draft?
>> Very well could be. uh you think wide
receiver, you think tackle. Um you know,
those would be the two that that come to
mind for me uh based on how the rest of
the the board has fallen because you
know, some of these wide receivers that
have gone uh maybe a little bit
different some of the other guys. Looks
like we've got a pick here, guys.
>> Yeah, Will Mlay is on the phone and they
make a selection. That was pretty quick.
Uh they had a long time to think about
it. 60 selections rolling off on day two
before they they get to the 92nd pick
here in the draft.
>> Stephen is giddy.
>> Is he?
>> Stephen looks pretty pumped right now.
>> He is red in the face. Excited about it.
We'll see exactly who that pick is if
that
ends up being an offensive player,
defensive player. We will see. We're
looking for possible
coaching staff working their way in.
>> Some of the scouting department working.
I mean, there's a lot of good corners if
that's the route that they wanted to go
here. Um, at wide receiver, you do have
some solid options. I I think offensive
lineman, there's some decent linemen
that we've talked about as well, but I
mean, I didn't expect Keith Abney out of
Arizona State, Malik Mohamd from Texas.
I didn't expect Keonte Scott from Miami,
any of those guys to still be, Even
Chris Bell with the injury. I I still
think that's a lot of good receivers.
Parker making the rounds there again.
>> Okay.
>> Your defense was terrible. I would love
it if the Cowboys like threw like just
keep throwing darts at defense. And
there's a bunch of names that I like. Uh
Keith Abney, the corner, uh you know,
Wheatly the safety, Max, Max Llewellyn,
the pass rush, I like him a lot. Harold
Harold Harold Perkins lowkey, I would
love to see how Christian Parker could
be creative and use him.
>> Um so offense could be an option, but
man, let's wait till to the fourth round
and let's see what happens here.
Shotti's about to pass the phone to
let's see let's see she if he pass the
parking then we'll know
>> Clayton Adams probably just at the crib
or on vacation or something
>> like you know what guys take care of
what you need
>> I haven't seen Clayton Adams in a while
it's fine
>> yeah he's been
>> this ain't your draft player
>> here's Christian Park
>> Park gets the phone so
>> defensive player looks like
>> there you go I wonder if it's one of
these corners here's the Raiders
selection in 91 Muhammad would make a
lot of sense here
>> yeah it
Raider selection in 91.
Waiting on the audio.
>> They've done a phenomenal job.
>> Certainly have.
>> With the 91st pick of the 2026 NFL
draft, the Las Vegas Raiders select Trey
Zoom. Thei guard Texas A&M.
>> That's a fun pick out of College
Station. Texas A&M Agies well
represented in the first two rounds of
the draft. They did hand the phone to
Christian Parker. So, we're thinking
defensive player here. Who are some of
the top defensive players on your board,
Zack?
>> It's all those corners really that I
listed. I mean, if it's not Jam McCoy, I
love Chandler Rivers from Duke. I mean,
Nick saying he's too small. That that
stinks. But I I get it. Scott from
Miami, Zaki Wheatley from Penn State.
Malik Muhamd's in that conversation from
Texas. Kyle Lewis, the linebacker from
Pit is a guy that I like a lot. Uh
Jaylen Kilgore from South Carolina. Is
that a little redundant since you just
took Caleb DS? That very well could be.
And then I mentioned Denise Sutton, the
edge from Penn State earlier, who could
probably put his hand on the ground,
play some fore you.
>> Another player that we haven't talked
about that I love his versatility is
Baram from Michigan. Jason
>> played linebacker, played edge. There's
a lot that you could do with in terms of
him being multiple. So, I mean, you got
a I mean, at linebacker, Ralder, Red
Murdoch from Buffalo,
>> Red Murdoch,
>> all these guys are I I'd be happy if
they took any of them.
>> Daryl Jackson Jr., the defensive lineman
from Florida State. Think he can play up
and down the line.
>> I just love that we're continuously
throwing darts at defense. Let's just
let's just figure it out.
>> All right, here's the pick. Drew Pearson
on his way to the podium. Tony Dorset
theaters, man. We got out there too
wearing the pit hat.
>> And here's Drew Pearson who lit up
Philadelphia in the Commonwealth a few
years ago. Here we go.
>> And this is their first pick since last
night.
All right.
>> Here's Drew Pearson.
>> How about them Steelers?
>> All right.
with the 92nd pick in the 2026 NFL
draft.
>> 2026 NFL draft, the Dallas Cowboys
select Shaquin Barber,
>> Jan Barham
for Michigan. Here we go. Boom, baby.
>> Edge rusher from Michigan.
>> I like this. You're here.
>> Two edge rushers already in the draft
out of the first three picks. They take
Malachi Lawrence yesterday, 23rd
overall, and then here at 92, they go
and get Borrow.
>> I I will give you a breakdown in real
time of me watching his film. 2025, I
see him on the edge pass rushing, very
explosive, flying off the football,
beating guys early in the reps. I'm
like, "Hey man, we got another pass rush
for Michigan." Cowboy fans ain't going
they're not going to like it. But I
really like what we're seeing so far.
And I'm just seeing winning early,
winning easy. But I'm kind of seeing
them look a little raw. I'm seeing them
running down the middle of people. So in
my mind I'm like, okay, it doesn't look
like he's been pass rush for a long
time. So I go to his last year's film,
he's just off ball linebacker all day.
Then I go back to 2025 Ohio State, he's
off ball linebacker all day. So I said,
"Oh, we got versatility in the
building." So I thought he was much
better as a off the- ball linebacker. So
now we talk about Christian Parker in
this defense, creativity, moving guys
around, mixing up the defense. You have
a player now you missed out on on Ree
and that's cool that you missed out on
RVL Reese, but you have a player that
has offball experience and he is a
growing pass rusher. He's a guy that can
win as a pass rusher right now, but a
lot more room to grow. Shouts out to the
Cowboys. Great pick.
>> Yeah, this is one where Christian Parker
can can kind of have fun with it in the
sense of you're going to decide a lot of
different ways where you want to play
him. He can play inside, he can play
outside. You're watching some of the
tape here where he's lining up in the
middle of the field like a middle
linebacker and coming down and making
plays against the run. But like Voch
said, this is a a guy, too, that
Michigan put on the outside and had Rush
the passer almost like an outside
linebacker. So versatility is a big one
here. Versatility, I think, is really
the name of the game when you think
about a lot of the guys that Dallas has
brought in so far in free agency and
here through the draft, too. Barham fits
that bill. Uh 63, 240 lbs, 32 and 38
inch arms, 10 and a/4 inch hands. Uh
there's going to be a lot of room for
growth for him and and now it's just a
question of whether or not it fits in
the scheme.
>> Super fun player. transferred from
Maryland. He started 23 games over two
years at linebacker, but the versatility
is there because you mentioned him
moving over to edge, 10 tackles for
loss. His blitzing ability is
incredible. The closing speed, the
timing, the aggression in which he plays
with, he is a guy that is a little bit
light as an edge, but I mean his
versatility, his ability to freelance.
You can play him off ball, makes tackles
in space. He covers ground so quickly.
He is a havoc type of player and they
have lacked guys that can be difference
makers and be disruptive. That is what
he is. Very smart player that looks like
he plays with natural instincts. He's
got some pop to him. I I I He was one of
the guys that I put in here could be a
steal in this draft and I think
Christian Parker is the perfect coach to
be able to use him to his strengths as a
chess piece.
>> Now I understand Cowboy fans, hey V, it
it sure does sound like you're hyping
him up a little bit. Hey, y'all can go
find my board. He's 70 on my board. So
to be able to get him here at 90 uh 92,
I think is fantastic value here.
>> Yeah, I I think this is right around
where he should go. I had him in the top
half of the fourth round there. It's not
perfect stuff, but it is stuff that you
can kind of mold into it. I thought one
of the things he he did have was uh he
attacks before really seeing what's
going on. Kind of overpursues at time.
He does adjust well. He just made a nice
play against Oklahoma on the film that
we're looking at here. But when when you
look at a guy like the the traits that
we saw from Malachi Lawrence yesterday,
this is kind of not that power length
guy. This is more of a speed get around
the edge sort of player. It's kind of a
a compliment to Lawrence per se. I I
like the selection. It gives you some
more position flex and versatility. He
was a 30 visit for Dallas. They loved
the interviews whenever he came in here
as well. He was one of the the I thought
it would maybe be early day three, but
if you don't think he's going to fall to
early day three, take your pick at day
four or in day two and make it happen.
>> That clip that you just saw of him
running east to west to chase down
number six from Oklahoma, that's Tory
Bllelock, one of the fastest players in
the country. He's he's a real real deal
track guy and he he was able to run with
him stride for stride moving east to
west. So that tells you what kind of a
player he is being able to move all
around the field and you know pass rush
obviously that quick first step he can
turn the corner but if he does move
inside and play some kind of linebacker
role he can move around pretty well for
you. Now it's just a matter of rounding
it out and kind of time on task on one
area versus another.
>> So once upon a time with the number 92
overall pick the Dallas Cowboys selected
another player out of Michigan, Jordan
Lewis.
>> Talk to him.
>> That worked out pretty well.
>> Yeah, it sure did. What what do you say
about the the fans that are probably on
social media right now saying Michigan
>> they're yelling at the sun.
>> It's they'll be fine.
>> It's it's just that right.
>> I tell you what and I love Wink
Martindelle so much and I think what
Wink Martindale has done for this
defensive unit in the last couple of
years has been so strong and we've seen
these guys be more NFL ready. Um I love
Jan I love Jan Barum and I love what
this Michigan defense has turned into in
the last couple of years.
>> Heck Raawn Benny is another player that
I like. I I liked Jon Barum's run
defense a little bit more than pass
rush. Am I weird to think that? I liked
his run stuff a little bit more. I think
his edge setting was strong. Uh I do
think he has pass rush to him, but I I I
would prefer him on early down.
>> I like him more as a blitzer than I do
as a as a pass rusher.
>> Like I can say a pass rusher, he has to
win early. Like if he gets caught up in
something, he has to learn how to, you
know, pull out a counter or second,
third move or something like that. But
as far as just athleticism, just winning
off the ball early, like that's what
he's good at. Uh, but hey, growth and
development. We're in the third round at
this point. Uh, I can see him being a
guy like doing something for you. I
don't know what starting role looks
like, but hey, coming past rush on third
down, mix up the look. Whether he's
rushing off the edges or just blitzing
an A- gap, I can see him doing something
creatively.
>> And it's the confusion aspect of it,
right? We're like, you don't know where
he's going to come from. Is he going to
back up? Is he going to drop in
coverage? He's clearly clearly
comfortable doing there. There there's a
lot that you can do with him.
and and kind of like what you were
talking about a couple moments prior to
this, the
the way that the board is shaking out
going into round four. They're in a
premium spot to take some really high
level players.
>> Yeah. I mean, there are top 100 players
on all of our boards, I believe, that
are still available going into day
three, and they've got three shots at it
in the fourth round if they intend to
keep those three shots at it. All right.
After the uh the Cowboys picked at 92,
Jan Barum, edge rusher from Michigan,
who we'll hear from in just a little
bit, the Rams took Keegan Trust, the
offensive tackle from Missouri. And then
the Dolphins at 94, just took wide
receiver Chris Bell out of Louisville.
Highest rated wide receiver on my board
remaining. And some really good players
flying off here. As the Cowboys war room
settles in, might be done here for uh
day three. Do you think there's a
possibility they trade back into the
third if they have a guy?
>> No.
>> I think there's too many players. You
just kind of let this thing fall. I'm
just
>> just throwing the question.
>> See y'all tomorrow.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Hey, I got one more for you.
>> We got another tweet in.
>> What say
>> my good gentleman? That athletic
individual is absolutely trouncing
tootsies.
>> Trouncing tootsies.
>> TROUNCING TOOTSIES IS CRAZY.
>> Shots and titties. Trouts and tootsies.
>> Here. Here. What' you say?
>> Where are you guys going? Bro,
>> I'm out.
>> Yeah.
>> To the the end of the draft. We're not
going to break yet.
>> Oh, I thought we were in break.
>> No, we're excuse me. Excuse me. Sorry.
>> Unfortunately, man, what's wrong with D
people, man?
>> I'm out.
>> I know.
>> Oh, man. Actually, you know what? It is
about time to go to a break. Let's go to
a break. All right. You're continuing.
We're continuing our coverage. We are
going to have the press conference
coming up in a little bit, but that
that's going to do it for us on the
radio side of things. We're done on
1053, The Fan. We'll catch you tomorrow,
10:00 a.m. Central time on the Fan. Uh
if you want to join us early before the
draft gets started. It's the best hour
of radio I say we do all year long.
We're going to get to talk to the
scouts, coaching staff, and some of the
decision makers out of the Cowboys war
room. We'll have the opportunity uh to
talk to them for a little bit. Zach,
kind of run down what we've done in the
past in terms of those interviews. It's
just a a valuable time of radio.
>> No, it's amazing. You get your position
coaches will come in here. You got to
talk to an offensive line coach for
instance, whether it's Connor Riley like
we got to talk with last year. We got
Steve Shimco who was big in taking Don
Azeraku a year ago. And then of course
the scouts, you know, the guys that
maybe you don't get to hear from,
whether it's a Ross Winy, a Mitch Leo
point, a Justin Stucky, these guys that
are really out there putting a ton of
work and time in, taking time away from
their family, the really the backbone of
the organization. And you get to kind of
hear what they do, what they saw in
these players, how they fit. It really
is. I think it's some of the best
information that you're going to get all
year long.
>> Bobby, it's also an opportunity, like
Zach just said, for some of the scouts
and individuals to to really put their
spin on the decisions that were made in
the early rounds. And I think outside of
the the the scouting that we're going to
hear from different regions, it's going
to be interesting to hear about the
decision-m process that went into the
war room.
>> Yeah, it's the if you're a fan who who
really wants to go ahead.
>> Sorry, we have uh the newest cowboy on
the line. Oh, let's party.
>> Let's talk to Jan Bar before we go to
break on the fan real quickly. Jan,
congratulations on this moment. Welcome
to Dallas. What's going through your
head right now?
>> Uh, no, I'm feeling excited. Uh, I feel
like I had a good good top 30 visit with
him. Uh, my mother a big fan, so I feel
like this was just it was meant to be
almost.
>> That's true. You are a local product in
that. But what's it mean to be drafted
by the the Cowboys in this moment?
What's going through your head?
I don't know. I think it feel great, but
it's going through my head. I'm ready to
work. So, I can't wait to get out there,
put the pads on, and start practicing.
>> Jan, congrats. Congrats. When you were
meeting with uh Dallas and the coaches
on defense, did they think of you as
more of a edge guy or more as offball
linebacker, 50-50 split? What do you
think?
>> Uh, we talked about both to be honest. I
got to meet with the outside backer
coach and inside back coach just just to
talk ball and see how I see stuff. uh
going over my inside backer tape and
outside backer state. Uh but to me, I
think they see me as like a guy that can
play both.
>> We have Jan Bur on the line, newest
Dallas Cowboy with the pick at 92. We
have to say goodbye to our listeners on
1053. The fan, we'll continue on on
dallascowboys.com. If you're watching on
the stream, it'll be uninterrupted. Be
sure to join us. DallasCowboys.com.
We'll see you tomorrow, 10 a.m. Central
time on the DallasCowboys Radio Network
and on DallasCowboys.com.
All right, Jan, you're still there,
right?
>> Yes, sir, man.
>> All right, so I just want to make sure
we're going to continue the interview
here. Appreciate you sticking around.
This is a a a draft where Dallas has
been defensive heavy already. How much
do you know about what you're coming
into and the situation that's at hand
here in Dallas?
>> I mean, I pretty much know what I'm
coming into. I seen that guy with Sean
Gary, uh, Malikai Lawrence in this
draft. So, uh, I feel like this is going
to be a deep deep room and it's going to
be fun.
>> J Sean, congratulations on getting
drafted. Excited to have you here. I'm
curious, you know, there's obviously a
lot of talk about what you're able to
do, you know, physically on the football
field, but there there's also a lot of
talk whenever people mention you about
just your motor and your intensity and
your play style. How important is that
aspect of your game just to, you know,
the relentless pursuit and that motor
running hot?
>> I mean, I feel like that's that's a
great thing because that's really
something you can't coach. So, I feel
like stuff like that, like your motor
and your pursuit to the ball and just
your want, I feel like that's something
that every coach want and need on their
team. So, I feel like that's that's
great.
>> Yeah. I I've described you as a havoc
type of player. How would you describe
yourself as a football player for Cowboy
fans that haven't been able to watch you
yet?
>> Oh, yeah. I like that word. I mean, I'm
trying to I'm trying to blow stuff up.
Uh cause havoc, like you say, and I'm
trying to cause problems for the
offense.
>> J Sean, is it uh is it going to be tough
at all to share your rookie class with
an Ohio State Buckeye?
No, I don't think so. We can make
homework. It's probably going to be a
little trash talk, but it's all right.
>> That's the best answer you could have
given. I love that. We got the chance to
meet Caleb DS today. We're going to get
a chance to meet you very, very soon.
What would you say Cowboys fans are
getting off the field with with J Sean?
>> I mean, I feel like they got a guy
that's not going to get any trouble. Uh
that's going to lead by the right way on
and off the field pretty much. Uh I'mma
represent that start the right way. What
are some of the things you like to do?
Uh
>> me, I like to watch movies. Uh hang with
my family. Uh just that's probably the
most popular, but I'm a TV show guy. I
like to be in the house, watch shows,
movies with my family, stuff like that.
>> All right. What show are you watching
right now?
>> Uh I just finished Peeky Blinders. You
seen that?
>> Nice. That's a good one.
>> Were you able to watch it without
subtitles? Could you understand all
their accents?
>> Yeah. Yeah. It took me a little like for
the first few episodes. I had I had to
fill them out. at the year. Yeah, I had
a f first few episodes, but we got
there.
>> Hey, he got there. That's
>> I never did. I never did.
>> That's what he's trying to do here. I
can't wait. How was the the process
leading up to this point in talking with
Christian Parker? Uh who were some of
the the individuals that really uh had
their uh their eyes on you on the
Cowboys side?
>> I mean, for sure, Coach Parker, I mean,
definitely when I first got to meet him,
it was like it was like we kind of had a
kind of had a match already because we
knew a lot of the same guys coming up.
uh he's from the Virginia area. So I
feel like it was kind of almost a
connection and he got me on the board
and I feel like that kind of that kind
of helped him with me. Just me getting
on the board, drawing up a play that
they showed me earlier and just me being
able to recite that and remember that
play. I feel like that kind of grew with
him too. So I feel like that was a good
connection.
>> Jan, this off season just as a pass
rusher, like what's uh what's something
you uh feel like you can work on? Was it
hands? Was it counters? Was it uh
putting moves together? What's something
that you really feel like you wanted to
focus on this off seasonason as a
rusher?
>> Uh to me, I think it's my counters.
>> Yeah,
>> I think I can work on my counters more
just when I get to the top of the rest,
go back or just working on different
moves, just perfecting my craft. I'm not
perfect, so I feel like it's still a lot
I can work on and get better at.
>> Hey man, shouts out to you, bro. You win
early. I was a big fan of watching you,
man. You was whooping up on everybody.
You know what I'm saying? I just saw you
as a as a pass rusher at first and then
I just watched the Oklahoma film. I was
like, "Oh boy, he's a off ball
linebacker." The whole game just at the
drop of a dime. Hey Jan, this week
you're off the ball linebacker. I
thought that was fantastic, bro. So,
shouts out to you, man. Glad to have you
here.
>> Yes, sir.
>> There he goes. J Sean, appreciate you.
Thank you for taking some time. We'll
talk to you down the line.
>> Appreciate it.
>> And Jan Baram, 92nd overall pick by your
Dallas Cowboys in the 2026 NFL draft.
Thanks for sticking around with us,
dallascowboys.com. for those that joined
us on the fan side of things and then
flipped over to dallascowboys.com. I
know it was kind of confusing there for
a moment, but with the radio heart out,
we got to get out at a certain time, but
we're going to continue our coverage
until the end of the press conference
here in a couple of moments. All right,
the the first two-day hall is done. I'm
going to catch you up on some of the
picks that's happened over the last few
moments. Uh Dolphins take Chris Bell,
wide receiver from Louisville. Patriots
take Eli Ren, the tight end from Notre
Dame. Seahawks with a good pick, man. At
96, Jennings Dunker.
>> Yeah.
>> Interior offensive lineman, guard from
Iowa. Played tackle at Iowa. Probably
going to move inside to guard. It seems
like he's a really stout player. Vikings
are on the clock. Their pick is in. They
picked twice in a row actually. Uh so
the pick is in for the Vikings and then
they're on the clock again, followed by
the Seahawks and the Jags to round out
day two. Cowboys with Caleb DS, Malachi
Lawrence, Jan Barum. What do you think
about the Hall so far for Dallas?
>> Yeah, and I mean, you also got to
remember they went out and got a
veteran, too. Winter.
>> Yeah. I mean, they've they've addressed
a lot. I'm I'm going to be interested. I
know he said they talked about both. Uh
I'm going to be interested to see if
they view him more as pure edge rusher
or if he's off the ball linebacker.
>> Because I know there's a lot of team
there's a lot of teams that viewed Barum
differently. There there teams who
thought like, hey, we can have him do a
lot of different things. Other teams
felt like he's going to be, you know, an
offball linebacker for us. Others who
said, "Nope, he's coming off the edge."
So, I I think that there's I'll be
interested to see how they look at it.
>> Here's the Viking selection in 97.
>> Caleb Tio, Northwestern offensive
tackle. Brian Bratis is back in the
building. What's up, Brian?
>> Hey. Hey. Uh, what do you think about
Jan Barum?
>> I tell you what, I I know that uh it's
funny because uh at Crown Global, we
were doing we were studying him. Vajai,
Aisha, this was one of these guys when
Zach and I played a game where we said
if you could have you can't have this
guy but you can have this guy and Barum
was one of those guys that we were we
were like every time in Lake V I heard
him you guys talking about him you watch
the tape and you're thinking like okay
this game they've got him doing this
then the other game they've got him
doing this and you're thinking like oh
wow this is probably a pretty smart guy
and and Wink Martindale former pro coach
the way he is the way he uses is his
players. I was thinking like, gosh dang.
Okay, here's one of those guys we talk
about weapons, you know, with with you
know, when you when you you look at uh
you know, your first overall pick and
then the way that that he was able to
kind of a weapon and then bar here's
another weapon guys that you can use
them in a lot of different roles, but I
was impressed with the way he's able to
close the burst, the way he's able to
finish. I mean, he plays with some
violence, too, when you watch him
tackle. Very physical player.
>> Jacobe Thomas is the second pick by
Minnesota.
>> That's the Jacobe I was thinking.
>> I'm surprised he went over
>> good wide receiver. What was it? What
were you talking about there?
>> I don't know. We just dreaded Jan Barn.
Nobody care about Jacob Thomas. What's
wrong with y'all? This Dallas Cowboys.
>> Yeah, you're right. You're right. Uh a
good play. You like this guy though.
>> I like Thomas safety. Nickel could play
on the roof. uh can play down in the uh
in the box at nickel. Got his hands on a
lot of footballs, picks and all that
kind of stuff. Uh active in the run game
and stuff. I like Jacob Blitzer. Really
good Blizzard, too. He got like like
like three sacks. So, shouts out to him.
>> Uh speaking of, you talked about we just
drafted Jan Barum, right? We just talked
to Jan Barum. Let's get that.
>> What's that one thing we got to listen
to?
>> The Secret Audio.
>> Oh, yeah. Let's hear it. Secret audio.
Jan Barum, 92nd overall.
>> This is Jerry Jones with the Cowboys.
And as of this minute, you are a Dallas
Cowboy.
>> Yes, sir. Let's do it. Ready to work.
>> Excited about you. Uh really are and had
uh been waiting you out. We've been
trying to uh get you down there to us
for a long time. And u so I'm going to
add you to the coach, but you're now a
Dallas Cowboy.
>> Appreciate it.
>> All right. Here's your coach,
>> J Sean. Coach Shot and Hammer, man.
>> What's good?
>> Hey, I love that, man. You excited?
>> Yeah.
Man, we are fired up. But you're a
Dallas Cowboy. Can you believe it?
>> Oh, yes, sir. I can't wait.
>> Hey, we've been we've been watching this
board for the last couple hours, man.
And uh you were a guy. We're hoping we
could find a way to get on the team,
man. And uh we uh can't wait to get you
in here and just have you wreak havoc
the way you do.
>> Yes, sir. I can't wait to do it.
>> Yeah, congratulations. Couple people
want to talk to you real quick. Hey, uh
CP.
>> Hold on one second. Here comes our
defensive coordinator, Christian Parker.
Congrats again. All right, hold on one
second.
>> Yep. Here he is. Here's Christian
Parker. Jan, hello.
>> Yes, sir. I can hear you.
>> You hear me? How you doing, man?
>> Yes, sir. I'm good. How are you?
>> I'm good, bro. How you feeling?
>> I feel great.
>> Yeah, man. Look, we, you know, we had a
great visit with you and, you know,
having you in the building and spending
that time with you,
>> you know, you're you're all right type
of guy. You know, that edge you play
with and everything else,
>> you going to make us better and uh, you
know, sir, best is yet to come for for
you and your career. You know what I'm
saying?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Get you here in this building and get
ready to work.
>> I can't wait. Let's do it. Yeah. That
was work. It's time now,
>> man. Christian Parker, what a man.
>> What a week he's had.
>> Chill. Cool.
>> Let's get to business.
>> Far away.
>> Yeah.
>> They said they said do whatever you need
as here's the Jags. The final pick of
the third round and day two pick number
100 of the draft.
>> Final pick in the third round with the
Hunter pick in 2026 NFL draft. The
Jacksonville Jaguars select Jaylen
Husky, defensive back from Maryland.
Yeah.
>> Right before that, by the way, the
Seahawks at 99 take Julian Neil, corner
from Arkansas.
>> Yeah.
>> So, that rounds out the second day of
the 2026 NFL draft. I'm going to give
you the last five picks starting with
the Seahawks at 96. Jennings Dunker,
offensive guard from Iowa. Vikings, it's
97. Take Caleb Tieran, offensive tackle
from Northwestern. They pick again. The
Vikings do. Jacobe Thomas, safety from
Miami. Julian Neil, corner from
Arkansas, goes to the Seahawks at 99.
And then Jaylen Husky, the safety from
Maryland. Couple defensive backs in that
last three picks uh of the second round.
So the Cowboys have to wait till 112,
114, 137 tomorrow. Three fourth round
picks as the second day comes to a close
in Pittsburgh. What do you guys think
about the the draft as a whole so far?
any big surprises that are still on your
board as we await the the press
conference that'll come up in a couple
of minutes.
>> Yeah, man. We got to find out about
Wheatley and ABNE. Those are those are
guys that I have in my uh second round.
Also, uh Connor Lou, Jaylen Jaylen
Farmer. I thought Jennings Dunker would
be gone by now. I thought, you know,
>> he was he is he got he just got heck
Steelers got him.
>> Cool. Also, my uh
>> they traded up from Seattle.
>> Also, my running backs are just kind of
like sitting around.
>> That's very surprising to me. I mean,
Keonte Scott not going, Chandler Rivers
still being there. I thought he was much
better than I guess the rest of the
league did. Wheatly to your point, but
the runners, I mean, you still have Kyle
Lewis, that's not exactly a huge
surprise just based on his size, I
suppose. But the fact that you didn't
have EMTT Johnson go today, Mike
Washington Jr. from Arkansas. That that
was a bit surprising to me. I thought
you get a little bit of a run on the
runners uh and and Kalon Black going
over some of those guys from Indiana. So
that's uh but hey, you still got some
good interior linemen. There's still
some really good wide receivers that are
there. And Malik Muhammad is still
sitting there, the quarterback from
Texas.
>> Uh I I I don't know that it's totally
odd because I think the guys that stand
out uh guys like you were just talking
about Kee Scott, Kyle Lewis, um even
Chandler Rivers. They're all those guys
that the league is I think telling you
like I don't know what to do with him.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't I like I don't know what to do
with Kanti Scott. I I don't know how I
want to play him necessarily. Like maybe
I like the player Kyle Lewis. I like the
player. I I don't know if I can work his
size at like like is he
>> I don't know that he's a good enough
athlete to be able to play safety
consistently, but he's he's probably too
small to play linebacker. Chandler
Rivers like can I win with a guy that
small consistently? So, I think all
these guys, like when you look at it,
the tape is good and those are all like
players that people like, but then you
look and go like, "All right, this this
still checks the box of like what the
NFL typically has reservations over."
>> See, this is where though you overthink
it and you make mistakes.
>> Sure.
>> This when you watch guys like the
Rivers, everybody that you guys
mentioned
>> can play the they could play and they
and they and it's not like listen and
nothing against Hobart College or
anything like that. These guys line up
at major programs and play and play at a
high level. And to me, you know, you
watch Rivers play, you watch him come up
and attack screens, you watch him cover
down the field, you watch him play zone,
you know, you watch, yeah, he's a
shorter guy, you watch Lewis play, he's
blitzing, he's making tackles. This is
where NFL people overthink things, you
know, and like I say, the tape shows
that these guys could play. And
hopefully tomorrow all these kids will
get drafted. But it's just it's shocking
to me that that some players are taken
that that don't that don't have that
that kind of ability or that playmaking
ability. And you know, like I say,
there's a lot of teams out there that
will make mistakes. And I think a few
teams made mistakes today. And you know,
your Dallas Cowboys are doing a nice job
of of doing what they need to do to take
care of their their players. They're
helping their defense. Obviously, their
defensive coordinator has a say in
what's going on here, but there's a lot
of really good football players on this
board tomorrow. When we get to that when
we get to that that round tomorrow on
Saturday, it is going to be a lot of fun
to see where these teams pick these
guys, but maybe not now. But I'll tell
you what, these guys were all talking
about, can you believe it was a fourth
round pick? Can you believe it was a
fifth round pick? These guys are going
to make some plays. You know, the teams
Listen, I did it for 13 years, Bobby.
Teams suck at this stuff sometimes.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Brian. Surely they
do.
>> Uh Brian, I would say this though, like
I mean because you're right
no argue about
>> I'm not going to argue about anything. I
can just say what I'm going to say.
Desmond King, for every Desmond King and
Buddha Baker, which those guys exist and
they they end up doing really well
consistently like the the the general
percentage has shown that a lot of times
those those kind of concerns that you
have about players more often than not
like like it becomes a struggle and so
so like they do exist. They can they can
rise above. just don't know how the hell
to use these guys. How about that? How
about for everyone?
>> Somebody figured out Desmond King,
somebody figured out Buddha, somebody
figured out uh gosh, who was the Quandre
Diggs who was thought to be too small.
They they figured all those guys out.
I'm just saying that like it is
>> you are working against history, too.
Yeah. Like like a little
>> Yeah. And then and there's a lot of
these histories that are doing podcasts
and doing uh TV and radio broadcasts and
stuff. Every one of these guys, that
poor ass Mike Mayok, you know, he he he
was up there on TV forever. Got a job to
run team, ruined the Raiders, the way he
blew all those picks with all these guys
that we kind of liked, all these guys
who were supposed to be really good
football players. Not one of those damn
players hit.
>> I don't need to hear this about, you
know, well, some of these teams, it's
history. Ah, come on, man.
>> I think another thing that we can like
think about as well is like it's not
just these players are falling. It's
like who's getting drafted while the
good dudes are falling. Like some of
these wide receivers are going, some of
these tight ends have gone and I'm like,
"Hey man, how do these guys go ahead of
Wheatley who has fantastic Penn State
film?" You know what I mean? Which is a
little weird for me, too.
>> Jaylen Husky, I didn't even
>> Are we going to are we going to have a
while? Because I'd kind of like to go
back and talk about these last players
that we cover.
>> Yeah. Real quickly, I want to I want to
have one little conversation while
they're still in the war room. Can we
take that war room feed full Chris Beam
if we could or Matt Kent whoever?
>> Can we get some sound up there?
>> Yeah, let's hear what they're saying.
Can we just like listen in for a little
bit? That'd be great. Uh I just want to
I want to take a look at what are they
having the conversation with right now.
There's Clayton Adams.
>> When did when did Clayton Adams go uh
with the shave?
>> It was good.
>> Semi-reent.
>> I hadn't seen that yet.
>> Yeah. Uh
>> that's very O line of him.
>> The entire the entire staff is still in
the war room. Usually it's pretty quick
to clear out. Part of this might be,
hey, we've got three picks
>> in the first.
>> They're lining them up right now. That's
what they're doing. They're lining them
up. Which order they'll take these guys.
I'm I'm sure the stack will tell them
that, but they're just going over it
again in what order do they need. And
maybe they need to reshuffle their
board. Maybe.
>> How big is that room?
>> Not super big.
>> How much How much wider is it outside of
our shot?
>> Not a ton.
>> Not much. Yeah. Not much. I do find I do
find it interesting that standing right
up front talking with them while they're
doing stuff is Bo Toifer who's their
Northeast area scout. That makes me
wonder what they're looking at at them
at tomorrow.
>> Interesting. The uh so the way this room
is outlined just looking at the shot
that we're at right now. If you go to
the left of of Chris Vaughn there, right
on the edge of the left hand.
>> He's on the left hand side.
>> Yep. There's no row behind that. It's
just a wall and a couple of television
screens.
>> Okay.
>> Directly behind us, let's say you're
looking behind the camera. That's the
main board and feed. It's all a video
wall, but there are seats that stretch
all the way to that that portion of the
room. So, there's probably six to seven
seats on each side. Yes, six, seven
seats on each side going back toward the
camera that you don't see in the shot.
Then, if you look to the right hand
side, there's a little bit more room to
that side. There's a second row of
chairs and a desk that sits back there
that goes all the way to the wall as
well. About maybe seven or eight extra
seats that are there. And then behind
that are offices where other people are
sitting in about two different offices
andor conference rooms. It also directly
goes into to Will Mccclelay's office
there too. So there's a lot of space to
the right hand side there, Brian. But I
agree with you if you've got both Toiver
up there kind of having the
conversation.
They're talking about something.
>> Well, they're looking at their board.
They're looking to their looking to
their right and they're they're looking
at the board and they're talking about,
you know, they're just this is a way you
sit down and we talk about sleeping on
your board. That's what they're doing
right now. They're kind of getting a
mental idea in of what is on the board,
what's left, all the tags have been been
taken. How many tags we have off the
board? 100 tags. Is that how many tags?
So that board if you know say they've
got say they've got 150 players on the
board they're they're off you know their
tags are off. So now you get an idea
though and you kind of it it really
paints a picture for you like do we have
any third round guys left? Is there
anybody that we needed to get to that we
need to make a priority uh going into
tomorrow. So that's what they're talking
about you know right now is though
>> it's Conor Riley that just walked into
the screen offensive line coach.
>> Yeah. Brian, you always say that the
fourth round is for the hurt guys and
the convicts. So, yeah, it's like Jamal
McCoy being talked about right now.
>> You know what I think to me that listen,
that injury is significant. Now, the
thing that he's going to have to get it
the thought is and Dallas brought him
in. So, they know exactly what the
injury is as far as his knee. It sounds
like the ACL is fine. They sound like
some other things that they're going to
have to go in on. And if they have to go
replace that, then he is out for the
whole entire year. There is no But if
it's a simple scope or clean, then he
could play this season. So, it's either
going to be one or the other for him as
far as that knee injury. Either you're
going to take a player that could that
can get fixed and then you've got him
you've lost him for the whole year or
you got a player that can get scoped uh
and then he can play uh here very
quickly. They just, you know, they have
to make that teams have have to make
that determination right now. When you
uh when you look at 112 and 114
because of those picks being so closely
together there, Brian, could you take
one guy that's going to make an impact?
>> See, that's what they're trying to
figure out
>> and then turn around and make a guy and
and take a guy that could be
>> That's what they're trying to figure
out. They're trying to figure out, you
know, and listen, if they if they stack
their board, they'll tell they'll know
who the order it is, but they're just
want to make sure that they have the
right order. You know, it's like, okay,
can and that's what Jerry's doing with
his hands right now. See, he's he's kind
of talking about the tags
>> and he's going through that and and
they're asking the questions he's asking
is which one of these guys do we need to
take first because is there somebody
that we can lose?
>> Is there somebody now? Maybe they're
thinking about trading back here, too.
Where is there somebody that we need to
take first and then if we lose a guy,
we're okay if we have to move that pick.
>> And while they do have three picks in
the fourth round, remember they don't
have a pick in the fifth or the sixth
anymore.
>> Absolutely.
>> So, they'll be times in the fourth.
>> Yeah. They need to get these they need
to get these fourth round picks right. I
mean, they need to and that's where,
like I say, their board their board is
telling them right now which direction
to go. They've done a really good job of
following their board, it appears to me.
So with, you know, and like I say, Will
Mcclelay is popping up now. He's looking
at it. He just wants a little bit better
view of like, okay, what does he have to
navigate tomorrow? See, he's explaining
like if you take this guy now, so he's
pointing, he's talking, you take him,
think about him, you know, that's the
adjustments that they're they're really
doing right now. Somebody's alerting the
grandkids that they're being watched on
the war room camera cuz he's showing
they're showing screenshots of uh of
conversations around everybody just
saying that we're breaking it all down.
So, we'll get off the war room camera
now. We've we've we've probably talked
about a little.
>> Yeah, that was a good breakdown.
>> Figuring this stuff out. That was gold.
>> Here's the thing. I I as a football fan
>> Yeah.
>> think it's the coolest weekend of the
year.
>> Absolutely. anytime. If there was one
thing I could I could pay a lump sum for
as an experience, it would be the to be
like a a uh a fly on the wall in a war
room.
>> Yeah.
>> Sign the NDA and just let me sit in
there.
>> Yeah, absolutely. I do that all day. See
how it all gets broken down.
>> Incredible thing. Uh but it is uh it is
very secretive work across the board.
All right. You wanted to go back through
a couple of those last names
>> if we can just to you know I mean Brian
you say like give them their due. We
watched them.
>> I absolutely.
>> Who do you want to start with? Jennings.
>> Can I say something quick real fast
though? Just real fast. Yeah, please.
>> Does taking Jan Barum stop them from
taking Kyle Lewis or Harold Perkins? No,
>> because they're similar type players.
>> Well, Perkins may as a linebacker.
>> Well, according to Bobby, they hate
small players.
>> Okay.
>> Who does?
>> Cowboys.
>> The Cowboys.
>> I didn't say the Cowboys do. I said the
NFL does.
>> I I think the the rest of the line,
>> you know, they hate small players. The
NFL. I'm not saying it's right.
>> That's why And again, Bobby, that's why
these guys suck at drafting. And I'm
saying the NFL general.
>> It's always into day two when it starts
really getting to
>> I'm just saying though when you look at
Listen,
>> but but you would agree that's what the
I'm not saying right or wrong. Right.
Not right or wrong. You would also agree
that's generally how the NFL has
approached it, right? That's all I'm
saying.
>> And that's why And that's why I'm saying
it shouldn't surprise us. That's why
every year there's like the Arizona
Cardinals and every year there's these
team.
>> But it shouldn't surprise us, right?
That's all I'm saying. The Dallas
Cowboys got a little bad at drafting
there for a little bit too. Taking like
maybe the maybe the perfect guy or
something like that that they thought
>> but Junior Fokos
>> but like where the start where the
started got to be
>> and Foko was a big bust. They were they
didn't work out the players have been
bust they've been busted.
>> But the the whole like start of the the
whole start of the conversation was who
are the best players that are left that
still haven't gone yet. I'm saying they
they shouldn't necessarily surprises
they that they haven't gone because the
NFL has routinely done that, whether
it's right or wrong. I'm not I'm not
commentating on whether that's a good
strategy. I'm just saying that it's it's
probably to be expected that they still,
you know, another year view it this way
regardless of just like it it shouldn't
be a surprise that the NFL still looked
at Bane and said that may be top 10
tape, but we're going to let Ruben Bane
get to 15. Like I mean that's just the
way that they typically. about. Okay,
you talked about Scott from Miami
>> and you're thinking like, well, where do
you play him?
>> Mhm.
>> Like, how about you play him in the
slot? How about you blitz him? How about
you play him at linebacker? How about
you play him in coverage at corner?
>> Sure. I think because I think there's a
lot of discussion about like is he good
enough to cover consistently in the slot
or or like I think that's things that
he's viewed as twer.
>> He's got tape that he shows you he could
do.
>> I think I'm not asking him to play slot.
They how you know we watch Nick Amanda
Warary play in Seattle but what do they
do? They don't always play Nick Amanda
Warary in the slot. Yeah.
>> And Nick and Nick Emanori still fell out
of the first round even though everybody
thought he was one of the better
players.
>> That's what I'm saying though. He's the
these that's when you take players and
you play them
>> right Brian. It's not a right or wrong
discussion. I'm not I'm not that's not
the point. Like the if you want to have
a right or wrong discussion, we can. I'm
saying what the the whole topic had
started was just are we surprised
they're still there or why why shouldn't
we be surprised? I'm saying that you
can't you wouldn't naturally think
injury or something. You think that's
probably just the NFL thinking about
things the way they have whether that's
right or wrong. That's typically how
they've approached.
>> I had a team call me and tell me they
were really wrong about about Lawrence.
That they were wrong about Lawrence.
>> Malachi Lawrence.
>> Malachi Lawrence. I had a team I had a
team ask me like, "Hey, what did you
see?" We sent three guys in there and
none of us got him right.
>> None of them got it right. A team
admitted that to me today. They asked
me, "What did you see?" And I told him I
I explained how I broke down the player
and they go, "Damn, we sent three guys
in there and we didn't get him right."
>> Okay. So, like in terms of they're now
looking at
>> the evaluation, they they they saw him.
>> So, they think he's better than they
ended up on their board. Is that what
you're saying?
>> They they they felt like that they got
the player. Well, they said we'll see.
>> But they had three scouts go to Central
Florida and not see the player right.
>> Uh-huh. Yeah. I'm not I'm not
>> so tell if you're telling me that people
are on the board because that's what the
league that's what the league again some
some of these teams don't evaluate
correctly.
>> Brian, you saying like they as like a
like a power rusher maybe, but we saw
him as like a bursty guy.
>> They didn't see him as a they didn't see
him as a legitimate pass rush guy.
>> Okay. They had him wrong then. Yeah.
>> They had him wrong. Okay.
>> They absolutely and they said, "Listen,
I Hey, what did you say?
>> Listen to the draft show."
>> Yeah. I'm like, what did you see? And
listen, he might he might not rush the
pass or worse a damn. And they might be
right.
>> But I'm just saying though, there's a
lot of people that we talk about, you
know, why these guys are on this board.
And maybe the league maybe the league
doesn't maybe the league needs to think
a little different.
>> Maybe and and and maybe
>> maybe the league doesn't be need to be
1986,
1988 all 1992 all
>> and and and maybe vegans need to eat
steak. But if they don't order it at the
table, I'm not then surprised that they
didn't order it. I'm just I'm not saying
that's right or wrong. I'm saying that I
expect like that's that's consistently
kind of the way they do it.
>> I think it's a terrible answer for why
players are why players are still on
board. You don't think it's a good
enough reason for them to have fallen,
but that that doesn't mean that it's a a
terrible explanation for how they
typically
I don't know how guys could get in a
room like, "Oh, I I know this because I
was actually in the room when we sat
there and like talked about these guys
and somebody said, "I don't like Randy
Moss and the way he his attitude. I
don't like his way he's thinking and you
know, he's a malcontent guy that Charles
Woodson,
>> you know."
>> No, I I agree. Again, Brian, it's not a
question of is it right or wrong. It's
that that's the way they typically do.
That's all. It's just about
expectations.
>> Typically do it get you fired.
>> Brian, you're we're talking past each
other here. I think there is not a
disagreement about what
>> No, I I'm just No, I'm just saying my
point, Bobby. I'm And I'm just venting
at you.
>> Sounds like I'm venting at you because
you defend you defend what they do.
>> You You take it as well. Gosh, it's been
gospel. Brian, Brian, we we can go pull
out the the clips of you talking about
that Mississippi State corner from a few
years ago at Forbes. Who said who said
who said it doesn't matter that we
haven't seen a corner like his build
before? He's going to succeed. And then
he didn't. I'm not saying right or
wrong. Everybody misses. Everybody hits.
It happens from time to time. I'm just
saying there is a history that says the
NFL goes, why don't you look like what
we see? Like like it just makes us pause
and say, you don't look like what we've
typically seen. And they've been wrong
before. They were wrong on Desmond King.
They were wrong on Quandry Digs. All of
those sort of things. All right, we got
to step aside. The press conference is
getting underway. Appreciate you joining
us all the way through day two. We'll be
back 10 a.m. tomorrow. We're going to
talk to the scouts and some of those
decision makers. Let's step aside. The
front office stepping up into the AT&T
media center.